export default [
  {
    ID: '67652',
    Subject: 'Discoveries',
    Question:
      'In 1848, John Marshall said he had discovered a chispa, a Spanish word for "bright speck" or "spangle." What had he discovered near the future site of Sacramento, California?',
    Answer: 'gold',
    Metadata:
      '1840s 1848 19th century American history California history Marshall, John social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '58067',
    Subject: 'Battles',
    Question:
      'At the 1896 Battle of Adwa, in the all-time worst defeat of Europeans at the hands of native Africans, forces from what invading country were annihilated by the Ethiopian army?',
    Answer: 'Italy',
    Metadata:
      '1890s 1896 19th century Africa battle defeat Ethiopia history imperialism social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '65543',
    Subject: 'Presidential Nicknames',
    Question:
      'What U.S. president became known as His Fraudulency after winning the disputed election of 1876?',
    Answer: 'Rutherford Hayes',
    Metadata: '1870s 1876 19th century American history history nickname president social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '14787',
    Subject: 'Month Names',
    Question: 'The month of May is named after what Greek goddess and eldest of the Pleiades?',
    Answer: 'Maia',
    Metadata: 'etymology goddess Greek myth language arts myth',
  },
  {
    ID: '14777',
    Subject: 'Poetic Allusions',
    Question:
      'What are you being asked to do if someone makes this request of you? Apply thine engine to the spongy door, Set Bacchus from his glassy prison free.',
    Answer: 'open (uncork) a wine bottle',
    Metadata: 'allusion Bacchus Greek myth language arts literature myth',
  },
  {
    ID: '77665',
    Subject: '\u001a Planetary Observations',
    Question: 'On what planet other than Earth are seasons most apparent?',
    Answer: 'Mars',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science planet science solar system',
  },
  {
    ID: '17778',
    Subject: 'Three Bears Grammar',
    Question: 'What two kinds of pronouns are in this line? Somebody has been sleeping in my bed.',
    Answer: 'indefinite, possessive',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts pronoun',
  },
  {
    ID: '21186',
    Subject: 'Latin Root Words',
    Question:
      'Allegiance and "legislate" are words derived from the Latin word "lex" which means what?',
    Answer: 'law',
    Metadata: 'language arts Latin language root word',
  },
  {
    ID: '77718',
    Subject: '\u001aSpace Probes',
    Question:
      'What is the term for a space probe designed to approach but not land or impact on a heavenly body?',
    Answer: 'flyby',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science science space exploration',
  },
  {
    ID: '137107',
    Subject: ',Algebraic Exponents',
    Question: 'What is the square of the following? -10/3 times y to the 20th power',
    Answer: '100/9(y to the 40th power)',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic fraction exponent math',
  },
  {
    ID: '146745',
    Subject: '1Composers',
    Question:
      'What composer with an interest in folk music and a knowledge of Hindu scales and Sanskrit literature wrote these works? The Perfect Fool Egdon Heath Hymns for the Rig-Veda The Planets',
    Answer: 'Gustav Holst',
    Metadata: '20th century classical music composer fine arts humanities music music history',
  },
  {
    ID: '31900',
    Subject: 'The Mideast',
    Question:
      'What country on the Arabian Peninsula is bordered to its north by Saudi Arabia and to its east by Oman?',
    Answer: 'Yemen',
    Metadata:
      'Arabian Peninsula border geography Mideast Oman peninsula Saudi Arabia social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '91835',
    Subject: '\u001fEvaporation',
    Question:
      'The evaporation rate depends primarily on wind speed, relative humidity, and what other factor?',
    Answer: 'temperature',
    Metadata: 'evaporation humidity physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '126739',
    Subject: '*Math',
    Question:
      'What is the name of a matrix of numbers such that the sum of the elements in any row, column or diagonal is the same?',
    Answer: 'magic square',
    Metadata: 'addition arithmetic math matrix vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '120708',
    Subject: '!Liverworts',
    Question:
      'Like all bryophytes, liverworts are anchored to the ground by what rootlike structures?',
    Answer: 'rhizoids',
    Metadata: 'biology botany liverwort science',
  },
  {
    ID: '35067',
    Subject: 'European Regions',
    Question:
      'Fife, a region between the Firth of Forth and the Firth of Tay, is in what part of the United Kingdom?',
    Answer: 'Scotland',
    Metadata: 'Europe firth geography Great Britain region social studies United Kingdom',
  },
  {
    ID: '136867',
    Subject: ',Money, Money, Money',
    Question:
      'You have $330 in your hand consisting of $5 and $20 bills. If you have 24 bills, how many fives do you have?',
    Answer: '10',
    Metadata: 'algebra math money problem word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '5332',
    Subject: '\u0002Drama',
    Question:
      "These characters are in what play? Jim O'Conner a poet named Tom Wingfield Tom's crippled sister Laura",
    Answer: 'The Glass Menagerie',
    Metadata:
      'American literature drama language arts literary character literature Williams, Tennessee',
  },
  {
    ID: '56504',
    Subject: 'Anthropology',
    Question:
      'What is the popular name for the anthropoid fossils of Homo erectus discovered in 1891 on an island in what is now Indonesia?',
    Answer: 'Java Man',
    Metadata:
      'anthropology history Homo erectus Indonesia social studies Southeast Asia world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '14209',
    Subject: 'Literary Riddles',
    Question:
      'Name the work in which these riddles occur. -The golden casket reads, "Who chooseth me shall gain what many men desire." -The silver casket reads, "Who chooseth me shall get as much as he deserves." -The leaden casket reads, "Who chooseth me must give and hazard all he hath."',
    Answer: 'The Merchant of Venice',
    Metadata: 'language arts literature riddle Shakespeare',
  },
  {
    ID: '66088',
    Subject: 'Congresses',
    Question:
      'The First Continental Congress met in 1774. Present were delegates from all the American colonies except Georgia. How many colonies participated?',
    Answer: '12',
    Metadata:
      '1770s 1774 18th century American history colonial period Continental Congress history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '99478',
    Subject: 'European Legislation',
    Question:
      'In 1993, the Dutch legislature passed a bill legalizing mercy killing under certain circumstances. Name this practice.',
    Answer: 'euthanasia',
    Metadata:
      '1990s 1993 20th century death Europe health history mercy killing Netherlands social studies vocabulary \n!Disease',
  },
  {
    ID: '21274',
    Subject: 'Borrowed Words',
    Question:
      'These words came into English from what language? tornado, mosquito, embargo, armadillo',
    Answer: 'Spanish',
    Metadata: 'borrowed word language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '32383',
    Subject: 'Waterways',
    Question:
      'The shortest distance between the North Atlantic Ocean and the Indian Ocean is through what two seas?',
    Answer: 'Mediterranean Sea, Red Sea',
    Metadata: 'geography sea social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '3292',
    Subject: 'Science Fiction Linguistics',
    Question:
      'In what science fiction work is this excerpt found? What justification is there for a word which is simply the opposite of some other word? Take "good", for instance. If you have a word like "good", what need is there for a word like "bad"? "Ungood" will do just as well -- better, because it\'s an exact opposite.',
    Answer: '1984',
    Metadata: 'English literature language arts linguistics literature novel quote science fiction',
  },
  {
    ID: '44218',
    Subject: '\u0012Law',
    Question:
      'Sarah said to Sheriff Sam Slayton that her neighbor Sal stole some silver in South St. Louis. If this matter goes to court, this accusation or assertion of a fact to be proved legally becomes what kind of assertion?',
    Answer: 'allegation',
    Metadata: 'court law social studies trial',
  },
  {
    ID: '13117',
    Subject: 'Poetic Cadence',
    Question:
      'What is the last, stressed, complete word in this verse? As I was going out one day My head fell off and rolled away.',
    Answer: 'rolled',
    Metadata: 'accent language arts literature poetry',
  },
  {
    ID: '94058',
    Subject: '\u001fEnergy',
    Question: 'An alternator converts what kind of energy to electrical energy?',
    Answer: 'mechanical energy',
    Metadata: 'alternator energy physical science science technology',
  },
  {
    ID: '149393',
    Subject: '3!Auto Racing',
    Question: 'What speedway in Indiana is the site of the Brickyard 400?',
    Answer: 'Indianapolis (Motor) Speedway',
    Metadata: 'auto racing Indiana sports state history trivia',
  },
  {
    ID: '75038',
    Subject: 'Protecting the President',
    Question:
      'Les Coffelt is the only member of the U.S. Secret Service to be killed during an assassination attempt. He was shot when two Puerto Rican nationalists tried to kill what president?',
    Answer: 'Harry Truman',
    Metadata: '20th century American history assassination history Secret Service social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '59499',
    Subject: 'Symbols',
    Question:
      'A five-pointed star symbolizes America. What symbol composed of two tools represented Communist ideology?',
    Answer: 'hammer, sickle',
    Metadata:
      '20th century communism Eastern Europe Europe history social studies symbol world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '7224',
    Subject: '\u0002American Literature',
    Question:
      'Whose ratiocinative tales have been cited as the origins of the modern mystery story?',
    Answer: "Edgar Allan Poe's",
    Metadata: 'American literature author language arts literature mystery',
  },
  {
    ID: '16146',
    Subject: 'Verbs',
    Question: 'What is the past participle form of "go"?',
    Answer: 'gone',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts participle past participle',
  },
  {
    ID: '44929',
    Subject: '\u0012Bail',
    Question:
      'Typically, a bail bondsman charges a fee that is what percentage of the amount of the bond?',
    Answer: '10%',
    Metadata: 'bail law social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '18125',
    Subject: 'Sentence Parts',
    Question:
      'What is the object of the verbal in this line? Tipping the cow was more than she could manage on an empty stomach.',
    Answer: 'cow',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts sentence analysis verbal',
  },
  {
    ID: '60707',
    Subject: 'Inspired Leaders',
    Question:
      'This is about whom? Her fate created a strong patriotic feeling among the French. Her example helped to bring about the successful conclusion of the war in 1453. The French finally drove the English out and re-established a strong monarchy.',
    Answer: 'Joan of Arc',
    Metadata: '15th century Europe France history social studies woman world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '133019',
    Subject: '+Polygons',
    Question: 'How many degrees are in one interior angle of a regular decagon?',
    Answer: '144 degrees',
    Metadata: 'decagon geometry interior angle math plane geometry polygon',
  },
  {
    ID: '49916',
    Subject: 'Nonfiction',
    Question:
      'A nonfiction book subtitled "The Fists of Righteous Harmony" is about what rebellion in China at the beginning of the 20th century?',
    Answer: 'Boxer Rebellion',
    Metadata:
      '1900 1900s 20th century Asia China history language arts literature nonfiction rebellion social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '34968',
    Subject: 'Mideast Geography',
    Question: 'Name the largest body of water adjacent to Israel.',
    Answer: 'Mediterranean Sea',
    Metadata: 'geography Israel Mideast sea social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '61807',
    Subject: 'Italy History',
    Question:
      'Largely because Botticelli, Petrarch, Dante, Michelangelo, Leonardo da Vinci, Galileo, and Amerigo Vespucci all lived in this region, Tuscany is said to be the birthplace of the Italian what?',
    Answer: 'Renaissance',
    Metadata: 'Europe history humanities Italy region social studies Tuscany world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '65211',
    Subject: 'Presidents',
    Question:
      'During whose administration did these events occur? -the Battle of Tippecanoe -chartering the Second Bank of the U.S. -Hartford Convention -War of 1812',
    Answer: "James Madison's",
    Metadata:
      '1810s 1812 19th century American history Battle of Tippecanoe Hartford Convention history president social studies War of 1812',
  },
  {
    ID: '82908',
    Subject: 'Traps',
    Question:
      'What word completes this caption? Trapped millions of years ago, this ant is perfectly preserved today in a sticky plant sap which turned into ...',
    Answer: 'amber',
    Metadata: 'earth science fossil geology paleontology sap science',
  },
  {
    ID: '93219',
    Subject: '\u001fPendulums',
    Question:
      'What is the period of a short pendulum that swings back and forth with a frequency of 3 cycles per second?',
    Answer: '1/3 second',
    Metadata: 'oscillation pendulum physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '122885',
    Subject: '(Skeletal Zoology',
    Question:
      'These are general characteristics of what kind of creatures? The trunk vertebrae are fused together. The cervical vertebrae are saddle-shaped allowing for especially free neck mobility. Many bones are thin and hollow. The sternum projects into a huge keel.',
    Answer: 'birds',
    Metadata: 'biology keel science sternum zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '58865',
    Subject: '\u0013War Crimes',
    Question:
      'What architect of Adolf Hitler\'s "final solution" for the extermination of European Jewry was hanged in Israel in 1962 for war crimes?',
    Answer: 'Adolf Eichmann',
    Metadata:
      '1940s 1960s 1962 20th century Europe final solution Germany history Hitler, Adolf Holocaust Israel Judaism Nazi people social studies war war crime world history World War II',
  },
  {
    ID: '561',
    Subject: 'Poetry',
    Question:
      "What poet wrote these lines? I wandered lonely as a cloud That floats on high o'er vales and hills When all at once I saw a crowd, A host, of golden daffodils",
    Answer: 'William Wordsworth',
    Metadata: 'author English literature language arts literature poet poetry quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '56061',
    Subject: 'Ancient Geography',
    Question:
      'These ancient cities are adjacent to what body of water? Carthage, Alexandria, Tyre, Syracuse, Tunis',
    Answer: 'Mediterranean Sea',
    Metadata: 'ancient history history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '13955',
    Subject: 'Daughters',
    Question: 'Identify the two treacherous daughters in "King Lear."',
    Answer: 'Goneril, Regan',
    Metadata:
      'drama (Shakespeare) King Lear (drama) language arts literary character literature Shakespeare',
  },
  {
    ID: '15889',
    Subject: 'Grammar',
    Question: 'Inflections of nouns may indicate number or what else?',
    Answer: 'case',
    Metadata: 'grammar inflection language arts noun',
  },
  {
    ID: '140846',
    Subject: '-Statistical Expectations',
    Question:
      'In a game involving a single die, the player wins $20 if a 2 comes up, wins $40 if a 4 comes up, loses $30 if a 3 comes up, and neither wins nor loses if a 1, 5, or 6 come up. What is the expected sum of money to be won?',
    Answer: '$5',
    Metadata: 'dice math statistics word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '149774',
    Subject: '4Hot Water',
    Question:
      'What happens to the element in a hot water heater if the electric power is on and the tank is empty?',
    Answer: 'element burns out',
    Metadata: 'construction vocational wiring',
  },
  {
    ID: '69323',
    Subject: 'Court Rulings',
    Question:
      'In 1955, the Supreme Court ordered the desegregation of public golf courses, parks, swimming pools, and playgrounds based on what 1954 ruling relating to public schools?',
    Answer: 'Brown v Board of Education',
    Metadata:
      '1950s 1955 20th century American history black history desegregation history social studies Supreme Court Supreme Court case',
  },
  {
    ID: '47829',
    Subject: 'Historic Documents',
    Question:
      'Who wrote this around 1920? When a person claims to be non-violent, he is expected not to be angry with one who has injured him. He will not wish him harm. He will wish him well.',
    Answer: 'Mohandas (Mahatma) Gandhi',
    Metadata:
      '1920 1920s 20th century Asia historical document history India quote social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '85669',
    Subject: 'Hydrological Analogies',
    Question:
      'Rock formations that store water are to aquifers as rock formations that are impermeable to groundwater are to what?',
    Answer: 'aquicludes',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology hydrology science vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '126782',
    Subject: '*\u0002Topology',
    Question:
      'What, according to topologists, is the simplest geometric figure in three-dimensional space?',
    Answer: 'tetrahedron',
    Metadata: 'math topology',
  },
  {
    ID: '5205',
    Subject: '\u0002 Short Stories',
    Question:
      'What name is indicated in this excerpt from a short story? Nolan never did hear her name but once again. From that moment, Sept. 23, 1807, till the day he died, May 11, 1863, he never heard her name again. For that half-century and more, he was a man without a country.',
    Answer: 'United States',
    Metadata:
      'American literature language arts literature Man Without a Country, The quote short story',
  },
  {
    ID: '72283',
    Subject: 'Old West Crimes',
    Question:
      'After a battle with Indians and exhausted from fatigue and thirst, caravan members were approached by white men under a flag of truce and induced to surrender their arms under solemn promises of protection. They were then murdered in cold blood. This 1857 massacre occurred in what territory?',
    Answer: 'Utah',
    Metadata:
      '1850s 1857 19th century American history history massacre Mountain Meadows Massacre Old West social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '77112',
    Subject: 'Legislation',
    Question:
      'The 1932 act banning yellow dog contracts and federal injunctions against nonviolent labor disputes was named for Senator George Norris of Nebraska and Representative Fiorello La Guardia of what state?',
    Answer: 'New York',
    Metadata:
      '1930s 1932 20th century American history history legislation people social studies state history yellow dog contract',
  },
  {
    ID: '135175',
    Subject: '+Transversals',
    Question:
      'A line is cut by a transversal. If one of the four angles formed is 40 degrees, what are the measures of each of the alternate exterior angles?',
    Answer: '140 degrees',
    Metadata: 'exterior angle geometry math plane geometry transversal',
  },
  {
    ID: '34002',
    Subject: 'Continental Borders',
    Question: 'What African country borders on Asia?',
    Answer: 'Egypt',
    Metadata: 'Africa Asia border continent geography social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '28285',
    Subject: 'U.S. Cities',
    Question:
      'Only Warsaw has more Polish residents than this American city. Name this metropolis in which you would also find the Museum of Science and Industry, the oldest zoo in the country, and the largest grain market in the world.',
    Answer: 'Chicago',
    Metadata: 'American geography city geography museum social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '91865',
    Subject: '\u001fSound',
    Question:
      'Sound can be heard around a corner, even though there is no straight path from the source of the sound to the ear, because waves spread out when they pass the edge of an obstacle. Name this phenomenon.',
    Answer: 'diffraction',
    Metadata: 'physical science science sound',
  },
  {
    ID: '71336',
    Subject: 'Museum',
    Question: 'In what state is the Lincoln-Douglas Debate Museum?',
    Answer: 'Illinois',
    Metadata:
      'American geography American history Douglas, Stephen geography history Lincoln, Abraham museum social studies state history',
  },
  {
    ID: '3709',
    Subject: 'Russian Literature',
    Question:
      "In what Russian novel do these characters appear? Raskolnikov, a student Dounia, Raskolnikov's sister Sinia, a prostitute Profiry, a police inspector",
    Answer: 'Crime and Punishment',
    Metadata: 'language arts literary character literature novel Russian literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '85254',
    Subject: 'Rock',
    Question: 'Name either of the textures that characterize all metamorphic rocks.',
    Answer: 'foliated (or non-foliated)',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology metamorphic rock petrology rock science',
  },
  {
    ID: '27313',
    Subject: 'U.S. Geography',
    Question: 'You have an alphabetical list of states bordering the Atlantic. What is first?',
    Answer: 'Connecticut',
    Metadata: 'American geography border geography social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '85604',
    Subject: 'Landforms',
    Question:
      'These are names for what kind of landforms in the U.S.? Atchafalaya, Barley Barber, Great Cypress, Great Dismal, Okefenokee',
    Answer: 'swamps',
    Metadata: 'earth science geography geology landform social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '89712',
    Subject: '\u001f! Subatomic Particles',
    Question: 'Baryons and mesons are two categories of what class of subatomic particles?',
    Answer: 'hadrons',
    Metadata: 'antibaryon baryon meson physical science physics science subatomic particle',
  },
  {
    ID: '122855',
    Subject: '(Caloric Expenditures',
    Question:
      'The damselfly uses less than one calorie a day while what little avian needs up to 330 calories per minute?',
    Answer: 'hummingbird',
    Metadata: 'biology bird ornithology science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '124709',
    Subject: '*Symbols',
    Question: 'As a mathematical symbol, what does an exclamation point mean?',
    Answer: 'factorial',
    Metadata: 'exclamation point math symbol',
  },
  {
    ID: '11281',
    Subject: 'Poetic Meter',
    Question:
      'Samuel Taylor Coleridge says, "Trochee trips from long to short, / From long to long in solemn sort / Slow spondee stalks, strong foot, yet ill able / Ever to come up with dactyl trisyllable." What does he say marches from short to long?',
    Answer: 'iambic (iambics)',
    Metadata: 'Coleridge, Samuel language arts literature poetic meter poetry',
  },
  {
    ID: '53273',
    Subject: 'Homophones',
    Question:
      'Spell the term for a provincial governor in the Ottoman Empire or a ruler of the former kingdom of Tunis that is a homophone for a body of water enclosed by land with a wide mouth opening to the sea.',
    Answer: 'bey',
    Metadata: 'history homonym homophone Ottoman Empire social studies Tunis world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '30798',
    Subject: 'Harbors',
    Question: 'Elsinore is a seaport in what country?',
    Answer: 'Denmark',
    Metadata: 'Elsinore Europe geography Hamlet port Shakespeare social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '146663',
    Subject: '1!Instruments',
    Question: 'What is the name for the keyboard of a harpsichord, clavichord, or piano?',
    Answer: 'clavier',
    Metadata: 'clavichord fine arts harpsichord humanities music musical instrument piano',
  },
  {
    ID: '61934',
    Subject: 'National Economics',
    Question:
      'In 2012, what European nation adopted harsh austerity measures demanded by its bailout creditors to save the debt-crippled nation from bankruptcy?',
    Answer: 'Greece',
    Metadata: '2010s 2012 21st century Europe social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '129753',
    Subject: '*Factorials',
    Question: 'Express 24 as a factorial.',
    Answer: '4!',
    Metadata: 'factorial math',
  },
  {
    ID: '65042',
    Subject: 'Abbreviations of the Depression Era',
    Question:
      'For what does the abbreviation stand in this? When the National Credit Corporation proved inadequate, Hoover sent Congress a bill to create the RFC to support railroads, industry, and commerce.',
    Answer: 'Reconstruction Finance Corporation',
    Metadata:
      '1930s 20th century abbreviation American history federal agency Great Depression history Hoover, Herbert RFC social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '14008',
    Subject: 'Valor',
    Question: 'According to Shakespeare, what is the better part of valor?',
    Answer: 'discretion',
    Metadata: 'aphorism English literature language arts literature quote Shakespeare',
  },
  {
    ID: '6756',
    Subject: '\u0002Plays',
    Question:
      'Eugene O\'Neill\'s play, "The Fountain," is about what conquistador who explored Florida?',
    Answer: 'Ponce de Leon',
    Metadata:
      "American literature conquistador drama Florida language arts literature O'Neill, Eugene",
  },
  {
    ID: '137686',
    Subject: ',\u0002Algebraic Division',
    Question: 'Divide (10 (x squared) - 25x) by -5x.',
    Answer: '-2x + 5',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic operations math',
  },
  {
    ID: '83665',
    Subject: 'Plate Tectonics',
    Question:
      'What plate is being subducted beneath the North American continent from southern British Columbia to northern California?',
    Answer: 'Juan de Fuca plate',
    Metadata:
      'British Columbia California earth science geology North America plate tectonics science subduction',
  },
  {
    ID: '34070',
    Subject: 'Japan',
    Question:
      'The largest and most populated of the Japanese islands are Hokkaido, Shikoku, Kyushu, and what other?',
    Answer: 'Honshu',
    Metadata: 'Asia geography island Japan social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '76191',
    Subject: 'Symbols',
    Question:
      'These are examples of what kind of symbols used in the Old West? Flying H Diamond T Box L K Bar Running N Lazy A',
    Answer: 'brands (cattle brands)',
    Metadata: 'American history history Old West ranching social studies symbol',
  },
  {
    ID: '95279',
    Subject: '!Explosives',
    Question:
      'It is made by treating nitric acid with ammonia vapor. By combining it with diesel fuel, it becomes an inexpensive explosive. Name this substance also used in fertilizers.',
    Answer: 'ammonium nitrate',
    Metadata:
      'ammonia chemical compound chemistry explosive fertilizer nitric acid physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '68328',
    Subject: 'Capital Names',
    Question:
      'If you alphabetize the four U.S. state capitals named after presidents, which is last?',
    Answer: 'Madison',
    Metadata: 'American history capital city history president social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '1263',
    Subject: 'Fictional Transportation',
    Question: 'With what kind of vessel is Captain Nemo associated?',
    Answer: 'submarine',
    Metadata: 'English literature language arts literary character literature novel',
  },
  {
    ID: '25244',
    Subject: 'Vocabulary',
    Question:
      'What four-syllable verb should have been used in this line? They evicted a promise out of me.',
    Answer: 'elicited',
    Metadata: 'language arts malapropism vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '125594',
    Subject: '*\u0002Measurement',
    Question: '220 yards is what fraction of one mile?',
    Answer: '1/8',
    Metadata: 'math measurement',
  },
  {
    ID: '89445',
    Subject: '\u001fEnergy',
    Question:
      'What form of energy do materials possess from the kinetic energy of their molecules?',
    Answer: 'heat',
    Metadata: 'energy kinetic energy physical science physics science',
  },
  {
    ID: '67530',
    Subject: 'Adjective Etymology',
    Question:
      'What adjective meaning to act in a stubbornly obstructive or defensive manner was taken from the nickname of a Confederate general?',
    Answer: 'stonewall',
    Metadata:
      '19th century American history Confederacy eponym etymology general history nickname social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '47617',
    Subject: 'Ancient Buildings',
    Question:
      'Name the ancient stone building first built by Ishmael and Abraham and incorporated in the center of the Great Mosque at Mecca.',
    Answer: 'Kaaba',
    Metadata: 'Abraham history humanities Islam Mecca mosque social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '123520',
    Subject: '(\fZoology',
    Question:
      'Name any creature that fits this description. Although ancient people believed they were fish, cetaceans are aquatic mammals that bear live young, produce milk to feed their offspring, and have a bit of hair.',
    Answer: 'whales (dolphins, seals, walruses, porpoises)',
    Metadata: 'biology mammal science taxonomy zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '112035',
    Subject: '#!Cognitive Structure',
    Question:
      'What is the next term in this series of thought processes developed by Benjamin Bloom? knowledge comprehension application analysis synthesis',
    Answer: 'evaluation',
    Metadata: 'psychology science thinking',
  },
  {
    ID: '49248',
    Subject: 'The Suez War',
    Question:
      'In the Suez War of 1956, Egypt was opposed by Britain, France, and what other country?',
    Answer: 'Israel',
    Metadata:
      '1950s 1956 20th century Egypt France Great Britain history Mideast social studies Suez War United Kingdom war world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '10505',
    Subject: 'Literary Techniques',
    Question:
      'These techniques are used in what general type of literature or oratory? exigency transfer testimonial glittering generality',
    Answer: 'propaganda',
    Metadata: 'language arts literary technique literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '98720',
    Subject: '! Fast Flight',
    Question:
      'NASA\'s X-43A broke the speed record for a plane powered by an "air-breathing" engine by going Mach 10 in 2004. But this speed is still a long way from Mach 26, known as what velocity?',
    Answer: 'escape velocity',
    Metadata: 'aviation Mach number NASA social studies technology velocity',
  },
  {
    ID: '80002',
    Subject: '\u001a\fEclipses',
    Question: "What kind of eclipse occurs when the Moon moves into the Earth's shadow?",
    Answer: 'lunar eclipse',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science eclipse science',
  },
  {
    ID: '49405',
    Subject: 'Island Nations',
    Question:
      'Five hundred years ago, Portuguese colonists and their slaves settled on this archipelago of ten volcanic islands and five islets off the west coast of Africa. Name this country which achieved its independence from Portugal in 1975.',
    Answer: 'Cape Verde',
    Metadata:
      '1970s 1975 20th century Africa archipelago geography history Portugal social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '90883',
    Subject: '\u001fWork',
    Question:
      'How much more work may be done by using a one-rope, six-wheel pulley to lift an object ten feet than by using a one-rope, one-wheel pulley for the same job?',
    Answer: 'none',
    Metadata: 'mechanics physical science pulley science work',
  },
  {
    ID: '121884',
    Subject: '(Monotremes',
    Question: 'Name a monotreme.',
    Answer: 'duck-billed platypus (or echidna)',
    Metadata: 'biology monotreme science taxonomy zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '10686',
    Subject: 'Fiction',
    Question:
      "When the reader of a novel or the viewer of a play temporarily withholds doubt about truth or actuality and readily accepts the author's make-believe world, this is called the willing suspension of what?",
    Answer: 'disbelief',
    Metadata: 'drama humanities language arts literature novel',
  },
  {
    ID: '80740',
    Subject: '\u001b Waves',
    Question:
      'Name the distance which waves have traveled in open water from their point of origin to where they break.',
    Answer: 'fetch',
    Metadata: 'earth science ocean wave oceanography science vocabulary wave',
  },
  {
    ID: '29896',
    Subject: 'Mideast Geography',
    Question:
      'Since it is in the Khuzistan Province on an island in the Shatt al Arab waterway near the head of the Persian Gulf, Abadan is in what country?',
    Answer: 'Iran',
    Metadata: 'Abadan city geography gulf island Mideast Persian Gulf Shatt al Arab social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '69273',
    Subject: '1932 Flights',
    Question:
      'After traveling 2026 miles in a solo flight, who arrived near Londonderry, Ireland, after leaving Harbor Grace, Newfoundland nearly fifteen hours earlier?',
    Answer: 'Amelia Earhart',
    Metadata:
      '1930s 1932 20th century American history aviation history Ireland Newfoundland people social studies woman',
  },
  {
    ID: '138638',
    Subject: ',Trigonometric Functions',
    Question: 'What is the maximum value of either the sine or cosine function?',
    Answer: '1',
    Metadata: 'cosine math sine trigonometry',
  },
  {
    ID: '30634',
    Subject: 'Beaches',
    Question:
      'Copacabana Beach is in what Brazilian city, the name of which includes that of a month?',
    Answer: 'Rio de Janeiro',
    Metadata: 'city Copacabana Beach geography Latin America social studies South America',
  },
  {
    ID: '93971',
    Subject: '\u001fFundamental Physics',
    Question:
      'What fundamental concept in physical science is usually described in terms of velocity, acceleration, displacement, and time?',
    Answer: 'motion',
    Metadata: 'physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '25077',
    Subject: 'Etymology',
    Question:
      'What noun referring to a drunken orgy was derived from the ancient Roman god of wine?',
    Answer: 'bacchanalia',
    Metadata: 'etymology god language arts myth Roman myth vocabulary wine',
  },
  {
    ID: '115476',
    Subject: '%Bones',
    Question:
      'These are categories of what bones in the body? cervical, thoracic, lumbar, sacral, coccygeal',
    Answer: 'vertebrae',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology bone science skeletal system',
  },
  {
    ID: '54192',
    Subject: 'Latin American History',
    Question:
      "At the time of the invasion by Pizarro's conquistadors, what civilization included some 12 million people in what is now Peru, Ecuador, and parts of Chile, Bolivia, and Argentina?",
    Answer: 'Incas',
    Metadata:
      '16th century archaeology history Latin America Peru Pizarro, Francisco social studies South America world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '49997',
    Subject: 'Hunters',
    Question:
      'Simon Wiesenthal bagged his biggest trophy in 1960 when he located and captured what former Nazi official in Argentina?',
    Answer: 'Adolf Eichmann',
    Metadata:
      '1960 1960s 20th century Argentina history Judaism Latin America Nazi social studies South America Wiesenthal, Simon world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '8155',
    Subject: '\u0002American Authors',
    Question: 'Who wrote these stories? Beggar Queen Kestrel The Iron Ring Westmark',
    Answer: 'Lloyd Alexander',
    Metadata: 'American literature author language arts literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '140455',
    Subject: '-\fWalking Statistics',
    Question:
      'Brunhilde began her walk at 10 a.m. At 11:30 a.m., she was 4.6 miles from her starting point. To the nearest mile per hour, what was her average speed?',
    Answer: '3 mph',
    Metadata: 'average math speed problem statistics word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '55296',
    Subject: 'Emperors',
    Question:
      'By the time of his death in 1405, what handicapped Tatar emperor had conquered Persia, Mesopotamia, Afghanistan, and much of India?',
    Answer: 'Tamerlane (Timur)',
    Metadata: '15th century Asia emperor empire history people social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '60910',
    Subject: 'Revolutions',
    Question:
      'What major revolution began in Eastern Europe about the same time that the U.S. entered the First World War?',
    Answer: 'Russian Revolution',
    Metadata:
      '20th century Eastern Europe Europe history revolution social studies world history World War I',
  },
  {
    ID: '122709',
    Subject: '(Big Birds',
    Question: 'Name the largest land bird in South America.',
    Answer: 'Andean condor',
    Metadata: 'biology bird Latin America ornithology science South America zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '72420',
    Subject: '\u0002National Goals',
    Question:
      'President Kennedy committed the U.S. to landing an astronaut on the Moon before the end of which decade?',
    Answer: '1960s',
    Metadata:
      '20th century American history decade history Kennedy, John social studies space exploration',
  },
  {
    ID: '136216',
    Subject: ',!Line Equations',
    Question:
      'What is c if the graphs of these two equations are parallel lines? 2x + 5y = 7 6x + cy = 11',
    Answer: '15',
    Metadata: 'algebra equation math parallel lines',
  },
  {
    ID: '44948',
    Subject: '\u0012Infractions',
    Question: 'In reference to a certain misdemeanor, what is the meaning of DUI?',
    Answer: 'driving under the influence',
    Metadata: 'abbreviation law misdemeanor offense social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '97260',
    Subject: 'Chemistry',
    Question:
      'The condensation of a solid from a solution during a chemical reaction is called what?',
    Answer: 'precipitation',
    Metadata: 'chemical reaction chemistry condensation physical science science solution',
  },
  {
    ID: '48609',
    Subject: 'Hitler',
    Question:
      'In 1923, Adolf Hitler organized a revolt against the German government. What is the German name for this attempted coup which began in a Munich beer hall?',
    Answer: 'putsch',
    Metadata:
      '1920s 1923 20th century Germany history Hitler, Adolf Munich revolt social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '73308',
    Subject: 'Military Leaders',
    Question:
      'What American general commanded the 12th Army Group of over one million men during World War II and later became the first chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff?',
    Answer: 'Omar Bradley',
    Metadata:
      'American history Army (U.S.) general history Joint Chiefs of Staff military people social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '117837',
    Subject: '& Biomes',
    Question: 'Name the two major types of aquatic biomes.',
    Answer: 'freshwater, saltwater',
    Metadata: 'biology biome ecology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '93767',
    Subject: '\u001fFields of Science',
    Question:
      'What is the study of the motion of objects that have been launched, shot, hurled, or thrown?',
    Answer: 'ballistics',
    Metadata: 'field of science general science motion physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '73417',
    Subject: 'State Capitals',
    Question:
      'What is the capital of the state that gave its name to the battleship upon which the Japanese formally surrendered to end World War II?',
    Answer: 'Jefferson City',
    Metadata:
      '1940s 1945 20th century American geography American history battleship capital city history social studies World War II',
  },
  {
    ID: '147939',
    Subject: '1\tSpiritually Transported',
    Question:
      "What kind of vehicle appears in the refrain of the spiritual that includes this verse? If you get there before I do, Comin' for to carry me home, Tell all my friends I'm comin' there too, Comin' for to carry me home.",
    Answer: 'chariot',
    Metadata: 'fine arts lyrics music poetry quote refrain song spiritual',
  },
  {
    ID: '98546',
    Subject: '! Piggyback Rides',
    Question:
      'Sometimes a space shuttle had to land somewhere other than the Kennedy Space Center. For its trip back to Florida, it was bolted to the top of what model of aircraft?',
    Answer: '(Boeing) 747',
    Metadata: 'aircraft aviation earth science science space exploration space shuttle',
  },
  {
    ID: '119598',
    Subject: '! Spores',
    Question: 'Name the spore-containing structure that forms at the end of a hypha.',
    Answer: 'sporangium',
    Metadata: 'biology botany hypha plant anatomy plant reproduction science spore',
  },
  {
    ID: '115747',
    Subject: '& Life',
    Question:
      'Name the macromolecules from which these compounds are built. collagen hormones hemoglobin enzymes',
    Answer: 'proteins (or monomers)',
    Metadata:
      'biology collagen enzyme hemoglobin hormone life macromolecule organic chemistry physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '127792',
    Subject: 'Fields of Medicine',
    Question:
      'What medical specialist is especially trained to deal with these conditions? torn meniscus anterior cruciate ligament injury articular cartilage injury patellar tendinitis rotator cuff injury',
    Answer: 'orthopedist (orthopedic surgeon)',
    Metadata: 'health injury medical specialist science',
  },
  {
    ID: '58028',
    Subject: 'Asian Taxation',
    Question:
      'The infamous salt tax of India was finally repealed in 1946 when what nationalist politician became prime minister of the interim government?',
    Answer: 'Jawaharlal Nehru',
    Metadata: '1940s 20th century Asia history India prime minister social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '131770',
    Subject: '*\u0002Scientific Notation Multiplication',
    Question: 'Multiply 4 times 10 to the 3rd power by 4 times 10 squared.',
    Answer: '16 times 10 to the 5th power',
    Metadata: 'math multiplication scientific notation',
  },
  {
    ID: '123792',
    Subject: '(Bear Attacks',
    Question:
      "What species of bear was responsible for these fatalities? Kevin Kammer in Montana's Gallatin National Forest Erwin Evert in Wyoming's Shoshone National Forest John Wallace in Yellowstone National Park Richard White in Denali National Park",
    Answer: 'grizzly bear',
    Metadata: 'bear biology science wildlife zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '85245',
    Subject: 'Landforms',
    Question:
      'Reminiscent of a certain barnyard animal, what are steep, sharp, even-crested ridges formed by the erosion of highly tilted strata called?',
    Answer: 'hogbacks',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology landform science stratigraphy',
  },
  {
    ID: '41107',
    Subject: 'U.S. Government Foundations',
    Question:
      'The U.S. Founding Father, George Mason, said this in support of what kind of limits? Nothing is so essential to the preservation of a Republican government as a periodic rotation.',
    Answer: 'term limits',
    Metadata:
      'American government Founding Father government history Mason, George quote social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '98783',
    Subject: '!Anthropology',
    Question:
      'Up until about 30,000 years ago, there were two species of human beings coexisting on the planet. Which one became extinct?',
    Answer: 'Neanderthal man',
    Metadata: 'anthropology extinction history Homo sapiens science social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '150234',
    Subject: '4Home Repairs',
    Question:
      'Name the material used to make airtight seals by filling in cracks around windows and doors.',
    Answer: 'caulking',
    Metadata: 'construction insulation vocational',
  },
  {
    ID: '22628',
    Subject: 'Medical Wordplay',
    Question:
      'What word with a double meaning completes this joke? A man rushed into a doctor\'s office and shouted, "Doctor! I think I\'m shrinking. You\'ve got to help me right now." The doctor said, "Settle down. You\'ll just have to be a little ..."',
    Answer: 'patient',
    Metadata: 'double-entendre language arts wordplay',
  },
  {
    ID: '14133',
    Subject: 'Shakespeare',
    Question:
      'What Shakespearean play opens with this? When shall we three meet again In thunder, lightning, or in rain?',
    Answer: 'Macbeth',
    Metadata:
      'drama (Shakespeare) English literature language arts literary beginning literature quote Shakespeare',
  },
  {
    ID: '40507',
    Subject: 'Congress',
    Question:
      'When the U.S. presidency and the Senate are controlled by a different party than the one controlling the House, what is the title of the House member who is the de facto leader of the opposition?',
    Answer: 'speaker of the House',
    Metadata:
      'American government Congress government House of Representatives legislative branch social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '34997',
    Subject: 'Lofty Places',
    Question:
      'On the border between France and Italy is the highest mountain in the Alps. Name it.',
    Answer: 'Mont Blanc',
    Metadata: 'Alps Europe France geography Italy mountain mountain range peak social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '72098',
    Subject: 'Military Journalism',
    Question: 'Name the U.S. Army newspaper first published in 1918 and continuing to this day.',
    Answer: 'Stars and Stripes',
    Metadata:
      '20th century American history Army (U.S.) history journalism military newspaper social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '26954',
    Subject: 'French Expressions',
    Question:
      "Translate the last four words in this expression made by Talleyrand to Napoleon in 1813. C'est le commencement de la fin.",
    Answer: 'beginning of the end',
    Metadata: 'foreign language French language language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '32624',
    Subject: 'Steamshipping',
    Question:
      'If you pilot your steamship from the Panama Canal to the capital of the Dominican Republic, you cross what sea?',
    Answer: 'Caribbean Sea',
    Metadata: 'Dominican Republic geography Panama sea social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '90410',
    Subject: '\u001f Sound',
    Question:
      'What term refers to the characteristics of an auditorium with regard to the degree to which speech and music may be heard clearly throughout their interiors?',
    Answer: 'acoustics',
    Metadata: 'architecture auditorium physical science physics science sound',
  },
  {
    ID: '34706',
    Subject: 'Compass Reading',
    Question: 'On a compass, what direction is opposite of WSW?',
    Answer: 'ENE (east northeast)',
    Metadata: 'compass geography social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '138455',
    Subject: ',Radicals',
    Question: 'Solve this equation for y. 7 + 2(square root of y) = 19',
    Answer: '36',
    Metadata: 'algebra math radical (math)',
  },
  {
    ID: '78891',
    Subject: '\u001a Nebulae',
    Question:
      'An absorption nebula is seen in silhouette because it absorbs or blocks light from behind it. What is another name for such a diffuse mass of interstellar gas and dust?',
    Answer: 'dark nebula',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science interstellar gas nebula science universe',
  },
  {
    ID: '35020',
    Subject: 'Controversial Constructions',
    Question:
      'Standing 49 meters tall, the massive African Renaissance Monument was formally opened in 2010 in Dakar, the capital of what country?',
    Answer: 'Senegal',
    Metadata: 'Africa capital city geography monument social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '118606',
    Subject: '&! Anthropology',
    Question: 'During what geological period in the Cenozoic era did Homo sapiens appear?',
    Answer: 'Quaternary period',
    Metadata:
      'anthropology biology Cenozoic era evolution geologic era geologic time Homo sapiens paleontology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '4894',
    Subject: '\u0002Ballpark Poetry',
    Question:
      'Consider these lines from "Casey at the Bat." And Blake the much despised tore the cover off the ball. And when the dust had risen And they saw what had occurred, There was Jimmy safe at second. Who was a-hugging third?',
    Answer: 'Flynn',
    Metadata: 'American literature baseball Casey at the Bat language arts literature poetry quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '65528',
    Subject: 'Statesmen',
    Question:
      'Daniel Webster was the architect of the Webster-Ashburton Treaty, which established the definitive border between Maine and what province?',
    Answer: 'New Brunswick',
    Metadata:
      '1840s 1842 19th century American history border Canada geography history Maine province social studies Webster, Daniel Webster-Ashburton Treaty',
  },
  {
    ID: '17247',
    Subject: 'Direct Objects',
    Question:
      'What is the direct object in this example? While climbing into her new pickup truck, Natalie Finch, known for her distinctively bad taste in shoes, made an unnecessary comment about the utility of alligators.',
    Answer: 'comment',
    Metadata: 'direct object grammar language arts sentence analysis',
  },
  {
    ID: '40244',
    Subject: 'Government',
    Question: 'What is the general term for a level of government smaller than a U.S. state?',
    Answer: 'local government',
    Metadata: 'American government government social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '1727',
    Subject: 'Legends',
    Question:
      'What was devised by King Arthur to preempt rivalry among members of his entourage for a seat at the hall table?',
    Answer: 'Round Table',
    Metadata: 'English literature King Arthur language arts legend literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '131456',
    Subject: '*Exponents',
    Question: 'In the expression 9 to the 15th power, what is the base?',
    Answer: '9',
    Metadata: 'exponent math number',
  },
  {
    ID: '83226',
    Subject: 'Mountains',
    Question:
      'Although it is the highest mountain in the world, most of it is under water. Name it.',
    Answer: 'Mauna Kea',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology Hawaii mountain science',
  },
  {
    ID: '25075',
    Subject: 'A Ticklish Question',
    Question: 'What is the four-syllable noun for the sensation produced by tickling?',
    Answer: 'titillation',
    Metadata: 'language arts sensation vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '67416',
    Subject: 'Reconstruction',
    Question: 'What were Southerners who cooperated with the carpetbaggers called?',
    Answer: 'scalawags',
    Metadata:
      '1860s 19th century American history carpetbagger history Reconstruction social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '118301',
    Subject: '& Phages',
    Question: 'What life form is host to a bacteriophage?',
    Answer: 'bacterium (bacteria)',
    Metadata: 'bacteriophage biology microorganism prokaryote science virus',
  },
  {
    ID: '14174',
    Subject: 'Shakespearean Stereotypes',
    Question:
      'What stereotypical character created by Shakespeare is a bawdy, rotund comic knight?',
    Answer: 'Falstaff',
    Metadata: 'English literature language arts literature Shakespeare stereotype',
  },
  {
    ID: '95455',
    Subject: 'Distillation',
    Question:
      'What resource is commonly separated into many substances through fractional distillation?',
    Answer: 'oil (petroleum, crude oil)',
    Metadata:
      'chemical process chemistry distillation fractional distillation physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '128277',
    Subject: 'Reflexes',
    Question: 'What highly contagious reflex behavior is associated with exhaustion and boredom?',
    Answer: 'yawning',
    Metadata: 'biology health physiology reflex science',
  },
  {
    ID: '53433',
    Subject: 'Bad Bees',
    Question:
      'The African killer bees that have now spread to several parts of the United States descended from bees that escaped from a breeding experiment in what South American country?',
    Answer: 'Brazil',
    Metadata:
      'bee entomology history insect killer bee Latin America social studies South America world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '76233',
    Subject: '\u0002State History',
    Question:
      "These are part of the history of what U.S. state? Treaty of Payne's Landing Dade Massacre Third Seminole War",
    Answer: 'Florida',
    Metadata: 'American history history social studies state history',
  },
  {
    ID: '130601',
    Subject: '*Cube Roots',
    Question: 'What is the cube root of 64(y cubed)?',
    Answer: '4y',
    Metadata: 'cube root math',
  },
  {
    ID: '118247',
    Subject: '&Symbiosis',
    Question:
      'Unlike larger predators, what kind of predator usually lives in a symbiotic relationship within its prey or on its surface?',
    Answer: 'parasites',
    Metadata: 'biology predator science symbiosis',
  },
  {
    ID: '26209',
    Subject: 'Bathing',
    Question: 'What is the Italian word for "bath"?',
    Answer: 'bagno',
    Metadata: 'foreign language Italian language language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '21093',
    Subject: 'Prefixes',
    Question:
      'What does the prefix mean in these words? hemistitch hemihydrate hemialgia hemisphere',
    Answer: 'half',
    Metadata: 'affix language arts prefix',
  },
  {
    ID: '97241',
    Subject: '\u0002Standards',
    Question:
      'Under what monetary standard is the basic unit of currency defined by a stated quantity of the element whose symbol is Au?',
    Answer: 'gold standard',
    Metadata: 'chemical symbol currency economics social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '90604',
    Subject: '\u001f\u0002Electricity',
    Question: 'What is a wire wound round a solid tubular object called?',
    Answer: 'coil (winding)',
    Metadata: 'electricity physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '54430',
    Subject: 'Oceania History',
    Question:
      'Name the capital of the country in which the Maoris fought several wars during the 19th century over disputed land sales.',
    Answer: 'Wellington',
    Metadata:
      '19th century capital city history Maori Oceania revolution social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '50449',
    Subject: 'Religious Heritage',
    Question: 'If you alphabetize the three principal Hindu deities, which is last?',
    Answer: 'Vishnu',
    Metadata: 'Hindu Hindu myth history humanities myth religion social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '38647',
    Subject: 'The House',
    Question:
      'What rule in the House of Representatives allows unlimited amendments of legislation to be offered with unlimited time to debate each proposed amendment?',
    Answer: 'open rule',
    Metadata:
      'American government government House of Representatives legislative branch social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '82270',
    Subject: 'Distinctive Topography',
    Question:
      'Karst landforms are generally the result of mildly acidic water acting on soluble bedrock such as dolostone or what common sedimentary rock consisting of calcium carbonate?',
    Answer: 'limestone',
    Metadata:
      'bedrock calcium carbonate earth science geology karst topography petrology science speleology',
  },
  {
    ID: '118798',
    Subject: '&Organic Chemistry',
    Question: 'Amino acids link together in chains to form what?',
    Answer: 'proteins (peptides, polypeptides)',
    Metadata: 'amino acid biology organic chemistry science',
  },
  {
    ID: '149654',
    Subject: '4\u0002Wiring',
    Question: 'Name the devices into which electric cords are plugged.',
    Answer: 'receptacles (outlets)',
    Metadata: 'construction vocational wiring',
  },
  {
    ID: '35461',
    Subject: 'Big Cities',
    Question: 'While Ankara is the second-largest city in Turkey, what is the largest?',
    Answer: 'Istanbul',
    Metadata: 'Asia city geography social studies Turkey',
  },
  {
    ID: '47801',
    Subject: 'Languages',
    Question: 'People in Denmark speak what Germanic language?',
    Answer: 'Danish',
    Metadata: 'Denmark Europe language arts linguistics',
  },
  {
    ID: '139001',
    Subject: '-Time Measures',
    Question: '7200 seconds equals how many hours?',
    Answer: '2',
    Metadata: 'math time time problem word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '51449',
    Subject: 'Disharmony',
    Question:
      'What Russian leader was severely criticized by his countrymen for waiting several days before requesting international assistance in the attempted rescue of 118 men trapped on a sunken submarine?',
    Answer: 'Vladimir Putin',
    Metadata:
      '2000 2000s 21st century disaster history Russia social studies submarine tragedy world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '119277',
    Subject: ' Syrup',
    Question:
      'When you tap a maple tree for syrup, you want not xylem but a certain type of sap. Name it.',
    Answer: 'phloem',
    Metadata: 'biology botany maple sap science vascular tissue',
  },
  {
    ID: '25703',
    Subject: 'Plural Spelling',
    Question: 'Spell the plural of "trousseau."',
    Answer: 'trousseaux (or trousseaus)',
    Metadata: 'language arts plural spelling',
  },
  {
    ID: '69198',
    Subject: 'Madison',
    Question:
      'What word is missing from this quote by James Madison? I believe there are more instances of the abridgment of the ---- of the people by gradual and silent encroachment of those in power than by violent and sudden usurpation.',
    Answer: 'freedom',
    Metadata: '18th century American history history Madison, James quote social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '9445',
    Subject: '\u0002 Settings',
    Question: 'Name the town in which Stephen King\'s "Needful Things" is set.',
    Answer: 'Castle Rock',
    Metadata: 'American literature King, Stephen language arts literature novel setting',
  },
  {
    ID: '142204',
    Subject: '.\tPhilosophy',
    Question:
      'These ideas are part of whose philosophy? Happiness is activity of soul. The false and the trivial pass away. No one may do wrong intentionally. The unexamined life is not worth living.',
    Answer: 'Socrates',
    Metadata:
      'ancient Greece ancient literature Greek literature humanities language arts literature philosophy quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '94664',
    Subject: '\u001fNuclear Reactions',
    Question:
      'Which kind of nuclear reaction produces no particulate air pollution or radioactive waste products?',
    Answer: 'nuclear fusion',
    Metadata: 'nuclear reaction physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '146221',
    Subject: '1Classical Music',
    Question:
      'Name the composer of these works. The Emperor Concerto Missa Solemnis Fidelio Pathetique',
    Answer: 'Ludwig van Beethoven',
    Metadata:
      'classical music composer concerto fine arts humanities music Pathetique symphony sonata',
  },
  {
    ID: '143003',
    Subject: '0 Images',
    Question: 'What is an image or representation of a saint or angel called?',
    Answer: 'an icon',
    Metadata: 'angel art fine arts humanities religion saint vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '23106',
    Subject: 'Etymology',
    Question:
      'The words captain, capital, caprice, biceps and cadet are derived from the Latin word "caput" which means what?',
    Answer: 'head',
    Metadata: 'etymology language arts root word',
  },
  {
    ID: '51402',
    Subject: 'Murders',
    Question:
      'Jack the Ripper made the London headlines in 1888 when several streetwalkers were killed. Scotland Yard found no solution to these crimes, and it was later alleged that agents of what queen murdered the women to hush up a scandal involving her grandson, Albert?',
    Answer: 'Victoria',
    Metadata:
      '1880s 19th century Great Britain history Jack the Ripper London monarch queen scandal social studies United Kingdom world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '40670',
    Subject: 'Political Pieces',
    Question:
      'These are the equivalent of U.S. states in what European country? Vestfold, Svalbard, Fjordane, Telemark, Nordland',
    Answer: 'Norway',
    Metadata: 'Europe geography government social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '76509',
    Subject: 'Political Symbols',
    Question: 'What feline was a symbol of Tammany Hall?',
    Answer: 'tiger',
    Metadata: 'American history history New York social studies symbol Tammany Hall',
  },
  {
    ID: '117928',
    Subject: '&Genetics',
    Question: 'What is the name for one of several forms of the same gene?',
    Answer: 'allele',
    Metadata: 'biology gene genetics science vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '116976',
    Subject: '&\fMistaken Opinion',
    Question:
      'In 1770, John Wesley wrote, "Death is never permitted to destroy even the most inconsiderable species." But the fossil record shows that myriads of life forms no longer exist. What is the word for such life forms that are gone forever?',
    Answer: 'extinct',
    Metadata:
      '1770 1770s 18th century biology death ecology fossil life quote science Wesley, John',
  },
  {
    ID: '143050',
    Subject: '0! Painters',
    Question:
      'Name the French impressionist whose paintings include these works. Luncheon of the Boating Party Madame Charpentier and her Children Girl Doing her Hair Lady Sewing On the Terrace After the Bath',
    Answer: 'Auguste Renoir',
    Metadata: 'art art history fine arts humanities impressionism painter painting',
  },
  {
    ID: '76863',
    Subject: 'World Fairs',
    Question:
      "The Centennial International Exhibition, the first official World's Fair in the U.S., was held in Philadelphia during what year?",
    Answer: '1876',
    Metadata: "American history history social studies world's fair",
  },
  {
    ID: '79771',
    Subject: '\u001aMoons',
    Question:
      'These are characteristics of what planetary moon? -the sixth largest moon in the solar system -discovered by Galileo -one of the smoothest surfaces in the solar system -surface composed of water ice -orbits Jupiter',
    Answer: 'Europa',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science Jupiter moon (planetary) science',
  },
  {
    ID: '137231',
    Subject: ',\u0002Algebraic Factoring',
    Question: 'Factor 9(x squared) - 4(y squared).',
    Answer: '(3x + 2y)(3x - 2y)',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic factoring math',
  },
  {
    ID: '93017',
    Subject: '\u001fMirages',
    Question:
      'While a mirage is said to be inferior when the image is seen beneath the real object, what kind of mirage is seen above a real object?',
    Answer: 'superior mirage',
    Metadata: 'antonym light mirage physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '129957',
    Subject: '*Square Roots',
    Question: 'The square root of 53 is between what two integers?',
    Answer: '7 and 8',
    Metadata: 'math square root',
  },
  {
    ID: '135711',
    Subject: ',Algebra',
    Question: 'What are the two solutions for this equation? x squared - 3 = 22',
    Answer: '5, -5',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic equation equation math quadratic equation',
  },
  {
    ID: '120991',
    Subject: '(\u0002Animal Characteristics',
    Question:
      'Quadruped amphibians with smooth, moist skin, no scales, no claws, a blunt nose, and bulging eyes are classified as what kind of animals?',
    Answer: 'salamanders',
    Metadata: 'biology quadruped science taxonomy zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '35776',
    Subject: 'Volcanic Mountains',
    Question:
      'Glass Mountain in northeastern California is a nearly treeless outcropping named for its abundance of what volcanic rock?',
    Answer: 'obsidian (or pumice)',
    Metadata: 'California geography petrology rock social studies volcano',
  },
  {
    ID: '137522',
    Subject: ',Squares',
    Question:
      'Algebraically represent the side of a square whose area is 4(y squared) + 4y + 1 square inches.',
    Answer: '2y + 1 inches',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic expression area geometry math plane geometry quadrilateral',
  },
  {
    ID: '26338',
    Subject: 'German',
    Question: 'What is the meaning of the German word "Abendland"?',
    Answer: 'the West (occident)',
    Metadata: 'foreign language German language language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '69210',
    Subject: 'Fights',
    Question:
      'Perhaps there has been no fight in American history so filled with racial hostility as the one between Jack Johnson and Jim Jeffries in 1910 held in what Nevada city?',
    Answer: 'Reno',
    Metadata:
      '1910 1910s 20th century American geography American history black history boxing city history Nevada social studies sports history state geography',
  },
  {
    ID: '34628',
    Subject: 'Rivers',
    Question: 'The headwaters of the Parana River are in what country?',
    Answer: 'Brazil',
    Metadata: 'geography headwaters Parana River river social studies South America',
  },
  {
    ID: '139677',
    Subject: '-Money Problems',
    Question: "What is the cost of 72 miles of old Gilligan's Island film costing $87.50 per mile?",
    Answer: '$6,300',
    Metadata: 'fraction math word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '22176',
    Subject: 'Soviet Vocabulary',
    Question:
      'What five-letter English word was borrowed from the abbreviation of the Soviet organization whose name translates as the "Main Directorate of Corrective Labor Camps"?',
    Answer: 'gulag',
    Metadata: 'abbreviation borrowed word etymology language arts Soviet Union vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '33846',
    Subject: 'Latin America',
    Question: 'Name the two northernmost Central American countries.',
    Answer: 'Belize, Guatemala',
    Metadata: 'Central America geography Latin America social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '140590',
    Subject: '-\fFields of View',
    Question:
      'Your binoculars have a field of view of 600 feet at 1000 yards. To the nearest whole degree, what is the subtended angle?',
    Answer: 'accept 11 or 12 degrees',
    Metadata: 'angle binoculars field of view math word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '1576',
    Subject: 'Characteristic Quotes',
    Question:
      'What character in "Alice and Wonderland" repetitively asked Alice this question? Who are you?',
    Answer: 'the Caterpillar',
    Metadata:
      'Alice in Wonderland English literature language arts literary character literature quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '146328',
    Subject: '1Operas',
    Question:
      'An opera based on the successful play, "Porgy," by DuBose Heyward and set in Charleston, South Carolina was written by what American composer?',
    Answer: 'George Gershwin',
    Metadata: 'composer fine arts Heyward, DuBose humanities music opera',
  },
  {
    ID: '89156',
    Subject: '\u001fEnergy',
    Question:
      'Atoms are excited when they are struck by x-rays and ultraviolet rays and give off heat and what else?',
    Answer: 'light (radiation)',
    Metadata: 'energy physical science physics science ultraviolet radiation x-ray',
  },
  {
    ID: '50803',
    Subject: 'Opened Passes',
    Question:
      'In 2006, the Nathu La Pass reopened after 44 years of being sealed during the Sino-Indian War. It connects India and what country?',
    Answer: "China (People's Republic of China)",
    Metadata: '21st century Asia geography history India pass social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '87574',
    Subject: '\u001dAtmospheric Pressure',
    Question:
      'The center of high atmospheric pressure known as the Azores High is more commonly known in North America by what other name reminiscent of an archipelago of British islands?',
    Answer: 'Bermuda High',
    Metadata: 'atmospheric pressure earth science meteorology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '113559',
    Subject: '%The Spine',
    Question:
      'The fifth lumbar vertebra rests upon what triangular bone consisting of five fused vertebrae?',
    Answer: 'sacrum',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology science skeletal system spine vertebra',
  },
  {
    ID: '139160',
    Subject: '-Time Summation',
    Question:
      'What number results when you add the number of minutes in one quarter of an hour to the number of seconds in a half minute?',
    Answer: '45',
    Metadata: 'math number problem time time problem word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '121610',
    Subject: '( Accelerated Avians',
    Question:
      'Common in parts of Africa, they can achieve speeds of up to seventy kilometers per hour. Name these flightless birds, the largest in the world.',
    Answer: 'ostriches',
    Metadata: 'Africa biology bird ornithology science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '8742',
    Subject: '\u0002 Novels',
    Question:
      "This line comes from what novel by S.E. Hinton? If you can picture a little dark puppy that had been kicked too many times and is lost in a crowd of strangers, you'll have Johnny.",
    Answer: 'The Outsiders',
    Metadata: 'American literature Hinton, S.E. language arts literature novel quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '12229',
    Subject: 'Aesop',
    Question:
      "That it is one thing to suggest a plan but quite another to actually carry it out is the moral to which of Aesop's fables about a feline and a hollow, metal, cup-shaped instrument that emits a tone when struck?",
    Answer: 'Belling the Cat',
    Metadata: "Aesop children's literature fable language arts literature moral",
  },
  {
    ID: '132031',
    Subject: '+Triangles',
    Question: 'The sum of the angles in any triangle equals how many degrees?',
    Answer: '180',
    Metadata: 'geometry math plane geometry triangle',
  },
  {
    ID: '61889',
    Subject: 'Airlifts',
    Question:
      'Germany was divided into four sectors after World War II. When the Soviet Union blockaded Berlin, the nation responsible for which of the other three sectors provided the least assistance in the Berlin airlift?',
    Answer: 'France',
    Metadata: 'Berlin Berlin airlift Europe Germany history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '69138',
    Subject: 'International Disputes',
    Question:
      'What American secretary of state unsuccessfully tried to settle the Alabama Claims before leaving office in 1869?',
    Answer: 'William Seward',
    Metadata: '1860s Alabama Claims American history history secretary of state social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '32015',
    Subject: 'Islands',
    Question: 'Name the second largest island in Europe after Great Britain.',
    Answer: 'Iceland',
    Metadata: 'Europe geography island social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '129941',
    Subject: '*Measurement Conversions',
    Question: 'Multiply by 0.3937 to convert centimeters to what other measure?',
    Answer: 'inches',
    Metadata: 'length math measurement metric',
  },
  {
    ID: '63402',
    Subject: 'Missed Vistas',
    Question:
      'Name the most notable bay that Juan Cabrillo apparently never saw during his voyage in 1542.',
    Answer: 'San Francisco Bay',
    Metadata: '16th century American history bay Cabrillo, Juan explorer history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '97518',
    Subject: 'Chemical Reactions',
    Question:
      'What chemical reaction between a fuel and an oxidizing agent produces heat and usually light.',
    Answer: 'combustion (burning, oxidation)',
    Metadata: 'chemical reaction chemistry oxidation physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '65376',
    Subject: 'Remote Roads',
    Question:
      'What highway stretches 1422 miles from Dawson Creek, British Columbia to Delta Junction, Alaska?',
    Answer: 'Alaska (Alcan) Highway',
    Metadata:
      'Alaska American history British Columbia highway history social studies transportation',
  },
  {
    ID: '134346',
    Subject: '+\u0002Geometry Vocabulary',
    Question: 'What adjective indicates any two lines that cross at exactly one point?',
    Answer: 'intersecting',
    Metadata: 'geometry line math plane geometry vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '114407',
    Subject: '%Vision',
    Question: 'Which type of photoreceptors in your eyes are more sensitive to light?',
    Answer: 'rods',
    Metadata: 'biology eye photoreceptor physiology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '77317',
    Subject: '\u001a NASA',
    Question: 'The Ranger and the Surveyor space programs explored what heavenly body?',
    Answer: 'the Moon',
    Metadata:
      '20th century astronomy astronomy history earth science earth science history NASA science science history social studies space program spacecraft',
  },
  {
    ID: '88436',
    Subject: '\u001fOptics',
    Question:
      'A coin is placed in a cup and you look over the rim into the cup so that the coin is just out of sight. Water is then poured into the cup and the coin comes into view. What causes this phenomenon?',
    Answer: 'refraction',
    Metadata: 'light optics physical science physics science',
  },
  {
    ID: '31578',
    Subject: 'Lakes',
    Question: 'These lakes are in what country? Lake Athabasca Reindeer Lake Great Bear Lake',
    Answer: 'Canada',
    Metadata: 'geography Great Bear Lake lake Lake Athabasca social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '64939',
    Subject: 'U.S. Eras',
    Question: 'What was prohibited during the era of Prohibition in the U.S.?',
    Answer: 'alcoholic beverages (spirits)',
    Metadata: '1920s 20th century American history history Prohibition social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '31762',
    Subject: 'Europe',
    Question:
      'The independent republic of San Marino is entirely surrounded by what other country?',
    Answer: 'Italy',
    Metadata: 'border Europe geography San Marino social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '120485',
    Subject: 'Leaf Anatomy',
    Question:
      'Closely packed, columnar cells just beneath the upper epidermis of a leaf that contain many chloroplasts are called what kind of cells?',
    Answer: 'palisade cells',
    Metadata: 'biology botany cell chloroplast leaf plant anatomy science',
  },
  {
    ID: '29660',
    Subject: 'Italian Rivers',
    Question: 'The headwaters of the Po River are in what mountains?',
    Answer: 'Alps',
    Metadata: 'Europe geography headwaters Italy mountain range Po River social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '10681',
    Subject: 'Story Telling',
    Question: 'What is phrase for the perspective from which a story is told?',
    Answer: 'point of view',
    Metadata: 'language arts literary technique literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '48083',
    Subject: '\u0002Crises',
    Question:
      'An international crisis centered on what island while Nikita Khrushchev was Soviet premier?',
    Answer: 'Cuba',
    Metadata:
      '1960s 1961 20th century history Khrushchev, Nikita premier social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '51683',
    Subject: 'Wars',
    Question: 'The French and Indian War was part of what larger European conflict?',
    Answer: "Seven Years' War",
    Metadata:
      '18th century American history French and Indian War history social studies war world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '135576',
    Subject: ',Mixture Problems',
    Question:
      'How many fluid ounces of water must be added to 20 ounces of a 15% solution of methanol to reduce it to a solution that is 10% methanol?',
    Answer: '10',
    Metadata: 'algebra math mixture problem solution problem word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '33408',
    Subject: 'Gulfs',
    Question:
      'West of Cambodia is what gulf that gets its name from the country just north of Cambodia?',
    Answer: 'Gulf of Thailand',
    Metadata: 'Asia Cambodia geography gulf social studies Southeast Asia',
  },
  {
    ID: '93261',
    Subject: '\u001f\u0002Camping Physics',
    Question:
      'Wayne went camping but because he forgot his sleeping bag and pad, he had to snooze just wrapped up in a plastic tarp. Through what process will he lose a great deal of body heat to the ground?',
    Answer: 'conduction',
    Metadata: 'heat transfer physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '137754',
    Subject: ',Number Problems',
    Question:
      'What is the two-digit number given that it is five times its unit digit and when the digits are reversed, the new number is 27 greater than the original number?',
    Answer: '25',
    Metadata: 'algebra math number problem word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '134789',
    Subject: '+\u0002 Cubes',
    Question:
      'In meters, what are the dimensions of a cube with a surface area numerically the same as its volume?',
    Answer: '6 x 6 x 6 meters',
    Metadata: 'cube geometry math solid geometry surface area volume',
  },
  {
    ID: '136674',
    Subject: ',Algebraic Expansion',
    Question: 'Expand the following. (2x - y)(2x + y)',
    Answer: '4(x squared) - y squared',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic expansion math',
  },
  {
    ID: '144869',
    Subject: '0Glazing',
    Question: 'In ceramics, what is the opposite of gloss glaze?',
    Answer: 'matte glaze',
    Metadata: 'ceramics fine arts glaze (ceramics) humanities pottery',
  },
  {
    ID: '145191',
    Subject: '0Cinema History',
    Question:
      'What French phrase, literally meaning "black film," is used to describe the menacing and cynical American crime movies released in the decade after World War II?',
    Answer: 'film noir',
    Metadata: 'borrowed word cinema fine arts French language',
  },
  {
    ID: '142857',
    Subject: '0!Paintings',
    Question:
      'Who painted these works? -The Nude Maja -The Clothed Maja -Saturn Devouring His Son -The Executions of the 3rd of May',
    Answer: 'Francisco Goya',
    Metadata: 'art fine arts humanities painter painting',
  },
  {
    ID: '147944',
    Subject: '1Crime Songs',
    Question:
      'What crime is common to all these songs? Lord Randall Frankie and Johnny Delilah Stagger Lee Tom Dooley Mack the Knife',
    Answer: 'murder',
    Metadata: 'humanities lyrics music song',
  },
  {
    ID: '32426',
    Subject: 'Asia',
    Question: 'Which Asian country adjacent to the Gulf of Tonkin extends farthest east?',
    Answer: 'China',
    Metadata: 'Asia border geography gulf Gulf of Tonkin social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '11972',
    Subject: 'Legendary Aspirations',
    Question:
      'What object from Arthurian legend has come to indicate a difficult or possibly unattainable goal?',
    Answer: 'Holy Grail',
    Metadata: 'allusion King Arthur language arts legend literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '135455',
    Subject: ',Algebra',
    Question: 'Square the quantity x - 4.',
    Answer: 'x squared - 8x + 16',
    Metadata: 'algebra exponent math',
  },
  {
    ID: '7335',
    Subject: '\u0002\tNonfiction',
    Question:
      'This biography is about what author? Invincible Louisa: The Story of the Author of Little Women',
    Answer: 'Louisa May Alcott',
    Metadata:
      'American literature author biography language arts literature Little Women nonfiction woman',
  },
  {
    ID: '74293',
    Subject: 'Trails',
    Question:
      'The Nez Perce National Historic Trail goes through parts of Oregon, Idaho, Wyoming, and what other state?',
    Answer: 'Montana',
    Metadata:
      'American geography American history history national historic trail Nez Perce social studies state geography trail',
  },
  {
    ID: '66075',
    Subject: 'Cover-Ups',
    Question:
      'Who ordered a cover-up of FBI failures in the investigation of Lee Harvey Oswald to protect the public image of the Bureau he directed?',
    Answer: 'J. Edgar Hoover',
    Metadata:
      '1960s 20th century American history FBI Federal Bureau of Investigation history Oswald, Lee Harvey people social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '63258',
    Subject: 'Minutemen',
    Question:
      'It was the night of April 18th in 1775. How many lanterns did Paul Revere see that night in the tower of the Old North Church?',
    Answer: '2',
    Metadata:
      '1770s 1775 18th century American history American Revolution history Old North Church Revere, Paul social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '55445',
    Subject: 'Invasions',
    Question:
      'What Asian country has, at various times, been invaded and occupied by Alexander the Great, Arabs, Turks, Mongols, British, Soviets, and Americans?',
    Answer: 'Afghanistan',
    Metadata: 'Asia history invasion social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '145934',
    Subject: '1 Lullabies',
    Question: 'What composer is famed for a lullaby that bears his name?',
    Answer: 'Brahms',
    Metadata: 'composer fine arts humanities lullaby music',
  },
  {
    ID: '44049',
    Subject: '\u0012Crime Rhymes',
    Question: 'What term that rhymes with "dwindle" means to cheat through trickery or fraud?',
    Answer: 'swindle',
    Metadata: 'crime fraud law social studies vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '5498',
    Subject: '\u0002Short Stories',
    Question:
      'What story begins with this dialogue? "Off there to the right - somewhere - is a large island," said Whitney. "It\'s rather a mystery." "What island is it?" Rainsford asked.',
    Answer: 'The Most Dangerous Game',
    Metadata:
      'American literature Connell, Richard language arts literary beginning literary character literature quote short story',
  },
  {
    ID: '14269',
    Subject: 'Mythical Wives',
    Question:
      "Cepheus' wife boasted she was more beautiful than the Nereids. Poseidon sent a sea monster to prey upon Greece which could only be appeased by the sacrifice of Andromeda. Who was Cepheus' wife?",
    Answer: 'Cassiopeia',
    Metadata: 'Andromeda Cepheus Greek myth language arts myth Nereid Poseidon',
  },
  {
    ID: '15708',
    Subject: 'Phrases',
    Question:
      'What kind of phrase occurs before the verb in these examples? -The long and winding trail was not made for the timid. -The old, gnarled, gashed tree stood alone in the field. -Several geese landed on the frozen lake. -A rumor began circulating last Monday.',
    Answer: 'noun phrase',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts phrase sentence analysis',
  },
  {
    ID: '24347',
    Subject: 'Alternades',
    Question:
      'Alternade is the creation of multiple words by skipping letters. By using every third letter in "lacerated" there are three words. What is the third word?',
    Answer: 'cad',
    Metadata: 'alternade language arts wordplay',
  },
  {
    ID: '22982',
    Subject: 'Fallacies',
    Question:
      'What fallacy is illustrated in this answer by Miss Alabama during a Miss USA contest to the question, "If you could live forever, would you and why?" I would not live forever, because we should not live forever, because if we were supposed to live forever, then we would live forever, but we cannot live forever, which is why I would not live forever.',
    Answer: 'begging the question (circular reasoning)',
    Metadata: 'fallacy language arts logic reasoning',
  },
  {
    ID: '90242',
    Subject: '\u001fWeight',
    Question:
      "Something that weighs 128 kilograms on Earth's surface would weigh how much if it were transported to 3 Earth radii above the Earth?",
    Answer: '8 kilograms',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science gravity physical science physics science weight',
  },
  {
    ID: '74990',
    Subject: 'Trials',
    Question:
      'In 1735, twelve New York jurors, inspired by the eloquence of the best lawyer of the period, Andrew Hamilton, ignored the instructions of the Governors\'s hand-picked judges and returned a not guilty verdict, thus ending the trial of what German printer who had been charged with publishing "seditious libels"?',
    Answer: 'John Peter Zenger',
    Metadata:
      '1730s 18th century American history history New York social studies state history trial',
  },
  {
    ID: '96557',
    Subject: 'Fuels',
    Question: 'Gasohol contains what type of alcohol?',
    Answer: 'ethanol (methanol)',
    Metadata: 'alcohol (chemistry) chemistry fuel gasohol physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '99055',
    Subject: 'Pain',
    Question:
      "Prolonged pain is chronic. What adjective describes the pain one endures when one stubs one's toe on one's child's bicycle abandoned one night in the middle of one's living room?",
    Answer: 'acute',
    Metadata: 'chronic disease health pain science vocabulary \nMedical Vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '72018',
    Subject: 'Conscription',
    Question: "During what war did Congress enact America's first national draft law?",
    Answer: 'Civil War',
    Metadata: '19th century American history draft history legislation social studies war',
  },
  {
    ID: '136779',
    Subject: ',Algebraic Factoring',
    Question: 'Factor y squared - 4y + 2y - 8.',
    Answer: '(y+2)(y-4)',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic factoring math',
  },
  {
    ID: '87336',
    Subject: '\u001dStorms',
    Question:
      'Measured in terms of their wind velocity, what category of storms is next in the list after tropical depressions and tropical storms?',
    Answer: 'hurricanes (cyclones)',
    Metadata: 'earth science meteorology science storm',
  },
  {
    ID: '88675',
    Subject: '\u001f\fScience and Technology',
    Question:
      'It is possible to make materials such as crystals, oil, and vitamins which formerly were only products of nature. What adjective describes such materials made by man?',
    Answer: 'synthetic',
    Metadata: 'physical science physics science vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '47123',
    Subject: 'Historical Cities',
    Question:
      'What is the current name for the great city adjacent to the Bosporus that was at various times the capital of the Roman Empire, the Byzantine Empire, the Latin Empire, and the Ottoman Empire?',
    Answer: 'Istanbul',
    Metadata:
      'capital city city geography history Ottoman Empire social studies Turkey world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '48675',
    Subject: 'Ancient Rome',
    Question:
      'What was the ancient Roman name for Britain as a whole and for that part of Britain which the Romans controlled?',
    Answer: 'Britannia',
    Metadata: 'ancient history ancient Rome B.C. Britain history Rome social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '135951',
    Subject: ',Algebraic Equations',
    Question: 'Solve 3x + 18y = 6 for x.',
    Answer: 'x = 2-6y (or -6y+2)',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic equation equation linear equation math',
  },
  {
    ID: '58732',
    Subject: 'Ghettos',
    Question:
      'A half-million Jews were enclosed by the Germans in one small area in what Polish city after 1941?',
    Answer: 'Warsaw',
    Metadata:
      '1940s 1941 20th century city Europe ghetto history Judaism Nazi Poland social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '23634',
    Subject: 'Wordiness',
    Question:
      "What phrase could be omitted from this sentence without any loss of meaning? All things considered, Colorado's elk herd is in better shape now than ever before.",
    Answer: 'all things considered',
    Metadata: 'language arts wordiness writing error',
  },
  {
    ID: '135892',
    Subject: ',Ordered Pairs',
    Question: 'In the ordered pair, (3, -5), what is the value of y?',
    Answer: '-5',
    Metadata: 'algebra graphing math ordered pair',
  },
  {
    ID: '123691',
    Subject: '(\u0002Anatomical Orientation',
    Question: 'Which surface of most fish faces away from the sky?',
    Answer: 'ventral',
    Metadata: 'biology fish science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '138909',
    Subject: '-\u0002Interest Problems',
    Question:
      'A girl took out a loan for 1 year and 4 months. The interest rate was 6% per annum. At the end of that period she repaid $432 which included the loan and interest. How much did she borrow?',
    Answer: '$400',
    Metadata: 'interest math word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '29709',
    Subject: 'Scandinavia',
    Question: 'What country is immediately west of the country whose capital is Stockholm?',
    Answer: 'Norway',
    Metadata: 'capital city Europe geography Scandinavia social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '126131',
    Subject: '*Fractions',
    Question: 'In lowest terms, 25 minutes is what fraction of an hour?',
    Answer: '5/12',
    Metadata: 'fraction math time',
  },
  {
    ID: '126261',
    Subject: '*Temperature Conversions',
    Question: '65 degrees Celsius equals how many degrees Fahrenheit?',
    Answer: '149',
    Metadata: 'Celsius Fahrenheit math measurement physical science physics science temperature',
  },
  {
    ID: '84323',
    Subject: 'Geological Sites',
    Question:
      'What formed the long, geologically significant gouges and grooves on Kelleys Island in Ohio?',
    Answer: 'glaciers',
    Metadata: 'American geography earth science geology Ohio science state geography',
  },
  {
    ID: '19824',
    Subject: 'Clauses',
    Question:
      'What kind of clause is introduced by the relative pronoun in this example? They told us that the man who laughs last will laugh best.',
    Answer: 'adjective clause',
    Metadata: 'clause grammar language arts pronoun relative pronoun',
  },
  {
    ID: '143221',
    Subject: '0Ancient Sculptures',
    Question:
      'The body of what animal was sculpted with the head of a human on ancient Egyptian sphinxes?',
    Answer: 'lion',
    Metadata: 'ancient Egypt archaeology art Egypt fine arts humanities monument sculpture',
  },
  {
    ID: '142888',
    Subject: '0Art History',
    Question: 'Picasso and other cubists favored the use of newspaper fragments in what art form?',
    Answer: 'collage',
    Metadata: 'art art form fine arts humanities Picasso, Pablo',
  },
  {
    ID: '53207',
    Subject: 'South African History',
    Question:
      "What is the abbreviation for the political party banned under apartheid in South Africa that became the nation's ruling party in 1994?",
    Answer: 'ANC',
    Metadata:
      '1990s 1994 20th century abbreviation Africa apartheid history political party social studies South Africa world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '144670',
    Subject: '0Stationery',
    Question:
      'Name the printed heading at the top of a piece of stationery consisting of a name and address, a logo, a monogram, or other design elements?',
    Answer: 'letterhead',
    Metadata: 'correspondence fine arts language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '92841',
    Subject: '\u001f Scientific Advancement',
    Question:
      'In 1905, Albert Einstein published a series of papers that formed the basis of modern physics. Nothing comparable to such a scientific achievement by one man in one year has ever occurred except for what is known as the "annus mirabilis" when theories of color, the calculus, and the law of gravitation were established by whom?',
    Answer: 'Isaac Newton',
    Metadata:
      'calculus gravity math math history physical science physical science history physicist science science history',
  },
  {
    ID: '41525',
    Subject: 'Real Estate',
    Question:
      'Jim is trying to buy a ranch. He has given over the entire down payment to an agent who will hold that money until the seller delivers the deed. That money is said to be where?',
    Answer: 'in escrow',
    Metadata: 'deed economics real estate social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '66380',
    Subject: 'Presidential Commitments',
    Question:
      'What U.S. president committed the greatest number of U.S. troops to Vietnam battlefields?',
    Answer: 'Lyndon Johnson',
    Metadata: '20th century American history history president social studies Vietnam War war',
  },
  {
    ID: '140563',
    Subject: '-Trail Combinations',
    Question:
      'There are 3 trails between Jerkwater and Podunk and 4 trails between Podunk and Whistlestop. In how many ways can you go from Jerkwater to Whistlestop by way of Podunk?',
    Answer: '12',
    Metadata: 'combination math word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '40743',
    Subject: 'Failures',
    Question: 'What Caribbean country is an example of a failed state?',
    Answer: 'Haiti',
    Metadata: 'Caribbean failed state government social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '89375',
    Subject: '\u001f!Super Accurate Clocks',
    Question:
      'The atomic clock can measure the length of a second to an accuracy of thirteen decimal places. This clock is based on the time it takes an electron to spin on its own axis inside an atom of what element?',
    Answer: 'cesium',
    Metadata: 'atomic clock electron physical science science time',
  },
  {
    ID: '22983',
    Subject: 'Euphemisms',
    Question: 'What is a two-word phrase for "vehicularly compressed maladapted life form"?',
    Answer: 'road kill',
    Metadata: 'euphemism language arts wordplay',
  },
  {
    ID: '27253',
    Subject: 'U.S. Geography',
    Question: 'Most of the western border of Texas is formed by what state?',
    Answer: 'New Mexico',
    Metadata: 'American geography border geography social studies state geography Texas',
  },
  {
    ID: '1912',
    Subject: 'Ovid',
    Question:
      'In Ovid\'s "Metamorphoses," the first metamorphosis is the transformation of what into order?',
    Answer: 'chaos',
    Metadata:
      'ancient literature ancient Rome language arts literature Metamorphoses Ovid Roman literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '47299',
    Subject: 'Blockades',
    Question:
      'What is the term for a prolonged military blockade and assault of a city or fortress?',
    Answer: 'siege',
    Metadata: 'blockade history military social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '40211',
    Subject: 'Federal Agencies',
    Question:
      'What government agency provides Congress with estimates of how much money programs will cost and taxes will provide?',
    Answer: 'CBO (Congressional Budget Office)',
    Metadata: 'American government Congress federal agency government social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '5832',
    Subject: '\u0002American Authors',
    Question:
      "Who wrote this? Well, Mr. Buzzard he feel mighty lonesome, he did, but he done prommust Br'er Fox dat he'd stay, en' he 'termin' fer ter sorter han 'roun' en' jine in de joke.",
    Answer: 'Joel Chandler Harris',
    Metadata: 'American literature author dialect language arts literature quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '77402',
    Subject: '\u001a Galileo',
    Question:
      'Galileo used his telescope to discover that what planet passes through phases just like the Moon?',
    Answer: 'Venus',
    Metadata: '17th century astronomy astronomy history earth science Galileo science',
  },
  {
    ID: '96564',
    Subject: 'Elements',
    Question:
      'What hard, dense, brittle, silver-white, corrosion-resistant, metallic element was named after the Latin term for "rainbow," and for its iridescence when dissolved in hydrochloric acid?',
    Answer: 'iridium',
    Metadata: 'chemistry element metal physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '123436',
    Subject: '(Zoological Orders',
    Question: 'What kind of primates are these? vervet, grivet, macaque, marmoset, rhesus',
    Answer: 'monkeys',
    Metadata: 'biology mammal primate science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '144995',
    Subject: '0Art History',
    Question: 'These art forms developed in what country? ikebana, kabuki, noh, origami, bonsai',
    Answer: 'Japan',
    Metadata: 'art art form art history fine arts humanities',
  },
  {
    ID: '115181',
    Subject: '%Ligaments',
    Question:
      'In what part of the body are these ligaments located? palmar radiocarpal ligament dorsal radiocarpal ligament ulnar collateral ligament radial collateral ligament',
    Answer: 'wrist (lower arm)',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology ligament science skeletal system',
  },
  {
    ID: '70051',
    Subject: 'Presidential Relationships',
    Question:
      'This is about what U.S. president? Widowed after twenty-nine years of marriage, he was still in his first term as president when he met Edith Galt.',
    Answer: 'Woodrow Wilson',
    Metadata: '20th century American history history president social studies woman',
  },
  {
    ID: '115558',
    Subject: '&Bacteria',
    Question: 'The three shapes of bacteria are cocci, spirilla, and what other?',
    Answer: 'bacilli',
    Metadata: 'bacteria biology microorganism protist science',
  },
  {
    ID: '147146',
    Subject: '1\tGershwin',
    Question:
      'George Gershwin began his career in what New York alley with a name reminiscent of cooking utensils?',
    Answer: 'Tin Pan Alley',
    Metadata:
      'fine arts Gershwin, George humanities music music history New York New York City state geography',
  },
  {
    ID: '49150',
    Subject: 'Home Sweet Home',
    Question:
      'Since the eleventh century, the principal residence of the English royal family has been what castle?',
    Answer: 'Windsor Castle',
    Metadata:
      'castle England Great Britain history residence social studies United Kingdom world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '61690',
    Subject: 'Vanquished Frenchmen',
    Question:
      'While the War of 1812 was raging in America, Napoleon was defeated and sent into exile on what island in the Tyrrhenian Sea?',
    Answer: 'Elba',
    Metadata:
      '1810s 19th century Europe exile history island Napoleon Bonaparte social studies Tyrrhenian Sea War of 1812 world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '72569',
    Subject: 'A Hanging Audience',
    Question:
      'Among those present at the execution of John Brown were Thomas Jackson, known as "Stonewall" after Bull Run, and what popular matinee idol destined for infamy at Ford\'s Theater in 1865?',
    Answer: 'John Wilkes Booth',
    Metadata:
      "1860s 1865 19th century American history Battle of Bull Run Brown, John Ford's Theater history social studies",
  },
  {
    ID: '8017',
    Subject: '\u0002 Narrators',
    Question:
      "What fictional narrator tells the story from which this excerpt is taken? \"Law, Br'er Tarrypin!\" sez Br'er Fox, sezee, \"you ain't see no trouble yit. Ef you wanter see sho' nuff trouble, you des oughter go 'longer me; I'm de man w'at kin show you trouble', sezee.\"",
    Answer: 'Uncle Remus',
    Metadata: 'American literature language arts literary character literature narrator quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '84707',
    Subject: 'Plutons',
    Question: 'What are, by far, the largest intrusive igneous bodies?',
    Answer: 'batholiths',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology igneous rock intrusion pluton rock science',
  },
  {
    ID: '83261',
    Subject: 'Lithification',
    Question:
      'As sedimentary rocks are formed, what process gradually reduces the pore spaces between individual grains by means of the pressure exerted by overlying sediments?',
    Answer: 'compaction',
    Metadata:
      'earth science geology lithification petrology pore (geology) rock science sedimentary rock sedimentation',
  },
  {
    ID: '83754',
    Subject: 'Sedimentary Rock',
    Question:
      'Bedding planes are well-defined divisions of sedimentary rock units. They separate successive layers otherwise known as what?',
    Answer: 'strata',
    Metadata: 'bedding plane earth science geology petrology rock science sedimentary rock',
  },
  {
    ID: '23612',
    Subject: 'Reasoning',
    Question:
      "Jill's mother had four children. The first was April, the second was May, and the third was June. What was the name of her fourth child?",
    Answer: 'Jill',
    Metadata: 'language arts reasoning',
  },
  {
    ID: '23533',
    Subject: 'Root Word Etymology',
    Question:
      'The roots in these words came from what language? compel, deduce, digress, subscription',
    Answer: 'Latin',
    Metadata: 'etymology language arts root word',
  },
  {
    ID: '18832',
    Subject: 'Corrections',
    Question:
      'What three-letter symbol would an English teacher use to indicate the kind of correction needed in this sentence? Each one takes their bullet and load it.',
    Answer: 'agr',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts proofreading writing error',
  },
  {
    ID: '124489',
    Subject: '*Powers',
    Question: 'Five to the negative four power is what fraction?',
    Answer: '1/625',
    Metadata: 'exponent math negative exponent',
  },
  {
    ID: '139937',
    Subject: '-\tAcceleration',
    Question:
      'A ball rolls down an inclined plane. It rolls 2 feet in the first second, 6 feet in the next second, and 10 feet in the third second. How far will it roll during the fourth second?',
    Answer: '14',
    Metadata:
      'acceleration inclined plane math motion physical science physics science word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '59756',
    Subject: 'Reichs',
    Question: 'During what Reich was Adolf Hitler in power?',
    Answer: 'Third Reich',
    Metadata:
      '1930s 1940s 20th century Europe Germany history Hitler, Adolf social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '116731',
    Subject: '&\tBunnies',
    Question:
      'Jackrabbits and snowshoe rabbits are actually not rabbits. They are more correctly classified as what?',
    Answer: 'hares',
    Metadata: 'biology jackrabbit mammal rabbit science taxonomy wildlife zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '55619',
    Subject: '\u0002Weapons',
    Question:
      'Spears can be divided into two categories including those designed for throwing and those designed for what else?',
    Answer: 'thrusting (lunging, stabbing, jabbing, etc)',
    Metadata: 'history social studies spear weapon world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '45132',
    Subject: '\u0012Crime Vocabulary',
    Question:
      'What do lawyers call the deliberate execution of a wrongful act, without just cause or excuse, with an intent to inflict injury?',
    Answer: 'malice',
    Metadata: 'crime law offense social studies vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '154',
    Subject: 'Answers',
    Question:
      'Here\'s the answer. You quote the question. "I," said the sparrow, "with my bow and arrow."',
    Answer: 'Who killed Cock Robin?',
    Metadata:
      "bow and arrow children's literature English literature language arts literature poetry quote",
  },
  {
    ID: '128825',
    Subject: '* Clown Combinations',
    Question:
      'A clown has 5 wild wigs and 7 fabulous artificial noses. How many wig-nose combinations does he have?',
    Answer: '35',
    Metadata: 'combination math',
  },
  {
    ID: '93269',
    Subject: '\u001f States of Matter',
    Question:
      'Under normal conditions, there is no liquid phase of what gas produced by breathing and combustion?',
    Answer: 'carbon dioxide',
    Metadata: 'combustion gas physical science respiration science state of matter',
  },
  {
    ID: '149894',
    Subject: '4 Electronics History',
    Question:
      'Just before there were microchips there were transistors and just before transistors there were what other electronic devices?',
    Answer: '(vacuum) tubes',
    Metadata:
      '20th century chronology electronics history physical science physical science history science science history technology transistor',
  },
  {
    ID: '146382',
    Subject: '1\tHistory of Music',
    Question:
      'Who is this about? In September, "Die Zauberflote" was completed and he set to work feverishly upon the "Requiem," convinced that he was writing it for himself.',
    Answer: 'Wolfgang Mozart',
    Metadata:
      '18th century classical music composer fine arts humanities music music history quote requiem',
  },
  {
    ID: '126195',
    Subject: '*\fFraction Division',
    Question: 'Express in lowest terms the quotient of 5 divided by 11 2/3.',
    Answer: '3/7',
    Metadata: 'arithmetic division fraction lowest terms math quotient',
  },
  {
    ID: '58997',
    Subject: 'Weapons Testing',
    Question: 'What nation exploded its first atomic bomb in the deserts of Algeria?',
    Answer: 'France',
    Metadata:
      '20th century Africa Algeria atomic bomb Europe history North Africa physical science history science history social studies weapon world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '119439',
    Subject: '!Plant Pathology',
    Question:
      'Name the gradual, progressive death of plant shoots beginning at their tips due to injury or disease.',
    Answer: 'dieback',
    Metadata: 'biology botany plant pathology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '22435',
    Subject: 'Sayings',
    Question: "How is this cliche supposed to be stated? It'll only tell over time.",
    Answer: 'Only time will tell.',
    Metadata: 'cliche language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '137504',
    Subject: ',Algebraic Ratios',
    Question: 'What is the value of y in this ratio? (2y+8) is to (y+2) as (2y+5) is to (y+1)',
    Answer: '2',
    Metadata: 'algebra math ratio',
  },
  {
    ID: '43971',
    Subject: '\u0012 Grand Juries',
    Question:
      'A prosecuting attorney can require that you answer questions before a grand jury that are self-incriminating by guaranteeing that nothing you say will be used against you in a subsequent criminal proceeding. You have been granted what?',
    Answer: 'immunity',
    Metadata: 'attorney court grand jury jury law social studies testimony',
  },
  {
    ID: '12869',
    Subject: 'City Settings',
    Question:
      'These stories are entirely or partly set in what city? Gigi The Day of the Jackal The Phantom of the Opera A Tale of Two Cities Arch of Triumph The Hunchback of Notre Dame',
    Answer: 'Paris',
    Metadata: 'language arts literature novel setting',
  },
  {
    ID: '66869',
    Subject: 'New Arrivals',
    Question:
      'Who arrived in the Ohio Valley in 1801 with seeds from Philadelphia cider presses that soon turn this valley into a rich source of apples?',
    Answer: 'Johnny Appleseed (John Chapman)',
    Metadata:
      '1800s 1801 19th century American history apple history Ohio Valley Philadelphia social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '64381',
    Subject: 'Aviation History',
    Question:
      'What plane took off in May of 1927 from Roosevelt Field on Long Island and landed with its one occupant about 33 hours later at Le Bourget Airport near Paris?',
    Answer: 'The Spirit of St. Louis',
    Metadata:
      '1920s 1927 20th century aircraft airport American history aviation France history Lindbergh, Charles social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '87309',
    Subject: '\u001dWinds',
    Question: 'Heated by sunshine, what type of local wind blows up a slope ?',
    Answer: 'anabatic',
    Metadata: 'earth science meteorology science wind',
  },
  {
    ID: '62049',
    Subject: '\u0002Medieval Guilds',
    Question: 'In a medieval guild, what was the status of the lowest level of tradesmen?',
    Answer: 'apprentice',
    Metadata: 'Europe guild history medieval Middle Ages social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '43482',
    Subject: 'Gourmet Foods',
    Question:
      'What kind of creatures are you about to consume when your waiter brings an order of Escargot a la Bourguignonne?',
    Answer: 'snails',
    Metadata: 'home economics vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '38459',
    Subject: 'The United Nations',
    Question:
      'There are 15 members of the U.N. Security Council. In this body, how many affirmative votes are required to pass a resolution?',
    Answer: '9',
    Metadata:
      'government international relations resolution Security Council social studies United Nations',
  },
  {
    ID: '61116',
    Subject: 'English Dynasties',
    Question:
      'With monarchs including Henry VIII and Elizabeth I, what was the name of the royal family that occupied the British throne from 1485 to 1603?',
    Answer: 'Tudor',
    Metadata:
      '16th century dynasty Elizabeth I England Europe Great Britain Henry VIII history monarch social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '1638',
    Subject: 'Openings',
    Question:
      'What six words precede these in the opening of a novel? ... it was the worst of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, it was the epoch of belief, it was the epoch of incredulity.',
    Answer: 'It was the best of times',
    Metadata: 'English literature language arts literary beginning literature novel quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '36401',
    Subject: 'U.S. Representation',
    Question:
      'Which state bordered in part by the Colorado River has the greatest number of members in the U.S. House of Representatives?',
    Answer: 'California',
    Metadata:
      'American government Colorado River Congress government House of Representatives social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '138471',
    Subject: ',Algebraic Factoring',
    Question: 'Factor this expression. (x-1) squared - (y-2) squared',
    Answer: '(x-y+1)(x+y-3)',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic factoring factoring math',
  },
  {
    ID: '75005',
    Subject: 'Memorials',
    Question:
      "Perry's Victory and International Peace Memorial commemorates a battle on which of the Great Lakes?",
    Answer: 'Lake Erie',
    Metadata:
      'American history battle Great Lakes history memorial Perry, Oliver social studies War of 1812',
  },
  {
    ID: '82267',
    Subject: 'Mohs Minerals',
    Question:
      'Using the Mohs scale, what number do you get when you add the hardness number for corundum to the hardness number for diamond?',
    Answer: '19',
    Metadata: 'corundum diamond earth science geology hardness mineral Mohs scale science',
  },
  {
    ID: '128229',
    Subject: 'Vitamins',
    Question:
      'A Wisconsin biochemist discovered that irradiating many foods with ultraviolet light turns them into rich sources of what vitamin?',
    Answer: 'vitamin D',
    Metadata: 'biology health science ultraviolet radiation vitamin',
  },
  {
    ID: '15866',
    Subject: 'Sentence Analysis',
    Question:
      "Since is used as what part of speech in this sentence? Margo has no life of her own since her husband's death.",
    Answer: 'preposition',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts part of speech sentence analysis',
  },
  {
    ID: '14511',
    Subject: 'Myths',
    Question:
      'When he was born, he was plunged by Thetis into the River Styx which almost made him invulnerable. Name this most distinguished Greek of the Trojan wars.',
    Answer: 'Achilles',
    Metadata: 'Greek myth language arts literature myth Styx Thetis',
  },
  {
    ID: '25453',
    Subject: 'Autoantonyms',
    Question:
      'What noun that means an advantage in golf may also indicate a physical or mental disability?',
    Answer: 'handicap',
    Metadata: 'autoantonym language arts vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '35138',
    Subject: 'Place Names',
    Question:
      'These are sites on what continent? McMurdo Sound, Marie Byrd Land, Victoria Land, Shackleton Ice Shelf, Ross Ice Shelf',
    Answer: 'Antarctica',
    Metadata: 'continent geography social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '137582',
    Subject: ',\u0002Number Sleuthing',
    Question: 'What number equals 60% of itself plus 240?',
    Answer: '600',
    Metadata: 'algebra equation linear equation math',
  },
  {
    ID: '89175',
    Subject: '\u001f\f History of Science',
    Question: 'In scientific legend, with what fruit is Isaac Newton associated?',
    Answer: 'apple',
    Metadata:
      'legend Newton, Isaac physical science physical science history physics science science history',
  },
  {
    ID: '32882',
    Subject: 'Africa',
    Question:
      'What country adjacent to the Mediterranean forms most of the northern borders of Mali and Niger?',
    Answer: 'Algeria',
    Metadata: 'Africa border geography Mali Mediterranean Niger North Africa social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '112562',
    Subject: '#\u0002Superstitions',
    Question:
      'What ordinal number is repeatedly missing in this passage? More than 80 percent of high-rises lack a ---- floor, many airports skip the ---- gate, airplanes have no ---- aisle, and hotels regularly have no ---- room number.',
    Answer: '13th',
    Metadata: 'psychology science superstition',
  },
  {
    ID: '64174',
    Subject: 'Famous Websters',
    Question: 'What was the first name of the Webster remembered as a lexicographer?',
    Answer: 'Noah',
    Metadata:
      '19th century American history American literature author dictionary history language arts lexicography literature reference',
  },
  {
    ID: '115453',
    Subject: '%Veins',
    Question: 'Intercostal veins are adjacent to what bones?',
    Answer: 'ribs',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology bone circulatory system science skeletal system vein',
  },
  {
    ID: '144034',
    Subject: '0Shutter Speeds',
    Question:
      "Your camera's shutter speed is set to 1/500. To reduce the amount of light admitted into the camera by half, you should set the shutter speed to what?",
    Answer: '1/1000',
    Metadata: 'art camera fine arts photography shutter speed',
  },
  {
    ID: '50232',
    Subject: 'Empires',
    Question: 'The Safavid and Mogul empires were based on what religion?',
    Answer: 'Islam',
    Metadata: 'empire history Mogul religion Safavid Empire social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '34026',
    Subject: 'Seas',
    Question: 'What sea is named after a Scandinavian country?',
    Answer: 'Norwegian Sea',
    Metadata: 'Europe geography Scandinavia sea social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '58383',
    Subject: 'Great Britain',
    Question:
      'There is a continuing distrust between the Catholics and Protestants in what region of Great Britain?',
    Answer: 'Northern Ireland',
    Metadata:
      '20th century Europe Great Britain history monarch Protestant social studies United Kingdom world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '128890',
    Subject: '*Sets',
    Question: 'What kind of mathematical set includes all the even integers from 1 to 10 million?',
    Answer: 'finite set',
    Metadata: 'math set',
  },
  {
    ID: '76975',
    Subject: 'Old West Lore',
    Question:
      'Thanks to an event in Deadwood, South Dakota, in 1876, what came to be the name of a poker hand that includes a pair of eights and a pair of aces?',
    Answer: "dead man's hand",
    Metadata: '1870s American history history Old West poker social studies South Dakota',
  },
  {
    ID: '67815',
    Subject: 'Bygone Communications',
    Question:
      'Two days after the first coast-to-coast telegraph line was completed in 1861, what mail delivery service made its last trip?',
    Answer: 'Pony Express',
    Metadata:
      '1860s 1861 19th century American history communication history mail Old West social studies telegraph',
  },
  {
    ID: '85131',
    Subject: 'Geological Principles',
    Question:
      "James Hutton said that while that the Earth's landforms change over time, the geologic processes responsible for the changes do not. This became known as the principle of what?",
    Answer: 'uniformitarianism',
    Metadata:
      'earth science earth science history geological process geology Hutton, James landform science science history',
  },
  {
    ID: '92188',
    Subject: '\u001fForce',
    Question:
      'What force between two objects in contact with one another can be increased by irregularities on their surfaces or adhesion of molecules of one surface to those of the other?',
    Answer: 'friction',
    Metadata: 'adhesion force physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '117217',
    Subject: '&Skin',
    Question:
      'The skin contains numerous sensory structures such as mechanoreceptors that detect pressure, thermoreceptors that detect heat and cold, and free nerve endings that detect what?',
    Answer: 'pain',
    Metadata: 'biology nervous system science sensation',
  },
  {
    ID: '17953',
    Subject: 'Sentence Analysis',
    Question:
      'Words of what part of speech are joined by the conjunction in this example? The steak was tender, huge, yet flavorless.',
    Answer: 'adjectives',
    Metadata: 'conjunction grammar language arts part of speech sentence analysis',
  },
  {
    ID: '12323',
    Subject: 'Similes',
    Question:
      'What word should be substituted for "egg" in this simile? It is as plain as the egg on your face.',
    Answer: 'nose',
    Metadata: 'figure of speech language arts literature simile',
  },
  {
    ID: '40407',
    Subject: 'Federal Agencies',
    Question:
      'These are agencies of what executive department? Bureau of Engraving and Printing Bureau of the Public Debt Financial Crimes Enforcement Network Internal Revenue Service',
    Answer: 'Department of the Treasury',
    Metadata: 'American government executive department federal agency government social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '9569',
    Subject: 'Literary Latin',
    Question:
      'What Latin phrase that literally means "from the egg" indicates a narrative "at the beginning" of a plot and moves on in chronological order describing events until the plot ends?',
    Answer: 'ab ovo',
    Metadata: 'language arts Latin language literary technique literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '114990',
    Subject: '%Teeth',
    Question: 'What category of teeth have two cusps?',
    Answer: 'bicuspids',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology science tooth',
  },
  {
    ID: '118353',
    Subject: '&Ecological Classifications',
    Question:
      'Detritivores obtain most of their nutrients from what material consisting of accumulated organic debris from dead organisms?',
    Answer: 'detritus',
    Metadata: 'biology detritivore ecology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '128281',
    Subject: 'Central American Disease',
    Question:
      'By the time the Panama Canal opened in 1914, the death rate among workers had dropped to 6 per 1000 compared to 14 per 1000 when construction began in 1904. This was mainly because William Gorgas had won the battle against malaria and what other disease?',
    Answer: 'yellow fever',
    Metadata:
      'Central America disease Gorgas, William health health history history Latin America Panama Canal science social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '136932',
    Subject: ',\tSeesaws',
    Question:
      'A 12-foot seesaw pivots at its center. Carl weighs 40 pounds and is sitting at one end. Carla weighs 30 pounds and is 1 foot from Carl. How many feet from the fulcrum must Kelly sit to balance the seesaw, given that he weighs 155 pounds?',
    Answer: '2.5 feet',
    Metadata: 'algebra equation fulcrum lever math physical science science word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '15224',
    Subject: 'Prepositional Phrases',
    Question:
      'What is the object of the last preposition in this quote by Alfred Hitchcock? The length of a film should be directly related to the endurance of the human bladder.',
    Answer: 'bladder',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts phrase prepositional phrase',
  },
  {
    ID: '114682',
    Subject: '%Respiratory Anatomy',
    Question:
      'Humans have between 16 and 20 C-shaped rings of cartilage in what tube between the lungs and larynx?',
    Answer: 'trachea',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology cartilage respiratory system science',
  },
  {
    ID: '14823',
    Subject: 'Myths',
    Question: 'What was the Greek name for the Roman god Bacchus?',
    Answer: 'Dionysus',
    Metadata: 'Greek myth language arts literature myth Roman myth',
  },
  {
    ID: '128330',
    Subject: '*Number Combos',
    Question:
      'How many even numbers with two different digits can be formed by selecting from these numbers? 3 4 5 6 7 8 9',
    Answer: '18',
    Metadata: 'combination even number math',
  },
  {
    ID: '51975',
    Subject: 'Unexpected Journeys',
    Question:
      'When Pedro Cabral happened upon the coast of Brazil in 1500, his ship was supposed to be on its way to what land?',
    Answer: 'India',
    Metadata:
      '16th century age of exploration Brazil Cabral, Pedro history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '15456',
    Subject: 'Punctuation',
    Question:
      'Parenthetical matter in a sentence may be set off with parentheses, commas, or what other punctuation marks?',
    Answer: 'dashes',
    Metadata: 'comma grammar language arts parentheses parenthetical expression punctuation',
  },
  {
    ID: '144476',
    Subject: '0Dramatic Techniques',
    Question:
      'A dramatic reading by a group in which multiple members speak similar parts at the same time is known as what kind of speaking?',
    Answer: 'choral speaking',
    Metadata: 'drama fine arts humanities',
  },
  {
    ID: '59121',
    Subject: 'Aviators',
    Question: 'Roy Brown shot down what German ace?',
    Answer: 'Red Baron',
    Metadata:
      '1910s 1918 20th century ace aviation Europe Germany history people pilot social studies war world history World War I',
  },
  {
    ID: '76626',
    Subject: 'Colonial Cartoons',
    Question:
      'The snake in Ben Franklin\'s famous "Join or Die" political cartoon is divided into just eight sections. "N.E." in that cartoon represented the four New England colonies and Delaware was then part of Pennsylvania. Which of the thirteen colonies was completely omitted?',
    Answer: 'Georgia',
    Metadata:
      '18th century American history American Revolution colonial period Franklin, Benjamin history political cartoon social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '98069',
    Subject: 'Compound Proportions',
    Question:
      'The definite proportion of water is one gram of hydrogen for how many grams of oxygen?',
    Answer: '8',
    Metadata: 'chemical compound chemistry physical science science water',
  },
  {
    ID: '35983',
    Subject: 'Peninsulas',
    Question: 'Mt. Sinai is located on what Mideast peninsula?',
    Answer: 'Sinai Peninsula',
    Metadata: 'geography Mideast mountain Mt. Sinai social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '87559',
    Subject: '\u001dWinds',
    Question: 'South of the equator, the trade winds blow from what intercardinal direction?',
    Answer: 'southeast',
    Metadata: 'earth science meteorology science trade wind wind',
  },
  {
    ID: '35805',
    Subject: 'The Mideast',
    Question: 'What Mideast country is on an island in the Mediterranean?',
    Answer: 'Cyprus',
    Metadata: 'geography Mediterranean Mideast social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '62841',
    Subject: 'Poetic Heroines',
    Question:
      "During what war was the heroine active who uttered this line? Shoot if you will this old gray head but spare your country's flag.",
    Answer: 'Civil War',
    Metadata:
      '1860s 19th century American history American literature flag heroine history language arts literature poetry quote social studies war woman',
  },
  {
    ID: '139069',
    Subject: '-Space Problems',
    Question:
      'The Xygring II spacecraft is 2.5 times faster than the old Xygring I. How long would it take the Xygring I to travel 6 parsecs if the Xygring II can cover the distance in 14 hours?',
    Answer: '35 hours',
    Metadata: 'math proportion word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '57953',
    Subject: 'Evidence',
    Question:
      'After months of speculation, debris from the missing Malaysian Airlines Flight 370 turned up in 2015 on Reunion Island in what ocean?',
    Answer: 'Indian Ocean',
    Metadata: '2015 21st century history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '126546',
    Subject: '*Other Base Division',
    Question: 'Divide 101 base 2 by 10 base 2.',
    Answer: '10 remainder 1',
    Metadata: 'bases (numbers) division math',
  },
  {
    ID: '20531',
    Subject: 'Fallacies',
    Question:
      'One argument goes that only man is logical, no woman is a man, and so no woman is logical. But because the meaning of "man" in the first premise is "mankind" or "Homo sapiens," the term is ambiguous and the argument is fallacious because of the fallacy of what?',
    Answer: 'equivocation (amphiboly)',
    Metadata: 'fallacy language arts reasoning',
  },
  {
    ID: '130245',
    Subject: '* Poetic Math',
    Question:
      'How old is the scientist in this limerick? There was a scientist from London Who with binary digits had fun When asked his age Replied this great sage, "I\'m 100001."',
    Answer: '33',
    Metadata: 'binary math limerick math number',
  },
  {
    ID: '33061',
    Subject: 'Highways',
    Question: 'The failed Trans-Amazonian Highway was in what country?',
    Answer: 'Brazil',
    Metadata: 'geography highway Latin America social studies South America',
  },
  {
    ID: '2263',
    Subject: 'Pirate Stories',
    Question:
      'In Robert Louis Stevenson\'s "Treasure Island," who first sings these lyrics? Fifteen men on the dead man\'s chest! Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum.',
    Answer: 'Billy Bones',
    Metadata:
      'English literature language arts literary character literature Stevenson, Robert Louis Treasure Island',
  },
  {
    ID: '116801',
    Subject: '&Cells',
    Question:
      'Near the center of what structure in a living cell lies a mass of fibers called chromatin?',
    Answer: 'nucleus',
    Metadata: 'biology cell chromatin cytology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '11931',
    Subject: 'References',
    Question:
      'Name the words that appear at the top of each page in a reference work to indicate the first or last entry on the page.',
    Answer: 'guidewords (headwords)',
    Metadata: 'dictionary encyclopedia language arts literature reference',
  },
  {
    ID: '50731',
    Subject: 'Scandals',
    Question:
      'Name the affair that began in 1986 when a Lebanese magazine revealed that the U.S. had been secretly selling arms to Iran in anticipation of securing the release of hostages held in Lebanon.',
    Answer: 'Iran-Contra',
    Metadata:
      '1980s 1986 20th century American history history Lebanon scandal social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '38596',
    Subject: 'Alliances',
    Question:
      'What is the name for a temporary alliance of factions such as the multi-national force that invaded Iraq in 2003?',
    Answer: 'coalition',
    Metadata: 'alliance government military social studies vocabulary world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '15480',
    Subject: 'Nouns',
    Question:
      'Count the nouns in this Polish proverb. Under capitalism man exploits man while under socialism the reverse is true.',
    Answer: '5',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts noun part of speech',
  },
  {
    ID: '146300',
    Subject: '1Written Music',
    Question: 'In written music, the great staff consists of 10 spaces and how many lines?',
    Answer: '11',
    Metadata: 'fine arts humanities music',
  },
  {
    ID: '145222',
    Subject: '0Art Vocabulary',
    Question:
      'What art term means that a work is one of a kind, authentic, made by the artist, and not a copy?',
    Answer: 'original',
    Metadata: 'art fine arts humanities vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '43709',
    Subject: '\u0012 County Government',
    Question:
      'What is the most common title of the chief law enforcement officer of a U.S. county?',
    Answer: 'sheriff',
    Metadata:
      'American government county government government law law enforcement local government social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '44950',
    Subject: '\u0012\tInterest',
    Question:
      'There are legal limitations to the amount of interest that may be charged. Charging a rate in excess of the legal limit is called what?',
    Answer: 'usury',
    Metadata: 'business debt economics interest law offense social studies vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '92949',
    Subject: '\u001fWaves',
    Question:
      'What is the term for the superposition of two or more waves resulting in a new wave pattern?',
    Answer: 'interference',
    Metadata: 'physical science physics science wave',
  },
  {
    ID: '30543',
    Subject: 'Provinces',
    Question: 'What Canadian province lies adjacent to and northeast of Maine?',
    Answer: 'New Brunswick',
    Metadata: 'Canada geography Maine province social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '58124',
    Subject: 'European History',
    Question: 'The Bourbons were a royal family of what country?',
    Answer: 'France',
    Metadata: 'Bourbon Europe history people social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '20685',
    Subject: 'Logic',
    Question:
      'What is the third line in this syllogism? Skin gets moist with perspiration. Moisture escapes from things through holes.',
    Answer: 'Skin has holes.',
    Metadata: 'deduction language arts logic reasoning syllogism',
  },
  {
    ID: '33415',
    Subject: 'Islands',
    Question: 'What islands 300 miles east of the Strait of Magellan are a British dependency?',
    Answer: 'Falklands',
    Metadata: 'dependency geography island social studies Strait of Magellan',
  },
  {
    ID: '50747',
    Subject: 'Empires',
    Question:
      'With its capital at Constantinople, what name was given to the eastern half of the Roman Empire after the year 330?',
    Answer: 'Byzantine Empire',
    Metadata: 'ancient Rome Constantinople empire history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '22418',
    Subject: 'Root Words',
    Question: 'What does the root mean in these words? equivocal, vocation, revocable, provocation',
    Answer: 'call',
    Metadata: 'etymology language arts root word',
  },
  {
    ID: '81260',
    Subject: 'Erosion',
    Question:
      'The process by which softer, less resistant rocks wear away leaving harder, more resistant rocks in place is called what kind of weathering?',
    Answer: 'differential weathering',
    Metadata: 'earth science erosion geology science weathering',
  },
  {
    ID: '18993',
    Subject: 'Grammatical Voice',
    Question: 'Restate this line in the passive voice. Why did the chicken cross the road?',
    Answer: 'Why was the road crossed by the chicken?',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts passive voice verb voice (grammar)',
  },
  {
    ID: '67319',
    Subject: 'Candidates',
    Question:
      "Who was Douglas' opponent in this account? His Republican opponent seemed unimpressive. A former one-term representative, at six feet four inches in height, he may have towered over Douglas, but he lacked the senator's stature and clout.",
    Answer: 'Abraham Lincoln',
    Metadata:
      '19th century American history Douglas, Stephen history quote Republican Party social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '10732',
    Subject: 'Allusions',
    Question:
      'An allusion meaning a temporary, makeshift, limited, stop-gap remedy is the same as the trademark for what adhesive bandage?',
    Answer: 'Band-Aid',
    Metadata: 'allusion language arts literature slang',
  },
  {
    ID: '135060',
    Subject: '+Hexagons',
    Question:
      'If the perimeter of a regular hexagon is 54 meters, what is the length of one of its sides?',
    Answer: '9 meters',
    Metadata: 'geometry hexagon math plane geometry polygon',
  },
  {
    ID: '15768',
    Subject: 'Phrases',
    Question:
      "What is the object of the last prepositional phrase in this sentence? Neil Bush indignantly denied allegations that his being George Bush's son had anything to do with the fact that he was named admiral of the U.S. 7th Fleet.",
    Answer: 'fleet',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts phrase prepositional phrase sentence analysis',
  },
  {
    ID: '2556',
    Subject: 'Literary Similarities',
    Question:
      'The story line of William Cowper\'s poem, "The Castaway," is similar to that of what novel by Daniel Defoe?',
    Answer: 'Robinson Crusoe',
    Metadata: 'Cowper, William Defoe, Daniel English literature language arts literature novel',
  },
  {
    ID: '150496',
    Subject: '5!\tActresses',
    Question:
      'What actress who represents the high-spirited, independent, outspoken, classy career woman often teamed with Spencer Tracy in motion pictures?',
    Answer: 'Katherine Hepburn',
    Metadata: 'actress art cinema fine arts people theater trivia woman',
  },
  {
    ID: '80619',
    Subject: '\u001bTrenches',
    Question: 'Name the major oceanic trench to the northeast of the Kuril Trench.',
    Answer: 'Aleutian Trench',
    Metadata: 'earth science Kuril Trench ocean floor oceanography Pacific Ocean science trench',
  },
  {
    ID: '28316',
    Subject: 'Islands',
    Question: "Martha's Vineyard is an island belonging to what state?",
    Answer: 'Massachusetts',
    Metadata:
      "American geography geography island Martha's Vineyard social studies state geography",
  },
  {
    ID: '129006',
    Subject: '*Mathematical Logic',
    Question: 'What is the converse of this statement? If x is odd then x squared is odd.',
    Answer: 'If x squared is odd then x is odd.',
    Metadata: 'converse logic math statement',
  },
  {
    ID: '134756',
    Subject: '+\u0002Loci',
    Question:
      'Two points, A and B, are seven units apart. How many points are there that are equidistant from both A and B and also eight units from A?',
    Answer: '2',
    Metadata: 'geometry locus of points math plane geometry',
  },
  {
    ID: '62184',
    Subject: 'Common Names',
    Question: 'In what European country is De Vries one of the most common surnames?',
    Answer: 'Netherlands',
    Metadata: 'Europe history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '142877',
    Subject: '0Art',
    Question:
      'George Washington had to sit still for several hours while an artist painted his picture. What is the name for such a painting?',
    Answer: 'portrait',
    Metadata: 'art fine arts humanities painting',
  },
  {
    ID: '118196',
    Subject: '& Scientific Voyages',
    Question:
      "The purpose of the voyage of the H.M.S. Beagle in the 1830s was to continue the surveying and mapping of South America. Who was the ship's naturalist?",
    Answer: 'Charles Darwin',
    Metadata: '1830s 19th century biology H.M.S. Beagle naturalist science',
  },
  {
    ID: '15502',
    Subject: 'Tense',
    Question: 'Express "he flies" in the past perfect tense.',
    Answer: 'he has flown',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts tense verb',
  },
  {
    ID: '86089',
    Subject: '\u001dLatitudes',
    Question: 'What is the name for the parallel that marks the edge of the northern polar zone?',
    Answer: 'Arctic Circle',
    Metadata: 'earth science latitude meteorology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '138914',
    Subject: '-Consecutive Integers',
    Question:
      'When two times the smaller of two consecutive integers is added to six times the larger, the result is 150. Find the smaller integer.',
    Answer: '18',
    Metadata: 'consecutive integers math word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '52508',
    Subject: 'Catholicism',
    Question:
      'Named after Saint Benedict of Nursia in the 6th century, a guide for living in monasteries and convents is called the ---- Rule.',
    Answer: 'Benedictine',
    Metadata: 'Catholicism history humanities monastery saint social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '80807',
    Subject: '\u001bOcean Basins',
    Question: 'In what ocean is the Canary Basin?',
    Answer: 'Atlantic',
    Metadata: 'basin earth science oceanography science',
  },
  {
    ID: '126800',
    Subject: '* Paper',
    Question: 'An office has 3500 sheets of typing paper left. This equals how many reams?',
    Answer: '7',
    Metadata: 'math measurement paper',
  },
  {
    ID: '135751',
    Subject: ',Number Problems',
    Question: 'The total of two numbers is 65 and their difference is 13. What are the numbers?',
    Answer: '26, 39',
    Metadata: 'algebra math number problem word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '35000',
    Subject: 'Gorgeous Gorges',
    Question:
      "While the world's largest gorge is the America's Grand Canyon, the second largest, the Vikos Gorge, is in what country on the Balkan Peninsula?",
    Answer: 'Greece',
    Metadata: 'Balkan Peninsula canyon Europe geography gorge social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '50901',
    Subject: 'Critical Technology',
    Question:
      'The most significant invention that gave birth to the Industrial Revolution was what kind of engine?',
    Answer: 'steam engine',
    Metadata: '18th century history Industrial Revolution social studies technology world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '119545',
    Subject: '!Ferns',
    Question: 'In what phylum do ferns belong?',
    Answer: 'Tracheophytes',
    Metadata: 'biology botany fern phylum science taxonomy',
  },
  {
    ID: '31615',
    Subject: 'Gulfs',
    Question: 'What gulf is shared by China and Vietnam?',
    Answer: 'Gulf of Tonkin',
    Metadata: 'Asia China geography gulf social studies Southeast Asia Vietnam',
  },
  {
    ID: '124379',
    Subject: '*Wide-Ranging Bases',
    Question:
      'What decimal numeral results when you add the binary numeral 111 to the base four numeral 10?',
    Answer: '11',
    Metadata: 'bases (numbers) binary math math',
  },
  {
    ID: '65199',
    Subject: 'Presidents',
    Question:
      'Who was elected U.S. president one day before South Carolina seceded from the Union?',
    Answer: 'Abraham Lincoln',
    Metadata: '19th century American history history president social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '144652',
    Subject: '0Artists',
    Question:
      'What artistic occupation is missing from this biblical quotation? Hath not the ---- power over the clay, of the same lump to make one vessel unto honour, and another unto dishonor?',
    Answer: 'potter',
    Metadata: 'art art form fine arts quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '85646',
    Subject: 'Habitats',
    Question: 'Identify the habitat of troglobites, troglophiles, and troglodytes.',
    Answer: 'caves',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '97155',
    Subject: 'Atomic Structure',
    Question: 'The innermost shell of an atom can hold a maximum of how many electrons?',
    Answer: '2',
    Metadata: 'atom chemistry electron physical science science valence',
  },
  {
    ID: '87558',
    Subject: '\u001dThe Atmosphere',
    Question:
      'In what layer of the atmosphere do temperatures rise to more than 1000 degrees Celsius, but because the gases are so sparse, they contain only an insignificant quantity of heat?',
    Answer: 'thermosphere',
    Metadata: 'atmosphere atmospheric layer earth science meteorology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '14156',
    Subject: 'Elizabethan Plays',
    Question:
      'This is in the opening of what Shakespearean play? My fair Bianca, bid my father welcome, While I with self-same kindness welcome thine. Brother Petruchio, sister Katharina, And thou, Hortensio, with thy loving widow, Feast with the best, and welcome to my house.',
    Answer: 'The Taming of the Shrew',
    Metadata:
      'drama (Shakespeare) English literature language arts literary character literature quote Shakespeare',
  },
  {
    ID: '56091',
    Subject: 'Revolutions',
    Question: 'The Russian Revolution occurred in what century?',
    Answer: '20th century',
    Metadata: 'history revolution Russian Revolution social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '9338',
    Subject: '\u0002 Dialogue',
    Question:
      "Who says this in a Mark Twain story? We's safe, Huck, we's safe! Jump up and crack yo' heels. Dat's de good ole Cairo at las', I jis knows it.",
    Answer: 'Jim',
    Metadata: 'American literature language arts literary character literature quote Twain, Mark',
  },
  {
    ID: '85179',
    Subject: 'Ores',
    Question:
      'Smithsonite and sphalerite are common ores of what lustrous metal used to make brass?',
    Answer: 'zinc',
    Metadata: 'alloy earth science geology metal metallurgy ore science',
  },
  {
    ID: '129882',
    Subject: '*\fRatios',
    Question: 'In simplest form, express the ratio, 155 to 186.',
    Answer: '5 to 6',
    Metadata: 'math ratio',
  },
  {
    ID: '48095',
    Subject: 'Explorer Latin',
    Question:
      'Amerigo Vespucci\'s letters frequently refer to the "Mundus Novus," which means what?',
    Answer: 'New World',
    Metadata:
      '16th century age of exploration explorer history Latin language social studies Vespucci, Amerigo world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '126452',
    Subject: '*Proportions',
    Question:
      'There are nine albatross eggs in two pounds. Three dozen albatross eggs weigh how much?',
    Answer: '8 pounds',
    Metadata: 'dozen math proportion',
  },
  {
    ID: '88898',
    Subject: '\u001f Nationalities',
    Question:
      'What was the nationality of the physicist who deduced this rule? Equal volumes of all gases at standard temperature and pressure contain the same number of molecules.',
    Answer: 'Italian',
    Metadata:
      'gas gas law nationality physical science physical science history physicist physics science science history scientific law',
  },
  {
    ID: '35399',
    Subject: 'Geographic Palindromes',
    Question: 'Complete this palindrome with the name of an atoll of Kiribati. A war at ...',
    Answer: 'Tarawa',
    Metadata: 'geography language arts palindrome social studies wordplay',
  },
  {
    ID: '150625',
    Subject: '5!Lyrics',
    Question:
      "Complete this passage from a John Lennon song. Will you still need me, Will you still feed me When I'm ...",
    Answer: 'sixty-four',
    Metadata: 'fine arts lyrics music song trivia',
  },
  {
    ID: '75013',
    Subject: 'Radio Roosevelt',
    Question:
      'What was the general name for these radio speeches delivered by Franklin Roosevelt? On the Coal Crisis On National Defense On Drought Conditions On the Works Relief Program On the Declaration of War with Japan',
    Answer: 'fireside chats',
    Metadata: '20th century American history history Roosevelt, Franklin social studies speech',
  },
  {
    ID: '57127',
    Subject: '\u0002Phoenicia',
    Question:
      'Like ancient Greece, the Phoenician civilization was organized in what kind of states?',
    Answer: 'city-states',
    Metadata: 'ancient history B.C. history Mideast Phoenicia social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '77999',
    Subject: '\u001a The Sun',
    Question:
      'The sudden release of an enormous amount of energy from the solar surface is called a solar what?',
    Answer: 'flare',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science energy science Sun',
  },
  {
    ID: '83760',
    Subject: 'Glaciers',
    Question:
      'If the total ablation exceeds the total accumulation for a particular glacier, then the glacier is said to be doing what?',
    Answer: 'retreating',
    Metadata: 'ablation earth science geology glacier science',
  },
  {
    ID: '99679',
    Subject: 'Food Preparation',
    Question:
      'These are categories of what in nutrition? antioxidants emulsifiers stabilizers preservatives sweeteners',
    Answer: 'food additives',
    Metadata: 'antioxidant cooking health home economics nutrition preservative science',
  },
  {
    ID: '96627',
    Subject: 'Chemical Particles',
    Question:
      'Small particles formed by shaving a metal, similar in size to grains or granules, but long and thin, are called what?',
    Answer: 'filings',
    Metadata: 'chemistry physical science science vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '140344',
    Subject: '-Interest Problems',
    Question:
      'If you borrow $5000 for one year at 7 1/2% simple interest, how much is the interest at the end of the year?',
    Answer: '$375',
    Metadata: 'interest math percent word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '60166',
    Subject: 'Celebrations',
    Question:
      'What day, celebrated annually since 1789, commemorates the fall of royal despotism in France?',
    Answer: 'Bastille Day',
    Metadata:
      '1780s 1789 18th century Europe France history holiday social studies tradition world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '95223',
    Subject: 'Numbers in Chemistry',
    Question:
      'What is the name for a number representing the combining power of an atom or radical in terms of hydrogen as a standard?',
    Answer: 'valence',
    Metadata: 'atomic structure chemistry physical science radical (science) science',
  },
  {
    ID: '9084',
    Subject: '\u0002Science Fiction',
    Question:
      'What story includes three mysterious characters called Mrs. Whatsit, Mrs. Who, and Mrs. Which?',
    Answer: 'A Wrinkle in Time',
    Metadata: 'American literature language arts literary character literature science fiction',
  },
  {
    ID: '83035',
    Subject: 'Mining',
    Question: 'What did miners extract from the Big Hole at Kimberley, South Africa?',
    Answer: 'diamonds',
    Metadata: 'Africa earth science geology Kimberley mining science South Africa',
  },
  {
    ID: '150383',
    Subject: '5\u0002Cartoon Equipment',
    Question: 'The Wayback Machine was a time traveling device used by what incredible canine?',
    Answer: 'Mr. Peabody',
    Metadata: 'dog trivia',
  },
  {
    ID: '34855',
    Subject: 'Seas',
    Question: 'The Sea of Okhotsk is mostly bordered by what country?',
    Answer: 'Russia',
    Metadata: 'Asia border geography sea Sea of Okhotsk social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '59355',
    Subject: 'Organizations',
    Question: 'What organization was established by the same document that ended World War I?',
    Answer: 'League of Nations',
    Metadata:
      '1910s 20th century document Europe history social studies treaty war world history World War I',
  },
  {
    ID: '122996',
    Subject: '(Bovines',
    Question: 'What creatures are the bison of Tibet?',
    Answer: 'yaks',
    Metadata: 'Asia biology bovine mammal science Tibet zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '126666',
    Subject: '*\u0002Negative Fractions',
    Question: 'Multiply -2/5 by -6/11.',
    Answer: '12/55',
    Metadata: 'fraction math',
  },
  {
    ID: '45414',
    Subject: '\u0012 Objectionable Behavior',
    Question:
      "Reminiscent of a burrowing mammal, what is the term for a lawyer's hostile cross-examination of a witness?",
    Answer: 'badgering',
    Metadata: 'court law social studies trial vocabulary witness',
  },
  {
    ID: '4501',
    Subject: '\u0002Geographic Poetry',
    Question: 'What is today\'s name for Gitchee Gumee in the poem, "Hiawatha"?',
    Answer: 'Lake Superior',
    Metadata: 'American literature Hiawatha language arts literature poetry',
  },
  {
    ID: '29671',
    Subject: 'Sea Travel',
    Question: 'A ship leaving Croatia heading for the Italy must pass over what sea?',
    Answer: 'Adriatic Sea',
    Metadata: 'Croatia geography sea social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '148672',
    Subject: '3Injuries',
    Question:
      'What kind of injury occurs when the elbow is forced to bend beyond its normal range of motion?',
    Answer: 'hyperextension (elbow hyperextension)',
    Metadata: 'elbow health injury science sports medicine',
  },
  {
    ID: '15003',
    Subject: 'Myths',
    Question:
      'The myths of what region include a one-eyed, bearded god, a goddess who rides into battle to choose among the slain, a horn-blowing god who was born of nine mothers, and a vast cosmological tree called Yggdrasil?',
    Answer: 'Scandinavia',
    Metadata: 'language arts literature myth',
  },
  {
    ID: '73616',
    Subject: 'Nicknames',
    Question: 'What president was known as "Old Rough and Ready" and as "Old Zach"?',
    Answer: 'Zachary Taylor',
    Metadata: '19th century American history history nickname president social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '25093',
    Subject: 'Shared Names',
    Question:
      'What term may indicate either an enclosed area for cockfights or the space in an airplane fuselage containing the seats for the pilots?',
    Answer: 'cockpit',
    Metadata: 'aviation homonym language arts vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '57200',
    Subject: 'Memorable Massacres',
    Question:
      'The late 17th-century Massacre of Glencoe, in which Campbell Clan soldiers slaughtered many members of the MacDonald Clan, occurred in what part of Great Britain?',
    Answer: 'Scotland',
    Metadata:
      '17th century Glencoe Massacre Great Britain history massacre social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '35775',
    Subject: 'Seas',
    Question:
      'What sea forms the northern border of the desert that is partially located in Eritrea, Mali, Niger, Sudan, and Mauritania?',
    Answer: 'Mediterranean Sea',
    Metadata: 'Africa desert geography sea social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '138816',
    Subject: ',Radians',
    Question: 'How many degrees is pi/5 radian?',
    Answer: '36',
    Metadata: 'math radian trigonometry',
  },
  {
    ID: '93798',
    Subject: '\u001fMechanics',
    Question: 'What is a synonymous phrase for the leverage provided by a lever?',
    Answer: 'mechanical advantage',
    Metadata: 'lever mechanics physical science science vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '69390',
    Subject: 'Gold',
    Question:
      'The name, Mother Lode, indicates a gold mining region in the northern and central part of what state?',
    Answer: 'California',
    Metadata: '19th century American history gold history mining Mother Lode social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '72841',
    Subject: 'Mangled Quotations',
    Question:
      'This quotation from the movie, "Small Soldiers," is actually a partial combination of quotations from what two people? Damn the torpedoes or give me death.',
    Answer: 'David Farragut, Patrick Henry',
    Metadata: 'American history history quote social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '37382',
    Subject: 'Monarchy Quotes',
    Question:
      'What is the last word in this quote about monarchies by Daniel Defoe? Titles are shadows, crowns are empty things. The good of subjects is the end of ...',
    Answer: 'kings',
    Metadata: 'Defoe, Daniel government monarchy quote social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '140254',
    Subject: '-\f\tWages',
    Question:
      'In 1910, U.S. workingmen earned, on average, $15 per week for a 60 hour work week. This is equivalent to how much per hour?',
    Answer: '25 cents',
    Metadata: '1910 1910s 20th century American history history math social studies word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '82608',
    Subject: 'Copper Ores',
    Question: 'Azurite is a blue copper carbonate. What color is the copper carbonate, malachite?',
    Answer: 'green',
    Metadata: 'carbonate copper earth science geology malachite mineral ore science',
  },
  {
    ID: '12350',
    Subject: 'Cinematic Errors',
    Question:
      'A scene from the movie "Goodfellas" set at Idlewild Airport in 1963 shows a Boeing 747 in the air, but the 747 did not make its first flight until 1969. This illustrates what kind of error?',
    Answer: 'anachronism',
    Metadata: 'cinema history language arts literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '31153',
    Subject: 'Country Borders',
    Question: 'Italy and Greece border what sea?',
    Answer: 'Adriatic Sea',
    Metadata: 'border Europe geography Greece sea social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '20111',
    Subject: 'Sentence Types',
    Question:
      "Classify this line by Donna VanLiere according to its structure. Half the battle in life is knowing what not to forget and forgetting what doesn't need to be remembered.",
    Answer: 'simple sentence',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts sentence type',
  },
  {
    ID: '125223',
    Subject: '* Numbers',
    Question: 'The natural numbers excluding 1 are either prime or what?',
    Answer: 'composite',
    Metadata: 'math natural number number',
  },
  {
    ID: '75671',
    Subject: '\u0002Dust Bowl Hinky-Pinkies',
    Question:
      'What plural word indicating a decade in the 20th century completes this hinky pinky name for the Dust Bowl? Dirty ...',
    Answer: 'Thirties',
    Metadata: '20th century American history Dust Bowl hinky pinky history social studies wordplay',
  },
  {
    ID: '68708',
    Subject: 'Prominent Colonists',
    Question:
      'Richard Mather of the Massachusetts Bay Colony begat Increase Mather who in turn begat a remarkably prolific son. Name him.',
    Answer: 'Cotton Mather',
    Metadata:
      '18th century American history colonial period history Massachusetts Massachusetts Bay Colony Mather, Increase social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '94283',
    Subject: '\u001f Lamps',
    Question:
      'More than 70 years before Thomas Edison produced his successful incandescent lamp, what British chemist developed a carbon arc lamp?',
    Answer: 'Humphry Davy',
    Metadata:
      '19th century incandescent lamp physical science physical science history science technology',
  },
  {
    ID: '56495',
    Subject: 'Secretive Organizations',
    Question:
      'The triads are worldwide criminal organizations that originated as secret societies in what country?',
    Answer: 'China',
    Metadata: '21st century crime history organized crime smuggling social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '15223',
    Subject: 'Nouns',
    Question: 'These are what kind of nouns? jury flock family committee herd army',
    Answer: 'collective',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts noun',
  },
  {
    ID: '27433',
    Subject: 'Cities',
    Question: 'These cities are in what state? Garden City Hays Shawnee Leavenworth',
    Answer: 'Kansas',
    Metadata: 'American geography city geography social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '30194',
    Subject: 'Asian Nations',
    Question:
      'What nation of southeast Asia between Burma and Cambodia has a southern coastline on the Gulf of Siam and the Indian Ocean?',
    Answer: 'Thailand',
    Metadata:
      'Asia Burma Cambodia geography Gulf of Siam Indian Ocean social studies Southeast Asia',
  },
  {
    ID: '113451',
    Subject: '%! Cellular Biology',
    Question:
      'What molecule is formed when the outside phosphate bond of the ATP molecule is broken?',
    Answer: 'ADP',
    Metadata:
      'ATP biology bond cell chemical bond chemistry phosphate physical science physiology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '138683',
    Subject: ',Radians',
    Question: 'In terms of pi, what is the radian measure of 45 degrees?',
    Answer: 'pi/4',
    Metadata: 'math radian trigonometry',
  },
  {
    ID: '135538',
    Subject: ',Averages',
    Question: 'What is x if the average of 3 and 9 and x is 9?',
    Answer: '15',
    Metadata: 'algebra average math mean word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '63087',
    Subject: 'Energy Consumption',
    Question:
      'In 1850, 91 percent of U.S. energy came from wood, while the rest was mostly from coal or what oil derived from marine mammals?',
    Answer: 'whales',
    Metadata: '1850 1850s 19th century American history history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '4588',
    Subject: '\u0002Mark Twain',
    Question:
      'Who in "The Adventures of Tom Sawyer" is described as "a lovely little blue-eyed creature with yellow hair plaited into two long tails, white summer frock and embroidered pantalettes"?',
    Answer: 'Becky Thatcher',
    Metadata:
      'Adventures of Tom Sawyer, The American literature language arts literary character literature quote Twain, Mark',
  },
  {
    ID: '122901',
    Subject: '( Defensive Adaptations',
    Question:
      'The ash borer moth has developed to resemble the common wasp, but it cannot sting. Since predators cannot distinguish between the two, they avoid the moth. This is an example of Batesian what?',
    Answer: 'mimicry',
    Metadata: 'adaptation arthropod biology insect science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '149590',
    Subject: '3Getting an Edge',
    Question:
      'Blood doping, an illegal practice in professional sports, involves boosting the number of what kind of cells in the bloodstream?',
    Answer: 'erythrocytes (red blood cells)',
    Metadata: 'biology circulatory system health science sports',
  },
  {
    ID: '142450',
    Subject: '.! Greek Wisdom',
    Question:
      "What ancient Greek husband of Xanthippe said this? By all means marry. If you get a good wife, you'll be happy. If you get a bad one, you'll become a philosopher, and that is a good thing for any man.",
    Answer: 'Socrates',
    Metadata:
      'ancient Greece ancient history ancient literature B.C. language arts literature marriage philosopher philosophy quote woman Xanthippe',
  },
  {
    ID: '35896',
    Subject: 'Jamaica',
    Question:
      'What is the modern name of a town in Jamaica whose name was taken from the Spanish words, "manteca bahia" meaning "bay of lard"?',
    Answer: 'Montego Bay',
    Metadata: 'Caribbean geography Jamaica social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '16433',
    Subject: 'Grammatical Nonsense',
    Question:
      "What is the subject of the adverbial phrase in this fractured sentence? Another story was about William Tell who shot an arrow through an apple while standing on his son's head.",
    Answer: 'William Tell',
    Metadata: 'adverb phrase grammar language arts phrase sentence analysis subject',
  },
  {
    ID: '70279',
    Subject: 'Political Get-Togethers',
    Question:
      'Those who met at the Hartford Conventions from 1814 to 1815 were linked to what political party?',
    Answer: 'Federalist',
    Metadata:
      '1810s 1814 19th century American history Connecticut Hartford Convention history political party social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '67406',
    Subject: 'Conflicts',
    Question: 'The U.S. went to war with what country when it attempted to liberate Cuba in 1898?',
    Answer: 'Spain',
    Metadata: '1890s 1898 19th century American history Caribbean Cuba history social studies war',
  },
  {
    ID: '124844',
    Subject: '*Other Bases',
    Question: 'Convert the binary numeral 110001 to base 10.',
    Answer: '49',
    Metadata: 'bases (numbers) binary math math',
  },
  {
    ID: '1780',
    Subject: 'D.H. Lawrence',
    Question:
      'D.H. Lawrence, self-tormented, persecuted, and tubercular, wandered restlessly throughout his adult life. Of the more than forty books he wrote, perhaps the best known is his autobiographical novel with what title?',
    Answer: 'Sons and Lovers',
    Metadata:
      'author autobiography English literature language arts Lawrence, D.H. literature novel',
  },
  {
    ID: '35695',
    Subject: 'Cities',
    Question: 'Name the transcontinental city straddling the Bosporus.',
    Answer: 'Istanbul',
    Metadata: 'Bosporus city continent geography social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '92924',
    Subject: '\u001fAtmospheric Phenomena',
    Question:
      'What is this about? It is a bright blue-white glow, sometimes appearing like jets of fire, emanating from sharply pointed structures such as masts, spires and chimneys.',
    Answer: "St. Elmo's fire",
    Metadata:
      'atmosphere atmospheric phenomenon meteorology physical science physics science static electricity',
  },
  {
    ID: '87656',
    Subject: '\u001dFloods',
    Question: 'What is the probability of a 100-year flood occuring in any given year?',
    Answer: '1% (1 in 100)',
    Metadata: 'earth science flood meteorology probability science',
  },
  {
    ID: '69793',
    Subject: 'Kansas Wars',
    Question:
      'As part of the Wakarusa War in the 1850s, Kansas Sheriff Samuel Jones led pro-slavery forces in an attack on what Kansas city whose citizens opposed slavery?',
    Answer: 'Lawrence',
    Metadata: '19th century American history history Kansas social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '149658',
    Subject: '4Doors and Windows',
    Question:
      'Name the thin tapered pieces of wood used in hanging doors and windows to adjust them to a vertical position.',
    Answer: 'shims (wedges)',
    Metadata: 'construction door vocational window',
  },
  {
    ID: '29757',
    Subject: 'Mountain Ranges',
    Question:
      'Name the major mountain range which runs north to south through the length of South America.',
    Answer: 'Andes',
    Metadata: 'geography Latin America mountain range social studies South America',
  },
  {
    ID: '57147',
    Subject: 'International Relations',
    Question:
      'In 1853, what Western nation became the first to establish trade relations with Japan since it had been declared closed to foreigners 200 years earlier?',
    Answer: 'United States',
    Metadata:
      '1850s 19th century history international relations Japan social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '131449',
    Subject: '*Divisibility',
    Question:
      'What is the smallest number that is evenly divisible by every number from one to six?',
    Answer: '60',
    Metadata: 'divisibility math number',
  },
  {
    ID: '86872',
    Subject: '\u001dCondensation',
    Question: 'Name the primary cause of condensation in the atmosphere.',
    Answer: 'cooling',
    Metadata: 'condensation earth science meteorology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '52350',
    Subject: 'French',
    Question:
      'The term "chivalry" comes from the French word "cheval" which indicates what kind of animal?',
    Answer: 'horse',
    Metadata:
      'chivalry etymology French language history medieval Middle Ages social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '123336',
    Subject: '(Wildlife Reductions',
    Question:
      'What disease periodically decimates the populations of prairie dogs in many western states?',
    Answer: 'plague',
    Metadata: 'biology prairie dog science wildlife zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '53580',
    Subject: 'Interesting Items',
    Question:
      'These are all examples of what? British florin Spanish pistole George I shilling Spanish doubloon',
    Answer: 'coins (money)',
    Metadata: 'doubloon history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '96782',
    Subject: 'Chemical Reactions',
    Question:
      'When table salt is dissolved in water, heat is absorbed. This illustrates what kind of reaction?',
    Answer: 'endothermic',
    Metadata: 'chemical reaction chemistry physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '53213',
    Subject: 'Prisons',
    Question: 'The Abu Ghraib prison is in what city?',
    Answer: 'Baghdad',
    Metadata: '21st century Abu Ghraib history Iraq Mideast prison social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '41614',
    Subject: 'Insurance',
    Question:
      'What kind of insurance protects a real estate buyer against errors, omissions, or defects in the title of a property?',
    Answer: 'title insurance',
    Metadata: 'economics insurance real estate social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '90080',
    Subject: '\u001f\tHeat',
    Question:
      "One pound of water needs one Btu to raise its temperature one degree C. What is water's specific heat?",
    Answer: 'one',
    Metadata:
      'British thermal unit Btu heat physical science physics science specific heat temperature water',
  },
  {
    ID: '93794',
    Subject: '\u001f\u0002Momentum',
    Question:
      'When you fire a gun, how does the momentum of the gun compare to that of the bullet?',
    Answer: 'They are equal.',
    Metadata: 'momentum physical science recoil science',
  },
  {
    ID: '88602',
    Subject: '\u001fLight Adjectives',
    Question:
      'What adjective describes the distinguishing feature of light emitted from lasers in contrast to that from flames and lamps?',
    Answer: 'coherent',
    Metadata: 'laser light physical science physics science',
  },
  {
    ID: '60319',
    Subject: 'Wars',
    Question:
      'This describes what war? The soldiers who had fought at Crecy had been dead for years. Their children, their grandchildren and their great grandchildren had grown up, fought, and died, and the English army was still fighting in France.',
    Answer: "Hundred Years' War",
    Metadata:
      '14th century 15th century England Europe France history social studies war world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '57882',
    Subject: 'Military Operations',
    Question:
      "Panama's democratically elected government was restored in Operation Just Cause when the U.S. removed what dictator from power?",
    Answer: 'Manuel Noriega',
    Metadata:
      '1980s 20th century American history Central America dictator history Latin America military operation Panama social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '145696',
    Subject: '1Musical Scales',
    Question: 'How many pitches are in a chromatic scale?',
    Answer: '12',
    Metadata: 'chromatic scale fine arts music music fundamentals scale (music)',
  },
  {
    ID: '37087',
    Subject: 'Rights',
    Question:
      'You and three hundred of your neighbors meet in the city park to discuss strategies to prevent the federal government from putting a nuclear waste dump just outside town. What amendment guarantees your right to have such a meeting?',
    Answer: '1st Amendment',
    Metadata: 'amendment American government Constitution government right social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '31462',
    Subject: 'Bodies of Water',
    Question:
      'Historically, how are these bodies of water collectively known? Arabian Sea Atlantic Ocean Bay of Bengal Mediterranean Sea Persian Gulf Red Sea South China Sea',
    Answer: 'Seven Seas',
    Metadata:
      'Arabian Sea Atlantic Ocean Bay of Bengal geography Persian Gulf Red Sea sea social studies South China Sea',
  },
  {
    ID: '38010',
    Subject: 'Treason',
    Question:
      'According to the Constitution, a person can be convicted of treason only if there are at least how many witnesses who will testify against him in open court?',
    Answer: '2',
    Metadata:
      'American government Constitution crime government offense social studies treason witness',
  },
  {
    ID: '15533',
    Subject: 'Person',
    Question:
      'This is written in what person? You said that if I beat you to the end of the lake on the raft, that nobody would ever have to know about our secret.',
    Answer: 'first person',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts person',
  },
  {
    ID: '128872',
    Subject: '*Numbers',
    Question: 'Which part is a real number in this expression? x + iy',
    Answer: 'x',
    Metadata: 'math number real number',
  },
  {
    ID: '75104',
    Subject: 'Native American Architecture',
    Question: 'What is the shape of Pueblo Indian kivas?',
    Answer: 'circular (round)',
    Metadata: 'American history archaeology history Indian kiva social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '18846',
    Subject: 'Adverbs',
    Question: 'What category of adverbs answer the question, "where"?',
    Answer: 'adverbs of place',
    Metadata: 'adverb grammar language arts modifier',
  },
  {
    ID: '149172',
    Subject: '3State Nicknames',
    Question: 'What is the only state whose nickname comes from a college football team?',
    Answer: 'Nebraska',
    Metadata:
      'American geography geography nickname social studies sports sports history state history',
  },
  {
    ID: '133384',
    Subject: '+Curves',
    Question: 'What is the term for any curved line that is part of the circumference of a circle?',
    Answer: 'arc',
    Metadata: 'circle circumference curve geometry math plane geometry vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '62397',
    Subject: 'European Inventions',
    Question:
      'These were all inventions by people of what country? roulette wheel vernier scale hot air balloon Daguerreotype photography pasteurization Cartesian coordinate system Foucault pendulum',
    Answer: 'France',
    Metadata: 'Europe history invention social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '5051',
    Subject: '\u0002Poetry',
    Question:
      'What is pondered in these lines by Poe? Once upon a midnight dreary while I pondered weak and weary over many a quaint and curious volume of ...',
    Answer: 'forgotten lore',
    Metadata: 'American literature language arts literature Poe, Edgar Allan poetry quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '116333',
    Subject: '&\fAnimals Analogies',
    Question:
      'Four-legged animals are quadrupeds. What is the corresponding name for two-legged critters?',
    Answer: 'bipeds',
    Metadata: 'biology quadruped science vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '33342',
    Subject: 'Sea Namesakes',
    Question:
      'What arm of the Mediterranean was named after the king of Athens and father of Theseus who threw himself into the sea when he thought his son had died?',
    Answer: 'Aegean Sea',
    Metadata:
      'Athens etymology Europe geography Greek myth Mediterranean myth sea social studies Theseus',
  },
  {
    ID: '133132',
    Subject: '+Geometric Figures',
    Question:
      'What term refers to a solid bounded by six faces in three pairs of similar, parallel, equal parallelograms?',
    Answer: 'parallelepiped',
    Metadata: 'geometry math parallelogram polyhedron solid geometry',
  },
  {
    ID: '87756',
    Subject: '\u001dMeteorological Concepts',
    Question: 'Meteorologically speaking, partly sunny is equivalent to partly what?',
    Answer: 'partly cloudy',
    Metadata: 'earth science meteorology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '145003',
    Subject: '0\u0002 Festivals',
    Question: 'In what country is the annual Pusan International Film Festival held?',
    Answer: 'South Korea',
    Metadata: 'Asia cinema fine arts geography humanities social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '16046',
    Subject: 'Indirect Objects',
    Question: 'Restate this sentence using an indirect object. Give my regards to them.',
    Answer: 'Give them my regards.',
    Metadata: 'grammar indirect object language arts sentence analysis',
  },
  {
    ID: '85710',
    Subject: 'Mineralogy',
    Question:
      'While obsidian with white markings is called snowflake obsidian, what is the name for agate that has white markings?',
    Answer: 'frost agate',
    Metadata: 'agate earth science geology mineral science',
  },
  {
    ID: '96180',
    Subject: 'Chemical Compounds',
    Question: 'How many atoms of iron are in one molecule of iron oxide?',
    Answer: '2',
    Metadata: 'chemical compound chemistry iron oxide molecule physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '121867',
    Subject: '(\fEggs',
    Question: 'What living bird lays the largest egg?',
    Answer: 'ostrich',
    Metadata: 'biology bird egg ornithology science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '99672',
    Subject: 'Not So Swell',
    Question:
      'What is the term for a swelling of the joint between the big toe and the first metatarsal?',
    Answer: 'bunion',
    Metadata: 'bone disorder health joint science',
  },
  {
    ID: '7320',
    Subject: '\u0002Literary Techniques',
    Question: 'Anachronism involves representing someone or something out of what order?',
    Answer: 'chronological order',
    Metadata: 'American literature anachronism language arts literary technique',
  },
  {
    ID: '51357',
    Subject: 'South American History',
    Question:
      'In 1821, Simon Bolivar returned to Venezuela where he became president of a region containing present-day Colombia, Venezuela, Ecuador, and Panama, an area then known as Gran what?',
    Answer: 'Colombia',
    Metadata:
      '1820s 1821 19th century Bolivar, Simon Ecuador history Latin America Panama president (not U.S.) social studies South America Venezuela world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '53150',
    Subject: 'The Red Sea',
    Question:
      'Until about 1869, the Red Sea was primarily of local importance and was used mainly by Arab dhows. The opening of what waterway drastically changed all that?',
    Answer: 'Suez Canal',
    Metadata:
      '1860s 19th century geography history Mideast Red Sea sea social studies waterway world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '139602',
    Subject: '-Purchasing Problems',
    Question:
      'If you bought 6 pairs of socks for $4 each and 3 pairs of shoes for $38 each, excluding tax, how much did you spend?',
    Answer: '$138',
    Metadata: 'math money problem word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '16081',
    Subject: 'Sentences',
    Question:
      'This illustrates which of the three categories of declarative sentences? An invisible car came right out of nowhere, struck my vehicle, and then it vanished.',
    Answer: 'compound',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts sentence type',
  },
  {
    ID: '2568',
    Subject: 'The End is Near',
    Question:
      'This is from what novel? "Myself, I\'d trust him to the end of the Earth," said Ford. "Oh yes," said Arthur, "and how far\'s that?" "About twelve minutes away," said Ford.',
    Answer: "Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy",
    Metadata: 'English literature language arts literature novel quote science fiction',
  },
  {
    ID: '37538',
    Subject: 'Elections',
    Question:
      'In a special election, some 87 percent of the registered voters in La Podunk County voted to remove the entire board of county commissioners from office. Name this sort of election.',
    Answer: 'recall election',
    Metadata: 'American government election government local government social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '49356',
    Subject: 'Atrocities',
    Question:
      'Approximately twelve thousand of the seventy-five thousand men in the Bataan Death March were Americans. Most of the rest were of what nationality?',
    Answer: 'Filipino (Philippines)',
    Metadata:
      '1940s 1942 20th century Asia Bataan Bataan Death March death march history nationality social studies war world history World War II',
  },
  {
    ID: '98875',
    Subject: '!Electronics',
    Question: 'What is the positive terminal of a diode called?',
    Answer: 'anode',
    Metadata: 'diode electronics physical science science technology',
  },
  {
    ID: '81113',
    Subject: '\u001b\fOceanographic Vocabulary',
    Question: 'What "line" separates a land surface from an ocean or sea?',
    Answer: 'coastline',
    Metadata: 'border earth science oceanography science vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '131125',
    Subject: '*!Sequences',
    Question:
      'In any Fibonacci-like sequence, the sum of the first how many numbers in the sequence will be 11 times the seventh term?',
    Answer: '10',
    Metadata: 'Fibonacci sequence math sequence',
  },
  {
    ID: '70903',
    Subject: 'False Accusations',
    Question:
      'In 1692, George Jacobs was one of 19 persons hanged during the witchcraft delusion that swept what Massachusetts town?',
    Answer: 'Salem',
    Metadata: '1690s 17th century American history history Massachusetts social studies witchcraft',
  },
  {
    ID: '126367',
    Subject: '*Decades',
    Question: 'Express as a base 3 numeral the number of years in a decade.',
    Answer: '101',
    Metadata: 'bases (numbers) decade math',
  },
  {
    ID: '118369',
    Subject: '& Poisonous Prefixes',
    Question: 'Something that is cytotoxic has a poisonous effect on what?',
    Answer: 'cells',
    Metadata: 'biology poison prefix science toxin vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '12372',
    Subject: 'Figurative Language',
    Question:
      "What figure of speech is masterfully used in the poem from which these lines are taken? Men march 'mid moles, 'mid mounds, 'mid murderous mines. Now nightfall's nigh, now needful nature nods. Opposed, opposing, overcoming odds.",
    Answer: 'alliteration',
    Metadata: 'figure of speech language arts literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '125100',
    Subject: '*\fRoman Numerals',
    Question: 'Express as a Roman numeral the difference between ML and CCCXX.',
    Answer: 'DCCXXX',
    Metadata: 'arithmetic math Roman numeral subtraction',
  },
  {
    ID: '48613',
    Subject: 'Ancient Tools',
    Question: 'What did Mayans and Aztecs throw with atlatls?',
    Answer: 'spears',
    Metadata: 'anthropology atlatl Aztec history Indian Maya social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '52165',
    Subject: '\u0002\tWonders of the Ancient World',
    Question: 'Name either of the major rivers in the vicinity of the ancient Hanging Gardens.',
    Answer: 'Tigris, Euphrates',
    Metadata:
      'ancient history Asia Babylonia Hanging Gardens history river social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '7863',
    Subject: '\u0002Final Acts',
    Question:
      "Taken from the title of a story by Edwin O'Connor about a Boston mayor, the final action of a person before the end of a career is called the last what?",
    Answer: 'hurrah',
    Metadata: 'allusion American literature language arts literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '10342',
    Subject: 'Literary Forms',
    Question:
      'These quotes praise of what literary form? -The post is the consolation of life. -The earth has nothing like a she epistle. -As long as there are postmen, life will have zest.',
    Answer: 'letters',
    Metadata: 'language arts literary form literature quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '137401',
    Subject: ',Factoring',
    Question: 'Completely factor p squared - 3p - 4.',
    Answer: '(p+1)(p-4)',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic factoring math',
  },
  {
    ID: '18656',
    Subject: 'Grammatical Mood',
    Question:
      'What mood is illustrated in this example? They actually seem to believe that we know something about nanotechnology.',
    Answer: 'indicative',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts mood (literary)',
  },
  {
    ID: '62938',
    Subject: 'Battle Cries',
    Question: 'The battle cry, "Remember Goliad," is associated with what state?',
    Answer: 'Texas',
    Metadata:
      '1830s 1836 19th century American history battle battle cry Goliad Massacre history massacre quote social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '31535',
    Subject: 'Europe',
    Question: 'What is the smallest but most densely populated country of northern Europe?',
    Answer: 'Denmark',
    Metadata: 'Europe geography Scandinavia social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '25679',
    Subject: 'Heteronyms',
    Question:
      "Spell the heteronym that can mean either a high citadel or someone who pulls another's vehicle with chains or ropes.",
    Answer: 'tower',
    Metadata: 'citadel heteronym language arts spelling vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '49418',
    Subject: '18th-Century Explorers',
    Question:
      "England's claim to Australia and New Zealand were based on the explorations of what British captain?",
    Answer: "James Cook's",
    Metadata:
      '18th century Australia captain explorer history New Zealand social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '123110',
    Subject: '(\f Arthropods',
    Question:
      'Walking legs compose the last four pairs of appendages on arachnids. This distinguishes arachnids from what other arthropods with just three pairs of walking legs?',
    Answer: 'insects',
    Metadata: 'arachnid arthropod biology science taxonomy zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '4426',
    Subject: '\u0002Awards',
    Question:
      'What medal is presented annually to the illustrator of the most distinguished picture book for children?',
    Answer: 'Caldecott Medal',
    Metadata: 'American literature art award language arts literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '145305',
    Subject: '0Special Schools',
    Question:
      'At a school specializing in which of the performing arts would you routinely hear these terms? cabriole, arabesque, glissade, entrechat, en pointe, pirouette, pas de deux',
    Answer: 'ballet',
    Metadata: 'dance fine arts humanities',
  },
  {
    ID: '113980',
    Subject: '%The Brain',
    Question: 'The brain is composed of how many hemispheres?',
    Answer: 'two',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology brain nervous system science',
  },
  {
    ID: '48560',
    Subject: 'Protocols',
    Question:
      'The Boxer Protocol consisted of terms forced on what country after the Boxer Rebellion?',
    Answer: 'China',
    Metadata:
      '1900s 20th century Asia Boxer Boxer Rebellion history rebellion social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '92995',
    Subject: '\u001fMachines',
    Question:
      'What simple machine that incorporates the principle of the inclined plane is used in shims and splitting mauls?',
    Answer: 'wedges',
    Metadata: 'machine mechanics physical science science simple machine',
  },
  {
    ID: '80238',
    Subject: '\u001b Ocean Currents',
    Question:
      'Name the wind-driven surface current that carries water around the tip of Florida and up along the eastern seaboard of the U.S.',
    Answer: 'Gulf Stream',
    Metadata:
      'American geography current earth science Florida oceanography science state geography',
  },
  {
    ID: '85687',
    Subject: 'Gems',
    Question: "Most of the world's annual production of what gems comes from Colombia?",
    Answer: 'emeralds',
    Metadata: 'earth science gem geology Latin America mining science South America',
  },
  {
    ID: '126565',
    Subject: '*! Pythagoras',
    Question:
      'According to Pythagoras, what number representing marriage was the sum of the first male and first female numbers?',
    Answer: '5',
    Metadata: 'B.C. history math math history number Pythagoras',
  },
  {
    ID: '130755',
    Subject: '*Pumpkin Problems',
    Question: 'How many pumpkins with average weights of forty pounds are in two tons?',
    Answer: '100',
    Metadata: 'average math',
  },
  {
    ID: '123260',
    Subject: '( Hybrids',
    Question: 'Hybrid predatory animals called tigons and ligers are a mix of what two felines?',
    Answer: 'tigers, lions',
    Metadata: 'biology cat hybrid mammal science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '34300',
    Subject: 'Reservoirs',
    Question: 'Lake Nasser spans the border of what two countries?',
    Answer: 'Egypt, Sudan',
    Metadata: 'Africa border geography lake Lake Nasser social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '144623',
    Subject: '0 Sculpture and Industry',
    Question:
      'In casting, name the entrance hole and main channel in the wall of a mold through which the liquid metal is introduced.',
    Answer: 'sprue',
    Metadata: 'art casting fine arts humanities mold (art) sculpture',
  },
  {
    ID: '134425',
    Subject: '+ Kite Area',
    Question:
      'If the shorter diagonal on a kite is 4.5 feet and the other is 3.5 feet longer, what is its area?',
    Answer: '18 square feet',
    Metadata: 'area diagonal geometry math plane geometry word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '56934',
    Subject: 'Pirates',
    Question:
      'With a record of some 470 vessels captured, the most successful pirate of the golden age of piracy was Black Bart, otherwise known as Bartholomew who?',
    Answer: 'Roberts',
    Metadata: '18th century history pirate social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '31021',
    Subject: 'Social Sciences',
    Question:
      'Name the field of social science which statistically deals with such factors of human populations as distribution, growth, size and composition.',
    Answer: 'demography',
    Metadata: 'economic geography social studies sociology',
  },
  {
    ID: '127690',
    Subject: 'Welfare',
    Question:
      'Established under the Social Security amendments of 1965, what program provides publicly funded health insurance for people over sixty-five and for those who are seriously disabled?',
    Answer: 'Medicare',
    Metadata:
      '1960s American history federal program health health history health insurance history science Social Security social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '44425',
    Subject: '\u0012Crime',
    Question: 'Meth labs illegally manufacture what drug?',
    Answer: 'methamphetamine',
    Metadata: 'crime drug law social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '96960',
    Subject: 'Poisons',
    Question: 'HCN is the chemical formula for what poison?',
    Answer: 'hydrogen cyanide',
    Metadata: 'chemical compound chemical formula chemistry physical science poison science',
  },
  {
    ID: '96170',
    Subject: 'Matter',
    Question:
      'They may be single, double, or triple, ionic, covalent, or polar covalent. What are they?',
    Answer: 'bonds (chemical bonds)',
    Metadata: 'chemistry physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '134648',
    Subject: '+Circumference',
    Question:
      'What is the circumference of a tire that rotates at 400 revolutions per minute when the car is travelling 72 kilometers per hour?',
    Answer: '3 meters',
    Metadata: 'circle circumference math plane geometry word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '82068',
    Subject: 'Geologic Geography',
    Question: 'During the Paleozoic and Mesozoic eras, what supercontinent existed?',
    Answer: 'Pangaea',
    Metadata:
      'earth science geologic era geology Mesozoic era Paleozoic era science supercontinent',
  },
  {
    ID: '128506',
    Subject: '*\u0002Proportionals',
    Question: 'Find the fourth proportional in this set of numbers. 3, 1/2, 4, ...',
    Answer: '2/3',
    Metadata: 'math proportion proportional',
  },
  {
    ID: '83341',
    Subject: 'Erosion',
    Question:
      'What kind of erosion involves the wearing away of rock by friction, rubbing, scraping, or grinding by materials suspended in rivers, glaciers, and wind?',
    Answer: 'abrasion',
    Metadata: 'earth science erosion geology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '35694',
    Subject: 'Seas',
    Question: 'The Ukraine and Russia border on what sea?',
    Answer: 'Black Sea (or Sea of Azov)',
    Metadata: 'border geography Russia sea social studies Ukraine',
  },
  {
    ID: '85259',
    Subject: 'Hydrology',
    Question:
      'That part of the stream discharge that is sustained groundwater discharge in contrast to direct runoff from precipitation or melting snow is called the ---- flow.',
    Answer: 'base',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology hydrology science stream',
  },
  {
    ID: '1815',
    Subject: 'English Literature',
    Question:
      'This is from what novel? "Davis was a man, too, by all accounts," said Silver. "I never sailed along of him - first with England, then with Flint. That\'s my story."',
    Answer: 'Treasure Island',
    Metadata: 'English literature language arts literary character literature novel quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '96662',
    Subject: 'Chemical Compounds',
    Question:
      'Any substance in which oxygen is bonded to one or more electropositive atoms is classified as what kind of compound?',
    Answer: 'oxide',
    Metadata: 'chemical compound chemistry oxygen physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '118198',
    Subject: '&\tHearing',
    Question:
      'What bone in the middle ear transmits sound vibrations from the tympanum to the incus?',
    Answer: 'malleus',
    Metadata: 'biology bone ear hearing incus middle ear science tympanum',
  },
  {
    ID: '42395',
    Subject: 'Investing',
    Question: 'What is the name for the purchase of a controlling interest in a company?',
    Answer: 'buyout (acquisition)',
    Metadata: 'economics investment social studies vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '7019',
    Subject: '\u0002 Historical Poetry',
    Question:
      'Longfellow\'s "Evangeline" is about the expulsions of what group from Nova Scotia in 1755?',
    Answer: 'Acadians',
    Metadata:
      '18th century American literature Canada Evangeline language arts literature Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth Nova Scotia poetry',
  },
  {
    ID: '32314',
    Subject: 'Islands',
    Question: 'What Caribbean country owns the islands of Tortuga and Gonave?',
    Answer: 'Haiti',
    Metadata: 'Caribbean geography Gonave island social studies Tortuga',
  },
  {
    ID: '113473',
    Subject: '%Body Tissues',
    Question:
      'What kind of body tissue is composed of elongated contractile cells known as myocytes?',
    Answer: 'muscle tissue',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology cell science tissue',
  },
  {
    ID: '76100',
    Subject: 'Funerals',
    Question:
      'In 1852, the city of New Orleans held a funeral for three of the greatest U.S. statesmen of the early 19th century. These men were Henry Clay, John C. Calhoun, and what noted orator from New England who served as U.S. representative, senator, and secretary of state, and is remembered largely for supporting the preservation of the Union?',
    Answer: 'Daniel Webster',
    Metadata: '19th century American history history people secretary of state social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '41682',
    Subject: 'Taxes',
    Question: 'In terms of tax accounting, what is the meaning of the abbreviation, FET?',
    Answer: 'federal excise tax',
    Metadata: 'abbreviation accounting economics social studies taxation',
  },
  {
    ID: '47931',
    Subject: 'Genocide',
    Question:
      'The most flagrant examples of genocide in modern times occurred in Germany during World War II and in what Southeast Asian nation following the Vietnam War?',
    Answer: 'Cambodia (Kampuchea)',
    Metadata:
      '1970s 20th century Asia disaster genocide history social studies Southeast Asia world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '149932',
    Subject: '4Cyberspace Acronyms',
    Question: 'IMHO is cyberspace shorthand for what phrase?',
    Answer: 'in my humble opinion',
    Metadata: 'computer Internet technology',
  },
  {
    ID: '114941',
    Subject: '%Ear Anatomy',
    Question: 'What membrane separates the external auditory meatus from the middle ear?',
    Answer: 'tympanic membrane (tympanum, eardrum)',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology ear middle ear science',
  },
  {
    ID: '95771',
    Subject: 'Electrons',
    Question: 'How many electrons are in the fourth shell of an atom of lithium?',
    Answer: 'none',
    Metadata: 'chemistry electron electron shell element lithium physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '60629',
    Subject: 'Rome',
    Question:
      'The history of ancient Rome can be broadly divided into two epochs. The Roman Republic lasted through 27 B.C. What epoch came after that date?',
    Answer: 'Roman Empire',
    Metadata: 'ancient Rome B.C. Europe history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '142944',
    Subject: '0 Art Movements',
    Question:
      'What 20th-century literary and artistic movement attempted to express the workings of the subconscious by fantastic imagery and incongruous juxtaposition of subject matter?',
    Answer: 'surrealism',
    Metadata: '20th century art art history art style fine arts imagery',
  },
  {
    ID: '68127',
    Subject: 'Holidays',
    Question:
      'The presidential proclamation setting aside a national day of Thanksgiving was signed during what conflict?',
    Answer: 'Civil War',
    Metadata:
      '1860s 1863 19th century American history history holiday proclamation social studies Thanksgiving tradition',
  },
  {
    ID: '122655',
    Subject: '(Vertebrate Taxonomy',
    Question: 'If the classes of vertebrates are arranged alphabetically, which is last?',
    Answer: 'reptiles (Reptilia)',
    Metadata: 'biology science taxonomy vertebrate zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '125222',
    Subject: '*\u0002Percentage',
    Question: '175% of 200 equals what?',
    Answer: '350',
    Metadata: 'math percent',
  },
  {
    ID: '16242',
    Subject: 'Verbs',
    Question: 'What are the principal parts of "hurt"?',
    Answer: 'hurt, hurt, hurt',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts principal parts verb',
  },
  {
    ID: '135903',
    Subject: ',Algebra',
    Question: 'Solve this equation for x. 1/3x - 2 = 1/2x + 4',
    Answer: 'x = -36',
    Metadata: 'algebra algebraic equation equation linear equation math',
  },
  {
    ID: '75136',
    Subject: 'Wartime Factions',
    Question:
      'During the American Revolution, how were those American colonists who remained faithful to the Britain king collectively known?',
    Answer: 'loyalists (Tories)',
    Metadata: '18th century American history American Revolution history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '23600',
    Subject: 'Idioms',
    Question:
      "Whenever you must make a choice that you don't want to make, you are between a rock and a what?",
    Answer: 'hard place',
    Metadata: 'idiom language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '42228',
    Subject: 'Trusts',
    Question:
      'What kind of trusts are created to advance some public purpose such as art, education, or science?',
    Answer: 'charitable (public, philanthropic)',
    Metadata: 'economics social studies trust',
  },
  {
    ID: '1986',
    Subject: 'Poetry',
    Question:
      'These lines are from what work by Edward Lear? And hand in hand, on the edge of the sand, They danced by the light of the moon.',
    Answer: 'The Owl and the Pussycat',
    Metadata:
      "children's literature English literature language arts Lear, Edward literature poetry quote",
  },
  {
    ID: '2264',
    Subject: 'Professions',
    Question:
      'What profession is shared by these characters? Frank Galvin Kathryn Murphy Adam and Amanda Bonner Atticus Finch Perry Mason',
    Answer: 'attorney (lawyer)',
    Metadata: 'language arts literary character literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '77142',
    Subject: 'Territorial Annexation',
    Question:
      'What league founded in 1898 was especially opposed to the annexation of the Philippines by the United States?',
    Answer: 'Anti-Imperialist League',
    Metadata: '1890s 19th century American history history Philippines social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '144960',
    Subject: '0TV Tests',
    Question:
      'What is the term for a television program produced as a prototype of a possible series for a network?',
    Answer: 'pilot',
    Metadata: 'fine arts humanities performing arts television',
  },
  {
    ID: '71407',
    Subject: 'Quick Trips',
    Question:
      'In 1497, he sailed from Bristol, England "to seek out regions of the heathen." He made land in Canada, laid claim to the region, and headed home. Name this Italian explorer.',
    Answer: 'John Cabot',
    Metadata:
      '15th century age of exploration American history Canada Europe explorer history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '32155',
    Subject: 'Provinces',
    Question: 'If you alphabetize the Maritime Provinces, which is first?',
    Answer: 'New Brunswick',
    Metadata: 'Canada geography Maritime Province province social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '145324',
    Subject: '0Paintings',
    Question:
      'These are titles of what category of paintings? Valley of Mexico Vista del Pico de Orizaba Adirondack Mountains Dover Plains Dedham Vale View on the Outskirts of St. Petersburg',
    Answer: 'landscapes',
    Metadata: 'art fine arts humanities painting',
  },
  {
    ID: '118822',
    Subject: '&Organic Acids',
    Question:
      'Experimental studies of what kind of acids constitute a major part of modern biological and medical research?',
    Answer: 'nucleic acids',
    Metadata: 'acid biology life organic chemistry science',
  },
  {
    ID: '49508',
    Subject: 'International Conflicts',
    Question: 'The War of 1812 was between the United States and what other country?',
    Answer: 'England (Great Britain)',
    Metadata:
      '1810s 1812 19th century American history history social studies war War of 1812 world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '7771',
    Subject: '\u0002Native American Novels',
    Question:
      'In "When the Legends Die," Thomas Black Bull attempts to come to terms with his heritage as a member of what tribe to determine his own role in society?',
    Answer: 'Ute',
    Metadata:
      'American literature Indian tribe language arts literary character literature novel When the Legends Die',
  },
  {
    ID: '2058',
    Subject: 'Commemorative Poetry',
    Question:
      'What poem by William Butler Yeats commemorates the martyrs of the Easter Uprising, an insurrection against the British government in Ireland in 1916?',
    Answer: 'Easter 1916',
    Metadata:
      '1910s 1916 20th century Easter Uprising English literature Europe insurrection Ireland language arts literature poetry Yeats, William',
  },
  {
    ID: '98415',
    Subject: '!!Museums',
    Question:
      'The Center for Short-Lived Phenomena, which studies phenomena such as earthquakes and tsunamis, is in what American museum?',
    Answer: 'Smithsonian Institution',
    Metadata: 'earth science earthquake general science museum science tsunami',
  },
  {
    ID: '47341',
    Subject: 'Exiles',
    Question: 'Exiles from what country were trained in the U.S. for the Bay of Pigs invasion?',
    Answer: 'Cuba',
    Metadata:
      '1960s 1961 20th century American history bay Bay of Pigs exile history invasion Latin America social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '134315',
    Subject: '+Circles',
    Question:
      'Two circles have radii of 11 and 6 respectively. What is their line of centers of the circles are tangent internally?',
    Answer: '5',
    Metadata: 'circle geometry line of centers math plane geometry',
  },
  {
    ID: '34640',
    Subject: 'Eastern European Geography',
    Question: 'If you alphabetically arrange the nations adjacent to the Black Sea, which is last?',
    Answer: 'Ukraine',
    Metadata: 'Black Sea Eastern Europe Europe geography social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '36733',
    Subject: 'Definitions',
    Question:
      'Any person whose conscience, spurred by moral, ethical, or religious beliefs, would give him no rest if he were to become an instrument of war is regarded by the Supreme Court as a what?',
    Answer: 'conscientious objector',
    Metadata:
      'American government civil rights government military morality social studies Supreme Court war',
  },
  {
    ID: '76041',
    Subject: 'Debate Doctrines',
    Question:
      'In what became known as the Freeport Doctrine, Stephen Douglas stated that the will of the citizens of a region trumps any national laws as well as any decisions made by what judicial organization?',
    Answer: 'Supreme Court',
    Metadata:
      '19th century American history Douglas, Stephen Freeport Doctrine history slavery social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '16348',
    Subject: 'Grammar',
    Question:
      'Correctly state this fractured grammatical principle. Between you and I, case is important.',
    Answer: 'Between you and me',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts writing error',
  },
  {
    ID: '29697',
    Subject: 'Passes',
    Question: 'In what European country is the Great St. Bernard Pass?',
    Answer: 'Switzerland',
    Metadata: 'Europe geography pass social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '78076',
    Subject: '\u001aPlanets',
    Question:
      "The core of what planet is solid hydrogen and six times hotter than the Sun's surface?",
    Answer: 'Jupiter',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science planet science solar system',
  },
  {
    ID: '139197',
    Subject: '-Weight Products',
    Question:
      'A factory produces 7/8-lb. glass orbs. How many pounds of glass are required to produce 600 of these orbs?',
    Answer: '525 pounds',
    Metadata: 'math proportion word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '71868',
    Subject: 'Passings',
    Question:
      'Judge Roy Bean of Langtry, Texas, died in the same year as what frontierswoman and companion of Wild Bill Hickok died in Deadwood, South Dakota?',
    Answer: 'Calamity Jane',
    Metadata:
      '1900s 1903 20th century American history history Old West social studies South Dakota woman',
  },
  {
    ID: '18836',
    Subject: 'Grammatical Shifts',
    Question:
      'What is inappropriately shifted in this line? They went to the dump and their garbage was thrown out.',
    Answer: 'shift in voice',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts writing error writing shift',
  },
  {
    ID: '85807',
    Subject: 'Hydrology',
    Question: 'Regarding watersheds, what is a synonym for an affluent?',
    Answer: 'tributary',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology hydrology science stream vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '53069',
    Subject: 'Space Exploration',
    Question:
      "Launched in December of 2013, Chang'e 3 was a Chinese mission designed to explore what heavenly body?",
    Answer: 'Moon',
    Metadata:
      '2010s 2013 21st century astronomy astronomy history China earth science history social studies space exploration',
  },
  {
    ID: '62858',
    Subject: '\u0002 Presidents',
    Question: 'What U.S. president immediately preceded Dwight Eisenhower?',
    Answer: 'Harry Truman',
    Metadata:
      '1950s 20th century American history Eisenhower, Dwight history president social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '18244',
    Subject: 'Punctuation',
    Question:
      'A conjunctive adverb at the beginning of a sentence should be set off by what punctuation mark?',
    Answer: 'comma',
    Metadata: 'adverb conjunctive adverb grammar language arts punctuation',
  },
  {
    ID: '146002',
    Subject: '1 Orchestral Music',
    Question:
      'Who composed a famed piece of music based on this story? Upon receiving a Nutcracker for Christmas, a little girl dreams that the Nutcracker becomes a handsome prince who leads the toys in a battle against the mice.',
    Answer: 'Peter Tchaikovsky',
    Metadata: 'Christmas classical music composer fine arts humanities music toy',
  },
  {
    ID: '149840',
    Subject: '4Wool',
    Question: 'The removal of wool from sheep is called what?',
    Answer: 'shearing',
    Metadata: 'ranching sheep vocational wool',
  },
  {
    ID: '2882',
    Subject: 'The Lord of the Rings',
    Question: 'From whom did Bilbo Baggins acquire the ring?',
    Answer: 'Gollum',
    Metadata: 'English literature language arts literature Lord of the Rings, The',
  },
  {
    ID: '53634',
    Subject: 'The Olympics',
    Question: 'The first Olympics were held in 776 B.C. In what year were the 10th Olympics held?',
    Answer: '740 B.C.',
    Metadata: 'ancient Greece ancient history B.C. history Olympics social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '26728',
    Subject: 'Horses',
    Question: 'What is Spanish for "horse"?',
    Answer: 'caballo',
    Metadata: 'foreign language horse language arts Spanish language',
  },
  {
    ID: '116888',
    Subject: '& Worm Food',
    Question: 'The favorite food of silkworms consists of leaves from what tree?',
    Answer: 'mulberry',
    Metadata: 'biology science silk silkworm tree worm',
  },
  {
    ID: '114062',
    Subject: '%!\tThe Heart',
    Question:
      'The atrium and the ventricle on the right side of the heart are separated from the left atrium and ventricle by what thick wall of muscle tissue?',
    Answer: 'septum',
    Metadata: 'anatomy atrium biology circulatory system heart muscle science ventricle',
  },
  {
    ID: '24853',
    Subject: 'Argumentation',
    Question:
      'What phrase reminiscent of a demonic lawyer indicates a person who presents an unpopular or apparently erroneous side to bring out the whole truth or a person who opposes a case with which he does not really disagree to test its validity?',
    Answer: "devil's advocate",
    Metadata: 'debate language arts vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '140986',
    Subject: '-Nickels in the News',
    Question:
      'In 2008, an accident involving a semi-truck caused 3 million 740 thousand nickels to be scattered on the roadway. That is how many dollars worth of nickels?',
    Answer: '$187,000',
    Metadata: 'math money problem social studies word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '146550',
    Subject: '1Music Notation',
    Question: 'What is another name for the G clef?',
    Answer: 'treble clef',
    Metadata: 'fine arts music music notation',
  },
  {
    ID: '115156',
    Subject: '%\fAnatomy',
    Question: 'Name the part of the body that contains the digestive organs.',
    Answer: 'abdomen',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology digestive system science',
  },
  {
    ID: '146992',
    Subject: '1!Musical Sounds',
    Question: 'Skirling is a high wailing tone associated with what musical instrument?',
    Answer: 'bagpipes',
    Metadata: 'fine arts humanities music musical instrument',
  },
  {
    ID: '20256',
    Subject: 'Objects',
    Question:
      'What is the indirect object in this verse from the song, "I Talk to the Trees"? I tell you my dreams And while you\'re listening to me I suddenly see them come true.',
    Answer: 'you',
    Metadata: 'grammar indirect object language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '41156',
    Subject: 'International Relations',
    Question:
      'What did the U.S. grant to Svetlana Alliluyeva that was also granted by Cuba to Assata Shakur, by Iceland to Bobby Fischer, by Ecuador to Julian Assange, and by Russia to Edward Snowden?',
    Answer: 'political asylum',
    Metadata: 'government history international relations social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '90597',
    Subject: '\u001f\u0002Waves',
    Question: 'A wave is characterized by wavelength, speed, and what else?',
    Answer: 'frequency',
    Metadata: 'physical science physics science wave',
  },
  {
    ID: '125581',
    Subject: '*\f\u0002Simplification',
    Question: 'Simplify (1/2 + 1/3) / (1/2 - 1/3).',
    Answer: '5',
    Metadata: 'fraction math',
  },
  {
    ID: '114210',
    Subject: '%Openings',
    Question: 'What are the openings on either side of your septum called?',
    Answer: 'nostrils (nares)',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '142087',
    Subject: '.\tLegendary Searches',
    Question: 'When he lit his lantern and went hunting, what was Diogenes looking for?',
    Answer: 'an honest man',
    Metadata:
      'ancient Greece ancient literature Diogenes Greek literature humanities language arts legend literature philosophy',
  },
  {
    ID: '133848',
    Subject: '+\u0002 Lines',
    Question:
      'What can be said about two lines if all the pairs of vertical angles created at their intersection are supplementary?',
    Answer: 'They are perpendicular.',
    Metadata: 'angle geometry intersection math supplementary angle vertical angle',
  },
  {
    ID: '113810',
    Subject: '%Anatomical Homophones',
    Question:
      'Spell the homophone for a vein in the neck that sounds like the term for one who can keep several objects in the air by alternately tossing and catching them.',
    Answer: 'jugular',
    Metadata: 'anatomy homophone language arts neck vein',
  },
  {
    ID: '35693',
    Subject: 'European Seas',
    Question: 'What sea is between Sweden and Poland?',
    Answer: 'Baltic Sea',
    Metadata: 'Europe geography Poland sea social studies Sweden',
  },
  {
    ID: '118571',
    Subject: '&Cytology',
    Question:
      'What structure of a living animal cell selectively controls the entrance and exit of particular substances between the cell and its environment?',
    Answer: 'cell membrane',
    Metadata: 'biology cell cytology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '32797',
    Subject: 'Seas',
    Question: 'The island of Marmara is in what sea?',
    Answer: 'Sea of Marmara',
    Metadata: 'geography island sea social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '82254',
    Subject: 'Ores',
    Question: 'What metal is abundant in kidney ore?',
    Answer: 'iron',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology metal mineral ore science',
  },
  {
    ID: '141390',
    Subject: '-Inquisition Math',
    Question:
      'During the Spanish Inquisition, about 40 heretics were burned at the stake annually, or roughly, 1 heretic every how many days?',
    Answer: '9',
    Metadata: 'history social studies Spanish Inquisition word problem world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '70295',
    Subject: 'Revivals',
    Question:
      'The Great Awakening, a period of religious revivalism, occurred during what century?',
    Answer: '18th century (1700s)',
    Metadata: 'American history Great Awakening history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '25143',
    Subject: '\u0002Prefixes',
    Question: 'What is the meaning of the prefix in "quinquagenerian" and "Quinquagesima"?',
    Answer: 'fifty (fifties, fiftieth)',
    Metadata: 'affix language arts prefix vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '113957',
    Subject: '%Anatomy',
    Question:
      'What type of organ is formed by a bundle of contractile fibers attached to parts of the body which move in relation to each other when the bundle shortens?',
    Answer: 'muscle',
    Metadata: 'anatomy biology organ physiology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '141470',
    Subject: '-Palindromic Numbers',
    Question:
      '24 is the sum of the individual digits in what three-digit odd palindromic number that ends in 9?',
    Answer: '969',
    Metadata: 'math palindrome word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '116843',
    Subject: '&\fLife Stages',
    Question: 'What is the term for a fully grown, mature organism?',
    Answer: 'adult',
    Metadata: 'biology life science',
  },
  {
    ID: '57763',
    Subject: 'Literary Inspirations',
    Question:
      'What war provided material for storytellers such as Virgil, Ovid, Aeschylus, Sophocles, and Homer?',
    Answer: 'Trojan War',
    Metadata: 'ancient history ancient literature B.C. history social studies war world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '72051',
    Subject: 'Hotels',
    Question:
      'Rivaling the finest resort hotels in the East, the Del Monte Hotel was opened in 1880 on the Monterrey Peninsula by the Central Pacific Railroad boss named Charles who?',
    Answer: 'Crocker',
    Metadata:
      '1880s 19th century American history California Central Pacific Railroad history people social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '141155',
    Subject: '-Greenhouse Gas Calculations',
    Question:
      'Between 1750 and the year 2000, atmospheric carbon dioxide increased from about 280 to 365 parts per million, an increase of about what percentage?',
    Answer: '30',
    Metadata: 'carbon dioxide earth science math meteorology percent science word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '67122',
    Subject: 'Presidential Jokes',
    Question:
      'In 1951, a joke circulated about Truman beer, which was "just like any other beer but without a head." This and other jokes ridiculing the president was part of the public response to Truman\'s firing of whom?',
    Answer: 'Douglas MacArthur',
    Metadata:
      '1950s 1951 20th century American history history people president social studies Truman, Harry',
  },
  {
    ID: '36727',
    Subject: 'Celebrations',
    Question:
      'There were ceremonies in the capitals of how many nations in 1994 when NAFTA was signed?',
    Answer: '3',
    Metadata:
      '1990s 1994 20th century government history international relations NAFTA social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '1777',
    Subject: 'Keats',
    Question:
      "What are the first words in this excerpt by John Keats? ... is a joy forever. It's loveliness increases, it will never pass into nothingness but still will keep a bower quiet for us, and a sleep Full of sweet dreams, and health, and quiet breathing",
    Answer: 'a thing of beauty',
    Metadata: 'art English literature esthetics Keats, John language arts literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '82177',
    Subject: 'Soils',
    Question: 'Name the topsoil made of silt, clay, sand, and humus.',
    Answer: 'loam',
    Metadata: 'agriculture agrology earth science gardening geology science soil',
  },
  {
    ID: '60291',
    Subject: 'Change of State',
    Question:
      'In 1649, King Charles I was tried for high treason and executed. England then became a republic called what?',
    Answer: 'the Commonwealth',
    Metadata:
      '1640s 17th century Charles I England Europe history king social studies traitor world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '124126',
    Subject: "(\u0002Lots o' Birds",
    Question:
      'What long-legged, long-necked birds with pinkish plumage that thrive in the Great Lakes of eastern Africa sometimes comprise flocks numbering up to several million?',
    Answer: 'flamingoes',
    Metadata: 'Africa biology bird ornithology science wildlife zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '89199',
    Subject: '\u001f Crystallography',
    Question: 'The abbreviation, Hex," indicates what crystal system?',
    Answer: 'hexagonal',
    Metadata:
      'abbreviation crystal crystal system crystallography earth science geology matter mineral physical science physics science',
  },
  {
    ID: '84752',
    Subject: '\u0002 Energy Sources',
    Question:
      'In Ireland and Scotland, where trees are relatively scarce, stacks of what substance that forms in wetlands and is useful as a fuel can be seen in rural areas?',
    Answer: 'peat',
    Metadata: 'earth science fuel geology Ireland science Scotland',
  },
  {
    ID: '147321',
    Subject: '1Biographic Films',
    Question: 'The movie, "Amadeus," is about the life of what composer?',
    Answer: 'Mozart',
    Metadata: 'art cinema composer fine arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '64739',
    Subject: 'Philadelphia',
    Question:
      'The Articles of Confederation, the Declaration of Independence, and what other important document in American history were signed at Independence Hall?',
    Answer: 'U.S. Constitution',
    Metadata:
      'American history Articles of Confederation Declaration of Independence document history Independence Hall social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '140285',
    Subject: '-Gas Consumption',
    Question:
      'Nadine travels 100 miles and burns gas at the rate of 15 miles per gallon. With the same quantity of gas, how far could she go if she only got 12 miles per gallon?',
    Answer: '80 miles',
    Metadata: 'math proportion word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '147516',
    Subject: '1\u0002Vocal Skills',
    Question:
      'Someone who can remember, identify, and sing tones accurately without the aid of hearing another tone has perfect or absolute what?',
    Answer: 'pitch',
    Metadata: 'fine arts music vocal music',
  },
  {
    ID: '95868',
    Subject: 'Melting',
    Question:
      'When 10 grams of ice melts at zero degrees Celsius, the total quantity of heat absorbed is how many calories?',
    Answer: '800',
    Metadata: 'chemistry melting physical science science water',
  },
  {
    ID: '45665',
    Subject: '\u0012 Criminal Poems',
    Question:
      "This is about what American gangster? The guns blazed with fury as F.B.I. agents neared In a dirty alleyway of Chicago he was shot down dead. History crowned him as public enemy number one A man who got his fame as America's outlawed son.",
    Answer: 'John Dillinger',
    Metadata: '1930s 20th century American history history outlaw social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '19381',
    Subject: '\u0002Verbs',
    Question:
      'Classify the first verb in this sentence. A series of failures may culminate in the best possible result.',
    Answer: 'helping (auxiliary) verb',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts verb',
  },
  {
    ID: '79526',
    Subject: '\u001aAstronomers',
    Question:
      'Two early astronomers who favored geocentric models of the universe were Ptolemy and what Danish scientist?',
    Answer: 'Tycho Brahe',
    Metadata:
      'astronomy astronomy history earth science earth science history geocentric theory science science history',
  },
  {
    ID: '124726',
    Subject: '*Fraction Conversion',
    Question: 'Convert 4/9 to sixty-thirds.',
    Answer: '28/63',
    Metadata: 'fraction math',
  },
  {
    ID: '30094',
    Subject: 'Islands',
    Question:
      'What enormous island is south of the Bismarck Sea, east of Indonesia, north of the Gulf of Carpentaria, and west of the Solomon Islands?',
    Answer: 'New Guinea',
    Metadata:
      'Bismarck Sea geography Gulf of Carpentaria Indonesia island Oceania social studies Solomon Islands South Pacific',
  },
  {
    ID: '138354',
    Subject: ', Conic Section Symmetry',
    Question: 'What is the axis of symmetry for this parabola? y = (x-1) squared + 1',
    Answer: 'the line x = 1',
    Metadata: 'algebra axis of symmetry conic section geometry math parabola',
  },
  {
    ID: '14036',
    Subject: 'English Drama',
    Question:
      'What American colonial figure restated this quote from Shakespeare\'s "King Henry VI"? And many strokes, though with a little axe, hew down and fell the hardest-timbered oak.',
    Answer: 'Benjamin Franklin',
    Metadata: 'English literature language arts literature proverb quote Shakespeare',
  },
  {
    ID: '15005',
    Subject: 'Norse Mythology',
    Question: 'What Viking god has an implement named Mjolnir?',
    Answer: 'Thor',
    Metadata: 'language arts literature myth Scandinavian myth',
  },
  {
    ID: '128177',
    Subject: 'Medical Procedures',
    Question:
      'Physicians can avoid using invasive surgical techniques by using what kind of sound to break up kidney stones and gallstones?',
    Answer: 'ultrasound',
    Metadata: 'health medical procedure medicine science sound',
  },
  {
    ID: '93084',
    Subject: '\u001fGarden Physics',
    Question:
      'Whose theorem explains why water squirts out farther and faster from a hose when you put your thumb over the end?',
    Answer: "Bernoulli's theorem",
    Metadata: 'fluid physical science physics science scientific theory',
  },
  {
    ID: '34243',
    Subject: 'Islands',
    Question: 'Cyprus is in the eastern part of what sea?',
    Answer: 'Mediterranean',
    Metadata: 'Cyprus geography island sea social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '54998',
    Subject: 'Cause for Alarm',
    Question:
      'People jammed the supermarkets to stockpile their bomb shelters, school children practiced hiding beneath their desks during what crisis in October of 1962?',
    Answer: 'Cuban missile crisis',
    Metadata: '1960s 1962 20th century American history history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '67258',
    Subject: 'Famous Last Words',
    Question:
      "It was just after he lost the race for what office that Richard Nixon said this to the press? You won't have Nixon to kick around anymore.",
    Answer: 'governor',
    Metadata:
      '1960s 1962 20th century American history history Nixon, Richard quote social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '32255',
    Subject: 'Riot Geography',
    Question:
      'The riots described below took place in what country? A series of attempted coups and civil disturbances has afflicted the country. Last week, 123 died in a Maracaibo prison riot involving Guajiro Indians. Nine prisoners and a guard died in a Caracas prison riot.',
    Answer: 'Venezuela',
    Metadata: 'Caracas city geography prison riot social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '81991',
    Subject: 'Aquifers',
    Question: 'Name the southernmost state under which part of the Ogallala Aquifer lies.',
    Answer: 'Texas',
    Metadata:
      'American geography aquifer earth science geology hydrology Ogallala Aquifer science social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '124022',
    Subject: '(Zoology',
    Question:
      'What kind of animals are these? mahi-mahi, bream, cobia, mojarra, wahoo, amberjack, blenny, turbot, gar',
    Answer: 'fish',
    Metadata: 'biology science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '129313',
    Subject: '*Mathematical Limericks',
    Question:
      'To what field of math was Arthur Eddington referring in this limerick? There was once a brainy baboon, Who always breathed down a bassoon, For he said, "It appears That in millions of years I shall certainly hit on a tune.',
    Answer: 'probability',
    Metadata: 'field of science language arts limerick literature math',
  },
  {
    ID: '7058',
    Subject: '\u0002 Conservationists',
    Question:
      'He had seen sheepmen "and their hoofed locusts" overgrazing the Merced River Valley above Yosemite and had heard the saws of the lumber mills "booming and moaning like bad ghosts." In response, who wrote this work? God\'s First Temples - How Shall We Preserve Our Forests',
    Answer: 'John Muir',
    Metadata:
      'American literature author California conservation ecology language arts literature lumber Merced River nonfiction',
  },
  {
    ID: '27641',
    Subject: 'Prisons',
    Question: 'In what state is the Sing Sing prison?',
    Answer: 'New York',
    Metadata:
      'American geography geography prison punishment Sing Sing social studies state history',
  },
  {
    ID: '75535',
    Subject: 'Civil War',
    Question: 'More than half of the Civil War battles were fought in what single state?',
    Answer: 'Virginia',
    Metadata: '1860s 19th century American history battle Civil War history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '68929',
    Subject: 'Border States',
    Question: 'During the Civil War, which was the westernmost border state?',
    Answer: 'Missouri',
    Metadata: '1860s 19th century American history border state Civil War history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '56221',
    Subject: 'B.C. Brains',
    Question:
      'What famed ancient Greek engineer, scientist, and mathematician was killed during the siege of Syracuse in 212 B.C.?',
    Answer: 'Archimedes',
    Metadata: 'ancient Greece ancient history B.C. history social studies Syracuse world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '32883',
    Subject: 'Mideast Boat Trips',
    Question:
      'If you got out of your canoe on the western shore of the Gulf of Aqaba, you would be in what country?',
    Answer: 'Egypt',
    Metadata: 'geography gulf Gulf of Aqaba Mideast social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '117024',
    Subject: '&\u0002Electromagnetic Ecology',
    Question:
      'What term in ecology that indicates the spread of a group of organisms into new habitats also indicates the emission and propagation of energy in the form of rays or waves?',
    Answer: 'radiation',
    Metadata: 'biology ecology science vocabulary wave',
  },
  {
    ID: '82708',
    Subject: 'Atmospheric Studies',
    Question:
      "Many theorists say that four billion years ago, the Earth's atmosphere was composed of mainly methane and what other deadly gas?",
    Answer: 'ammonia',
    Metadata: 'atmosphere earth science geology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '87368',
    Subject: '\u001dClouds',
    Question: 'What is the shape of a lenticular cloud?',
    Answer: 'like a lens (biconvex lens or almond-shaped)',
    Metadata: 'cloud earth science meteorology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '124635',
    Subject: '*Other Bases',
    Question: 'Express as a binary numeral the duration of a Greek Olympiad.',
    Answer: '100',
    Metadata: 'bases (numbers) binary math math Olympiad',
  },
  {
    ID: '10223',
    Subject: 'Poetry',
    Question: 'What 17-syllable form of poetry is associated with Japan?',
    Answer: 'haiku',
    Metadata: 'Asia humanities Japan language arts literature poetic form poetry',
  },
  {
    ID: '136272',
    Subject: ',\u0002 Triangles',
    Question:
      'Find the measure of the largest angle in a triangle with these features. The second angle measures twice the first. The third angle measures eight degrees more than the first.',
    Answer: '86 degrees',
    Metadata: 'algebra angle geometry math plane geometry triangle word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '4421',
    Subject: '\u0002 Muckraking',
    Question:
      'This is from what novel? The meat would be shoveled into carts, and the man who did the shoveling would not trouble to lift out a rat even when he saw one. There was no place for the men to wash their hands before they ate their dinner, and so they washed them in the water that was to be ladled into the sausage.',
    Answer: 'The Jungle',
    Metadata: 'American literature language arts literature muckraking novel quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '60788',
    Subject: 'Military Engagements',
    Question:
      "In the Battle of Austerlitz, Napoleon's forces soundly defeated the combined armies of Austria and what other country?",
    Answer: 'Russia',
    Metadata:
      '1800s 1805 19th century battle Battle of Austerlitz defeat Europe history Napoleon Bonaparte social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '125886',
    Subject: '*\u0002Other Bases',
    Question: 'Express as a base four numeral the age at which a person can vote in the U.S.',
    Answer: '102',
    Metadata: 'bases (numbers) math',
  },
  {
    ID: '1900',
    Subject: 'Foils',
    Question: 'Helen Burns is the foil in what novel by Charlotte Bronte?',
    Answer: 'Jane Eyre',
    Metadata:
      'Bronte, Charlotte English literature foil language arts literary character literature novel',
  },
  {
    ID: '44059',
    Subject: '\u0012 Inspiring Orders',
    Question:
      "In the War of 1812, what naval commander gave this order to his men just before he died? Don't give up the ship.",
    Answer: 'James Lawrence',
    Metadata:
      '1810s 1813 19th century American history history military Navy (U.S.) quote social studies war War of 1812',
  },
  {
    ID: '50551',
    Subject: 'Calendars',
    Question:
      'Based on the date traditionally believed for the creation of the world, which calendar begins at 3761 B.C. on the Gregorian calendar?',
    Answer: 'Jewish (Hebrew) calendar',
    Metadata:
      'B.C. calendar Gregorian calendar history humanities social studies time world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '143124',
    Subject: '0Architects',
    Question: 'With what structure in Washington is the architect James Hoban associated?',
    Answer: 'White House',
    Metadata: 'architect architecture art fine arts Hoban, James humanities',
  },
  {
    ID: '129454',
    Subject: '*\u0002Exponents',
    Question: 'Restate 5 to the 1/2 power in radical form.',
    Answer: 'square root of 5',
    Metadata: 'exponent math radical (math)',
  },
  {
    ID: '145379',
    Subject: '0 Pop Art',
    Question:
      'What company produced the canned foods that Andy Warhol depicted in a series of paintings?',
    Answer: "Campbell's Soup",
    Metadata: 'American history art fine arts humanities painting Warhol, Andy',
  },
  {
    ID: '14340',
    Subject: 'Muses',
    Question:
      'What Muse is associated with the profession shared by these people? Christiaan Huygens Johannes Kepler Pierre Laplace',
    Answer: 'Urania',
    Metadata:
      'Greek myth Huygens, Christiaan Kepler, Johannes language arts Laplace, Pierre Muse myth people science science history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '146701',
    Subject: '1 Aerophones',
    Question:
      "Which aerophones are played by directing an air stream from a player's lips across a hole in the instrument or by causing a reed to vibrate?",
    Answer: 'woodwinds',
    Metadata: 'aerophone fine arts humanities music musical instrument',
  },
  {
    ID: '85854',
    Subject: 'Oceanic Landforms',
    Question: 'Abyssal fans are underwater versions of what kind of terrestrial deposits?',
    Answer: 'alluvial fans',
    Metadata: 'abyssal fan earth science geology landform science',
  },
  {
    ID: '80203',
    Subject: '\u001b Sea Floor Spreading',
    Question: 'Sea floor spreading is most clearly evident in which ocean?',
    Answer: 'Atlantic Ocean',
    Metadata:
      'diastrophism earth science geology ocean floor oceanography plate tectonics science seafloor spreading',
  },
  {
    ID: '78415',
    Subject: '\u001aAstronomical Discoveries',
    Question:
      'Astronomers have discovered a stationary storm some 5,000 miles across with a distinctive eye wall at the south pole of what planet?',
    Answer: 'Saturn',
    Metadata: '21st century astronomy earth science planet science',
  },
  {
    ID: '77744',
    Subject: '\u001aMoon Phases',
    Question: 'To the nearest whole day, what is the number of days between new moons?',
    Answer: '29',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science Moon moon phase science solar system',
  },
  {
    ID: '9226',
    Subject: '\u0002 Science Fiction',
    Question: 'What kind of technology is central in Michael Crichton\'s novel, "Prey"?',
    Answer: 'nanotechnology',
    Metadata:
      'American literature Crichton, Michael language arts literature science fiction technology',
  },
  {
    ID: '45034',
    Subject: '\u0012Law',
    Question:
      'Unequal treatment in employment based on the sex of an employee is known as what kind of bias?',
    Answer: 'gender bias',
    Metadata: 'bias employment law sex social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '26562',
    Subject: 'Missive Abbreviations',
    Question: "What is the abbreviation for these French words? repondez s'il vous plait",
    Answer: 'r.s.v.p.',
    Metadata:
      'abbreviation correspondence foreign language French language humanities language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '6248',
    Subject: '\u0002 Island Stories',
    Question:
      'What story by Richard Connell concerns a big game hunter trapped on the island of a fellow hunter who is bored with conventional prey?',
    Answer: 'The Most Dangerous Game',
    Metadata: 'American literature author Connell, Richard language arts literature short story',
  },
  {
    ID: '80300',
    Subject: '\u001bContinent Edges',
    Question: 'Around which ocean are active continental margins mostly located?',
    Answer: 'Pacific',
    Metadata: 'continental margin earth science oceanography science',
  },
  {
    ID: '24584',
    Subject: 'Fractured Sentences',
    Question:
      'What name should replace the word that is definitely wrong in this sentence? Homer also wrote "The Oddity" in which Penelope was the last hardship that Ulysses endured on his journey.',
    Answer: 'Odyssey',
    Metadata: 'Homer journey language arts literature malapropism vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '132032',
    Subject: '+\u0002Solids',
    Question:
      'What type of geometric solid can be produced by rotating a rectangle about its axis?',
    Answer: 'cylinder',
    Metadata: 'axis geometry math rectangle solid geometry',
  },
  {
    ID: '70879',
    Subject: 'Epidemics',
    Question:
      "Within 20 years of Columbus' arrival in the Caribbean, the first major epidemic occurred in the New World. Name the disease.",
    Answer: 'smallpox',
    Metadata: '16th century American history Caribbean epidemic history New World social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '28920',
    Subject: 'Border States',
    Question: 'On an alphabetical list of U.S. states bordering Canada, which is last?',
    Answer: 'Washington',
    Metadata: 'American geography Canada geography social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '94822',
    Subject: 'Matter',
    Question: 'Chemically speaking, these are all what? niobium tantalum thorium iridium beryllium',
    Answer: 'elements',
    Metadata: 'chemistry matter physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '67093',
    Subject: 'Pilots',
    Question:
      'Exactly fifty years after he first broke the sound barrier, what famous American pilot ended his supersonic career aboard an F-15 Eagle in 1997?',
    Answer: 'Chuck Yeager',
    Metadata:
      '1990s 20th century American history aviation history people pilot social studies supersonic',
  },
  {
    ID: '86317',
    Subject: '\u001dStorms',
    Question:
      'What kind of storm is more likely to occur over a region with a high vorticity potential?',
    Answer: 'tornado (waterspout)',
    Metadata: 'earth science meteorology science storm',
  },
  {
    ID: '51367',
    Subject: 'Eruptions',
    Question:
      'In 1906, the town of Ottaiano was obliterated and 100 people in Naples were killed when roofs collapsed under the weight of ash spewed from what volcano?',
    Answer: 'Vesuvius',
    Metadata:
      '1900s 1906 20th century disaster Europe history Italy Naples social studies volcano world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '93423',
    Subject: '\u001fWeaponry',
    Question:
      'What in the barrels of firearms improves the stability of bullets by imparting a spin to them?',
    Answer: 'rifling',
    Metadata: 'aerodynamics physical science science stability weapon',
  },
  {
    ID: '113632',
    Subject: '%Sensation Mythology',
    Question:
      'What name for part of the inner ear was used in Greek mythology for the maze in which the Minotaur was confined?',
    Answer: 'labyrinth',
    Metadata: 'anatomy ear Greek myth inner ear language arts maze Minotaur myth',
  },
  {
    ID: '134142',
    Subject: '+Triangular Coordinates',
    Question:
      'How many square units are in the area of a triangle with these vertices? (0,-4), (3,-4), (3,2)',
    Answer: '9',
    Metadata: 'analytic geometry area coordinate geometry geometry math plane geometry triangle',
  },
  {
    ID: '46078',
    Subject: 'Weapons',
    Question:
      'Name the colorless and odorless gas used predominantly as a military chemical nerve agent that is lethal in doses as small as .5 milligrams more than 500 times as toxic as cyanide.',
    Answer: 'Sarin',
    Metadata: '21st century history military nerve gas poison social studies weapon world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '144338',
    Subject: '0!Biographies',
    Question: "What is the term for a filmed story of a person's life?",
    Answer: 'biopic',
    Metadata: 'biography cinema fine arts vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '59266',
    Subject: 'Radio Networks',
    Question:
      'What radio network broadcasted western news throughout many parts of the Communist world beginning in 1942?',
    Answer: 'Voice of America',
    Metadata:
      '1940s 20th century Europe history journalism mass media radio social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '70405',
    Subject: 'Numismatics',
    Question:
      'The U.S. began issuing new commemorative quarters in 1999. What determined the order by which these coins honoring each of the fifty states were issued?',
    Answer: 'order of admission to the Union',
    Metadata: 'American history coin history numismatics social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '63574',
    Subject: 'Alaskan Towns',
    Question:
      'It was founded as a result of a gold strike on the Seward Peninsula, for which it was the port. This town was named for a misspelling of a nearby cape referred to on a map as "no name." Name the town.',
    Answer: 'Nome',
    Metadata:
      '1890s 1896 19th century Alaska American geography American history cape geography gold history port Seward Peninsula social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '46426',
    Subject: 'Wars',
    Question:
      'Part of what war was fought between the Communist forces under General Lin Piao and the U.N. forces under General Matthew Ridgway?',
    Answer: 'Korean War',
    Metadata: '20th century American history Asia general history social studies war world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '72182',
    Subject: 'Scandals',
    Question:
      "Some members of President Reagan's National Security Council undertook a series of covert operations in which they diverted profits made from the sale of weapons to Iran to the Contra forces of what Central American country?",
    Answer: 'Nicaragua',
    Metadata:
      '1980s 20th century American history Central America Contra history Latin America National Security Council Reagan, Ronald scandal social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '47307',
    Subject: 'Bad Relations',
    Question:
      'The pronoun in this line refers to what 20th-century U.S. president? Having spent four years of effort and gaining nothing but a lasting Mexican hostility toward the United States, he at last granted formal recognition to the Carranza regime.',
    Answer: 'Woodrow Wilson',
    Metadata:
      '1910s 20th century American history Carranza, Venustiano history Latin America social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '96036',
    Subject: 'Crystals',
    Question:
      'There are four types of crystals. Which is missing from this list? molecular ionic covalent',
    Answer: 'metallic',
    Metadata: 'chemistry crystal crystallography physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '127456',
    Subject: 'Blood Disorders',
    Question:
      'Hyperglycemia is characterized by an abnormally high level of what monosaccharide in the blood?',
    Answer: 'glucose',
    Metadata: 'blood blood test disorder health hyperglycemia monosaccharide science sugar',
  },
  {
    ID: '34834',
    Subject: 'Bays within Bays',
    Question: 'What is the largest bay in the southern reaches of Hudson Bay?',
    Answer: 'James Bay',
    Metadata: 'bay Canada geography Hudson Bay social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '68219',
    Subject: 'Revolutionary Mottoes',
    Question:
      'How was this verbose statement usually expressed during the American Revolution? By combining into a single entity we remain upright and unvanquished, but by fragmentation we undergo conquest.',
    Answer: 'United we stand, divided we fall.',
    Metadata:
      '18th century American history American Revolution history motto social studies vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '116799',
    Subject: '&! Mitosis',
    Question: 'Mitosis takes place during which phase of the cell cycle?',
    Answer: 'M phase',
    Metadata: 'biology cell cycle cytology mitosis science',
  },
  {
    ID: '112399',
    Subject: '# Fears',
    Question:
      'A highly-respected herpetologist recently claimed that most people in his profession are arachnophobic. This means that scientists who routinely handle even the most venomous of reptiles are afraid of what?',
    Answer: 'spiders',
    Metadata:
      'abnormal psychology arachnophobia biology fear field of science herpetology neurosis phobia psychology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '147530',
    Subject: '1Lyrics',
    Question:
      "This is from a song in what musical? A matchbox of our own A fence of real chain link, A grill out on the patio Disposal in the sink A washer and a dryer and an ironing machine In a tract house that we share Somewhere that's green.",
    Answer: 'Little Shop of Horrors',
    Metadata: 'fine arts lyrics music musical song',
  },
  {
    ID: '394',
    Subject: 'Literary Quotes',
    Question:
      'From what literary work was this line taken? When it was the 669th night, she said, "It hath reached me, O auspicious King, that when the two hosts drew apart, everyone went to his tent until morning."',
    Answer: 'Arabian Nights',
    Metadata: 'Arabic literature language arts literature quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '32606',
    Subject: 'Oceans',
    Question:
      'What ocean is at the intersection of a latitude of 20 degrees south and a longitude of 20 degrees west?',
    Answer: 'Atlantic',
    Metadata: 'geography latitude longitude ocean social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '28686',
    Subject: 'U.S. Cities',
    Question:
      'Buffalo, New York, is near the mouth of the Niagara River at the eastern end of what lake?',
    Answer: 'Lake Erie',
    Metadata: 'American geography geography Great Lakes New York river mouth social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '50264',
    Subject: 'Emperors',
    Question:
      'What founder of the Mongol Dynasty in China established a great capital, now Beijing, where he received Marco Polo in the thirteenth century?',
    Answer: 'Kublai Khan',
    Metadata: '13th century Asia Beijing China dynasty history Mongol social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '81530',
    Subject: 'Soil Profiles',
    Question: 'From top to bottom, name the three layers in a soil profile.',
    Answer: 'A-horizon, B-horizon, C-horizon',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology science soil soil horizon',
  },
  {
    ID: '112902',
    Subject: '#Personality Disorders',
    Question:
      'These are characteristics of which phase of bipolar disorder? inflated self-esteem reduced need for sleep excessive talkativeness distractability pursuit of risky activities',
    Answer: 'mania',
    Metadata: 'bipolar disorder disorder psychology science symptom',
  },
  {
    ID: '89743',
    Subject: '\u001fMixture Distributions',
    Question:
      'In relation to the distribution of its materials, what general category of mixture is illustrated by a glass of iced tea?',
    Answer: 'heterogeneous mixture',
    Metadata: 'matter mixture physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '62510',
    Subject: '\u0002Revolutions',
    Question:
      'The French Revolution began how many years after the American Declaration of Independence was signed?',
    Answer: '13',
    Metadata: 'Europe France French Revolution history revolution social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '84388',
    Subject: 'Sculpture Geology',
    Question: 'Alabaster is a fine-grained, translucent variety of what mineral?',
    Answer: 'gypsum',
    Metadata: 'alabaster art earth science fine arts geology mineral science sculpture',
  },
  {
    ID: '85766',
    Subject: 'Landforms',
    Question:
      'Cirques, kames, eskers, moraines, and hanging valleys are landforms created by what natural phenomenon?',
    Answer: 'glacier',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology landform science',
  },
  {
    ID: '90625',
    Subject: '\u001fLenses',
    Question: 'What lens shape is exactly the opposite of a double-concave lens?',
    Answer: 'double-convex lens',
    Metadata: 'lens optics physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '84486',
    Subject: 'Geologic Stress',
    Question:
      'Normal stress is perpendicular to the designated plane. What kind of stress is parallel to the plane?',
    Answer: 'shear stress',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology physical science physics science stress',
  },
  {
    ID: '96414',
    Subject: '\u0002Mixtures',
    Question:
      'When material is added to a gas or liquid, the material added is the solute. What is the name for the substance it is added to?',
    Answer: 'solvent',
    Metadata: 'chemistry mixture physical science science solution',
  },
  {
    ID: '70209',
    Subject: 'North American Wars',
    Question:
      'The Pequot war of 1637 involving English settlers and the Pequots occurred in the region of what modern U.S. state?',
    Answer: 'Connecticut',
    Metadata:
      '1630s 17th century American history colonial period history Indian Indian tribe Pequot War social studies state history war',
  },
  {
    ID: '24879',
    Subject: 'Vocabulary',
    Question:
      'Waht is the term for the body of rules or principles prescribed by authority or established by custom that a community or state recognizes as binding on its members?',
    Answer: 'law',
    Metadata: 'language arts social studies sociology vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '79534',
    Subject: '\u001a\u0002 Mars',
    Question:
      'Any liquid water on the surface of Mars would quickly boil away because what is so low?',
    Answer: 'atmospheric pressure',
    Metadata: 'astronomy boiling earth science Mars planet science',
  },
  {
    ID: '145899',
    Subject: '1 Song Lyrics',
    Question: "This line is from a song about what river? There's where my heart is turning ever",
    Answer: 'Swanee River',
    Metadata: 'fine arts humanities lyrics music song trivia',
  },
  {
    ID: '14384',
    Subject: 'Mythology',
    Question:
      'Her beauty aroused the envy of Aphrodite who ordered her son Eros to make this lovely lady fall in love with a monster. But Eros himself fell in love with her. Who was she?',
    Answer: 'Psyche',
    Metadata: 'Aphrodite Eros Greek myth language arts love myth',
  },
  {
    ID: '94187',
    Subject: '\u001fHomemade Telephone Science',
    Question:
      'You can make a primitive telephone by connecting two paper cups by a tight string between them. What carries the transmission of sound along the string?',
    Answer: 'waves',
    Metadata: 'communication physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '128608',
    Subject: '*\fDeduction',
    Question:
      'What is the conclusion of this syllogism? All students are bright people. All bright people study logic. Therefore ...',
    Answer: 'all students study logic',
    Metadata: 'deduction logic math reasoning syllogism',
  },
  {
    ID: '88251',
    Subject: '\u001f Dams',
    Question:
      'Name the machines in dams that convert the kinetic energy of falling water into electrical energy.',
    Answer: 'generators (dynamos, turbines)',
    Metadata: 'electricity energy kinetic energy machine physical science physics science',
  },
  {
    ID: '146695',
    Subject: '1 Get-Togethers',
    Question:
      'This American social occasion originated in the 19th century and includes such dances as jigs and reels. A digging implement used in the garden is part of its name. Identify this party.',
    Answer: 'hoedown',
    Metadata:
      '19th century American history dance fine arts history humanities music Old West tradition',
  },
  {
    ID: '143351',
    Subject: '0 Paintings',
    Question:
      'A landscape is a depiction of natural landforms. What is a depiction of an urban scene called?',
    Answer: 'cityscape',
    Metadata: 'art art form art fundamentals fine arts humanities painting',
  },
  {
    ID: '81436',
    Subject: 'Geology',
    Question:
      'What is the name for the elevating of a stream bed through the deposition of detritus?',
    Answer: 'aggradation',
    Metadata: 'deposition detritus earth science geology science sedimentation',
  },
  {
    ID: '145893',
    Subject: '1\tConcert Halls',
    Question: 'In what country is the Wiener Konzerthaus located?',
    Answer: 'Austria',
    Metadata: 'Europe fine arts geography German language humanities music social studies theater',
  },
  {
    ID: '84293',
    Subject: 'Sedimentary Rock',
    Question: 'Faults are younger than the rocks they cut according to what geologic law?',
    Answer: 'law of crosscutting relationships',
    Metadata: 'earth science fault geology science scientific law sedimentary rock',
  },
  {
    ID: '38288',
    Subject: 'Canadian Government',
    Question: 'How many seats are there in the Canadian Parliament for each of its territories?',
    Answer: 'one',
    Metadata: 'Canada government legislature parliament social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '145641',
    Subject: '1 Composers',
    Question:
      'To what composer does this refer? Deafness did not interfere with either his creative power or the quantity of his productions. He died in Vienna in 1827.',
    Answer: 'Ludwig van Beethoven',
    Metadata:
      '1820s 1827 19th century composer deafness fine arts handicap humanities music Vienna',
  },
  {
    ID: '145942',
    Subject: '1\fSound',
    Question:
      'What is the term for the simultaneous sounding of three or more musical notes that blend harmoniously?',
    Answer: 'chord',
    Metadata: 'fine arts music music fundamentals',
  },
  {
    ID: '38849',
    Subject: 'Legislative Leaders',
    Question: 'What is another title for the president of the U.S. Senate?',
    Answer: 'vice president (of the United States)',
    Metadata: 'American government Congress government legislative branch Senate social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '52301',
    Subject: 'A Magnificent Metropolis',
    Question:
      'In 1500 it had a population of over 200,000, an impressive complex of public buildings, and temples comparable to the great pyramids of Egypt. Name this capital city of the Aztecs.',
    Answer: 'Tenochtitlan',
    Metadata:
      '16th century archaeology Aztec capital city history Latin America social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '57015',
    Subject: 'Famines',
    Question:
      'This is from an account of the Soviet famine of 1932 to 1933 about what abhorrent practice? Survival is a moral as well as a physical struggle. I am not yet one of them, but am not sure I shall not be by the time this letter reaches you. Almost all who have refused to eat corpses have died.',
    Answer: 'cannibalism',
    Metadata: '20th century history social studies Soviet Union world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '127462',
    Subject: 'Disorders',
    Question:
      'Name the arthritic disorder involving painful inflammation of joints in the hands and feet that results from increased uric acid in the blood.',
    Answer: 'gout',
    Metadata: 'arthritis disorder health science uric acid',
  },
  {
    ID: '49373',
    Subject: 'Religious Beliefs',
    Question:
      'These guidelines are part of what religion founded about 500 B.C.? -Four Noble Truths -Eightfold Path -Six Paramitas',
    Answer: 'Buddhism',
    Metadata:
      'Asia B.C. Eightfold Path Four Noble Truths history humanities noble truths religion social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '232',
    Subject: 'Famous Passages',
    Question:
      'Who wrote "Devotions Upon Emergent Occasions" in which these words first appeared? No man is an island entire of itself. Every man is a piece of the continent - a part of the main.',
    Answer: 'John Donne',
    Metadata: 'English literature language arts literature poem poetry quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '25687',
    Subject: 'Plurals',
    Question: 'Spell the plural of "pueblo."',
    Answer: 'pueblos',
    Metadata: 'language arts plural spelling',
  },
  {
    ID: '38378',
    Subject: 'Protection',
    Question:
      'All measures taken by a government to protect its civilian population and its property against enemy attack are what kind of defense?',
    Answer: 'civil defense',
    Metadata: 'government social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '81831',
    Subject: 'Minerals',
    Question:
      'To what major group of minerals do these belong? quartz feldspar amphibole micas olivine',
    Answer: 'silicates',
    Metadata: 'amphibole earth science feldspar geology mica mineral olivine quartz science',
  },
  {
    ID: '21034',
    Subject: 'Oratoricle Shenanigans',
    Question:
      'Consider this statement. Our new city government has spent two million dollars on improving our streets while the last one only increased its annual street repair budget by three percent. The fallacy illustrated in this statement is known as mixing what two kinds of fruit?',
    Answer: 'apples and oranges',
    Metadata: 'debate fallacy language arts oratory',
  },
  {
    ID: '115324',
    Subject: '%\u0002Mucus',
    Question:
      'The thick fluid called mucus lines the respiratory, urinary, reproductive, and what other tract?',
    Answer: 'digestive',
    Metadata: 'biology mucus physiology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '140214',
    Subject: '-Consecutive Integers',
    Question:
      'The sum of 7 consecutive integers is 112. What is the smallest integer in this group?',
    Answer: '13',
    Metadata: 'consecutive integers math word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '91999',
    Subject: '\u001fBrakes!',
    Question:
      'You are driving along at 22 meters per second when Bambi jumps onto the highway. You hit the brakes and stop just in time 45 meters later. What was your acceleration?',
    Answer: '5.4 meters per second per second',
    Metadata: 'acceleration physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '99130',
    Subject: 'Medical Practices',
    Question:
      'A person with an infectious disease may be kept separated from other people so that the disease will not spread. Name this medical practice.',
    Answer: 'isolation (quarantine)',
    Metadata: 'health infection infectious disease science \nBody Reactions',
  },
  {
    ID: '3336',
    Subject: 'C.S. Lewis',
    Question:
      'In "Out of the Silent Planet," what planet do the Malacandrans refer to as "the Silent Planet"?',
    Answer: 'Earth',
    Metadata:
      'English literature language arts Lewis, C.S. literature novel Out of the Silent Planet science fiction',
  },
  {
    ID: '54741',
    Subject: 'Canada',
    Question:
      'The first major change to the map of Canada since Newfoundland became a province in 1949 occurred when what new federal territory was created in 1999?',
    Answer: 'Nunavut',
    Metadata: 'Canada geography history social studies territory world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '44827',
    Subject: '\u0012\u0002Officials',
    Question:
      'What title is shared by county judicial officers in Northern Ireland and the chief law enforcement officer in U.S. counties?',
    Answer: 'sheriff',
    Metadata: 'government law enforcement Northern Ireland Scotland social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '7614',
    Subject: '\u0002Fictional Characters',
    Question: 'According to Sinclair Lewis, Elmer Gantry was in what line of work?',
    Answer: 'preaching',
    Metadata:
      'American literature Elmer Gantry language arts Lewis, Sinclair literary character literature novel',
  },
  {
    ID: '139489',
    Subject: '-Statistical Fractions',
    Question:
      'How many people comprise the group given these statistics? 1/3 are male bricklayers 1/4 are female executives 1/6 are female toddlers 15 are male high school students',
    Answer: '60',
    Metadata: 'fraction math word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '87532',
    Subject: '\u001dTornadoes',
    Question:
      'A tornado with two or more condensation funnels or debris clouds rotating around a common center is said to be a multiple ---- tornado.',
    Answer: 'vortex',
    Metadata: 'earth science meteorology science storm tornado',
  },
  {
    ID: '19010',
    Subject: 'Pronoun Case',
    Question:
      'What is the case of the relative pronoun in this example? I am afraid the board of directors, whose authorization is needed for all new ideas, have hurt you in the way your tongue hurts after you accidentally staple it to the wall.',
    Answer: 'possessive case',
    Metadata: 'case grammar language arts pronoun relative pronoun',
  },
  {
    ID: '69265',
    Subject: 'Orders',
    Question:
      'As evidenced by a taped conversation, who once ordered H.R. Haldeman to tell the FBI, "Don\'t go any further in this case, period!"',
    Answer: 'Richard Nixon',
    Metadata:
      '20th century American history FBI Federal Bureau of Investigation Haldeman, H.R. history president quote social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '71449',
    Subject: 'Political Ploys',
    Question:
      'What document issued by Abraham Lincoln left the status of slaves unchanged in the border states, freed no slaves in the North where slavery did not exist, and freed the slaves in the South where Lincoln had no control?',
    Answer: 'Emancipation Proclamation',
    Metadata:
      '1860s 19th century American history border state document history Lincoln, Abraham slavery social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '7385',
    Subject: '\u0002Sick Stories',
    Question:
      'In what story by Stephen King does an amoral, shipwrecked doctor use heroin as an anesthetic and cut off his own feet and other body parts to fend off starvation?',
    Answer: 'Survivor Type',
    Metadata: 'American literature King, Stephen language arts literature short story',
  },
  {
    ID: '7635',
    Subject: '\u0002\tTalented Brothers',
    Question: 'William James was the elder brother of what novelist?',
    Answer: 'Henry James',
    Metadata:
      'American history American literature author James, William language arts literature novelist people',
  },
  {
    ID: '150104',
    Subject: '4Reality?',
    Question:
      'In what kind of "reality" do participants have the illusion of being part of a computer-generated environment?',
    Answer: 'virtual reality',
    Metadata: 'computer illusion technology',
  },
  {
    ID: '59589',
    Subject: 'History of Cambodia',
    Question:
      'Cambodia was granted full independence from what European nation at the Geneva Conference of 1954, following the defeat of that European nation in Indochina by the Viet Minh nationalists?',
    Answer: 'France',
    Metadata:
      '1950s 1954 20th century Asia Cambodia defeat Europe Geneva Conference history Indochina social studies Southeast Asia Viet Minh world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '88590',
    Subject: '\u001f Science Projects',
    Question:
      'Name the multi-billion dollar particle accelerator on the border between Switzerland and France.',
    Answer: 'Large Hadron Collider',
    Metadata:
      'Europe France history particle accelerator physical science physical science history science science history social studies Switzerland',
  },
  {
    ID: '144170',
    Subject: '0 Artists',
    Question:
      'At age 71, fighting rheumatoid arthritis, he told his doctor, "I give up. It takes all my will-power to walk and I would have none of it left for painting. If I have to choose between walking and painting, I\'d much rather paint." Name this French founder of impressionism who never walked again.',
    Answer: 'Renoir',
    Metadata:
      '1910s 20th century art art history Europe fine arts France humanities impressionism painter people quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '48216',
    Subject: 'Israeli History',
    Question:
      'Theodor Herzl believed that the solution to what "ism" would be to establish a Jewish state?',
    Answer: 'anti-Semitism',
    Metadata: 'Herzl, Theodor history Israel social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '148917',
    Subject: '3 \u0002Golf',
    Question: 'What is another name for a sand trap in golf?',
    Answer: 'bunker',
    Metadata: 'golf sports',
  },
  {
    ID: '75244',
    Subject: 'Presidents',
    Question: 'How many different men served as president of the Confederate States of America?',
    Answer: 'one',
    Metadata: '1860s 19th century American history Confederacy history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '19637',
    Subject: 'Parallel Structure',
    Question:
      'Complete this statement by Mark Twain that illustrates parallel structure. Work consists of whatever a body is obliged to do while play consists of ...',
    Answer: 'whatever a body is not obliged to do',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts literary technique parallel structure',
  },
  {
    ID: '63633',
    Subject: 'Colonial Groups',
    Question: 'What company founded New Netherland in colonial America?',
    Answer: 'Dutch West India Company',
    Metadata:
      '1620s 17th century American history colonial period history New Netherland social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '90534',
    Subject: '\u001f Atomic Weapons',
    Question:
      'Robert Oppenheimer opposed the development of the more powerful hydrogen fusion bomb. Name the physicist who led the proponents of this super bomb.',
    Answer: 'Edward Teller',
    Metadata:
      '1940s 20th century American history atomic bomb history hydrogen bomb Oppenheimer, Robert physical science history physicist science history social studies weapon',
  },
  {
    ID: '54748',
    Subject: 'Queens',
    Question:
      'When Mary Tudor resorted to persecution of Protestants to reestablish the Roman Church in England, she earned what epithet?',
    Answer: 'Bloody Mary',
    Metadata:
      '16th century atrocity England epithet Europe genocide history queen social studies Tudor, Mary woman world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '131595',
    Subject: '*Factorials',
    Question: 'Evaluate 5! times 5!.',
    Answer: '14,400',
    Metadata: 'factorial math',
  },
  {
    ID: '141787',
    Subject: '-\u0002Propeller Proportions',
    Question:
      'The ratio of the rotation of a propeller to the engine driving it is 3 to 4. If the engine is turning at 5600 rpm, what is the propeller rate?',
    Answer: '4200 rpm',
    Metadata: 'math proportion word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '123187',
    Subject: '(\fBats',
    Question: 'Including their rudimentary "thumbs," bats have how many total fingers?',
    Answer: '10',
    Metadata: 'bat biology science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '2778',
    Subject: 'Sleuths',
    Question: 'Who is the detective in the novel, "Death in the Air," by Agatha Christie?',
    Answer: 'Hercule Poirot',
    Metadata:
      'Christie, Agatha detective English literature language arts literary character literature novel',
  },
  {
    ID: '63675',
    Subject: 'Presidential Acts',
    Question:
      'In 1836, on his last day in office, what U.S. president recognized the Republic of Texas?',
    Answer: 'Andrew Jackson',
    Metadata: '1830s 1836 19th century American history history social studies Texas',
  },
  {
    ID: '141246',
    Subject: '-Coin Problems',
    Question:
      'If you have 95 coins consisting of nickels and pennies and their value is $2.75, how many nickels do you have?',
    Answer: '45',
    Metadata: 'coin problem math word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '22048',
    Subject: 'Allusions',
    Question:
      'What verb meaning "to perform ostentatiously so as to impress an audience" was taken from the name for the spectators at an athletic event?',
    Answer: 'grandstand',
    Metadata: 'allusion language arts performing arts sports',
  },
  {
    ID: '47881',
    Subject: 'Political Movements',
    Question:
      'The 19th-century Flemish Movement was a cultural and political movement promoting the recognition of Dutch-speaking inhabitants of what country?',
    Answer: 'Belgium',
    Metadata: '19th century Europe Flemish history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '132801',
    Subject: '+\u0002Circles',
    Question: 'Find the circumference of a circle with a radius of 5 meters.',
    Answer: '3.14 meters',
    Metadata: 'circle circumference geometry math plane geometry radius',
  },
  {
    ID: '47458',
    Subject: 'Uncommon Careers',
    Question:
      'These folks participated in what illegal activity? John Andre Nathan Hale Alger Hiss Ethel Rosenberg Mata Hari Allan Pinkerton',
    Answer: 'spying (espionage)',
    Metadata:
      'Andre, John Hale, Nathan Hiss, Alger history people Pinkerton, Allan Rosenberg, Ethel social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '60395',
    Subject: '\u0002Walls',
    Question:
      'Name the Roman emperor who ordered the construction of a wall to prevent enemies from invading England from Scotland.',
    Answer: 'Hadrian',
    Metadata: 'emperor England Europe history Scotland social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '83414',
    Subject: 'Glaciation',
    Question: 'What kind of glacial deposit is Long Island in New York?',
    Answer: '(terminal, end) moraine',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology glacier Long Island New York science',
  },
  {
    ID: '132929',
    Subject: '+Quadrilaterals',
    Question:
      'Four times the square root of 2 is the length of the diagonal of a square how many units on each side?',
    Answer: '4',
    Metadata: 'diagonal geometry math plane geometry quadrilateral square',
  },
  {
    ID: '40443',
    Subject: 'Political Policies',
    Question:
      "A nation's guiding principles regarding how it interacts with other countries comprises what policy?",
    Answer: 'foreign policy',
    Metadata: 'government international relations social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '146301',
    Subject: '1! Broadway Biographies',
    Question:
      "These are songs from a musical celebrating the life of what American entertainment impresario? Museum Song The Prince of Humbug There's a Sucker Born Every Minute Join the Circus",
    Answer: 'P.T. Barnum',
    Metadata: 'American history fine arts humanities music musical song',
  },
  {
    ID: '45741',
    Subject: '\u0012Conscription',
    Question:
      'A form of temporary conscription in the United States empowers some law enforcement officers to summon local citizens for assistance in the execution of certain warrants. What is the name for the body of people assembled in this way?',
    Answer: 'posse',
    Metadata: 'government law law enforcement local government social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '31708',
    Subject: 'Emirates',
    Question: 'What country forms the western border of the United Arab Emirates?',
    Answer: 'Saudi Arabia',
    Metadata: 'border geography Mideast social studies United Arab Emirates',
  },
  {
    ID: '78383',
    Subject: '\u001aStars',
    Question: 'What yellow dwarf star is closest to the Earth?',
    Answer: 'Sun',
    Metadata: 'astronomy dwarf star earth science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '15286',
    Subject: 'Pronouns',
    Question: 'How are these pronouns classified? no one, each other, somebody, everything',
    Answer: 'indefinite pronouns',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts pronoun',
  },
  {
    ID: '91339',
    Subject: '\u001f The Earth',
    Question: "What fundamental force is responsible for Earth's spherical shape?",
    Answer: 'gravity',
    Metadata: 'earth science force fundamental force geology physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '126675',
    Subject: '*! Fields of Science',
    Question:
      'Name the field referred to in this passage. Originated in 1948 by Norbert Wiener, this field studies the mathematical structure of control and communication in such diverse systems as automata, computers and control mechanisms.',
    Answer: 'cybernetics',
    Metadata:
      '1940s 1948 20th century communication computer field of science math history science history technology Wiener, Norbert',
  },
  {
    ID: '148140',
    Subject: '1\u0002Musical Instruments',
    Question: 'What is the common name for most instruments classified as membranophones?',
    Answer: 'drums',
    Metadata: 'fine arts humanities membranophone music musical instrument',
  },
  {
    ID: '42031',
    Subject: 'Currency',
    Question:
      "Since Hamilton's time, government paper money had been backed by precious metal bought and stored by the Treasury. But, currency issued during Lincoln's administration to pay for the Civil War was based only on the government's credit. What were these bills called?",
    Answer: 'greenbacks',
    Metadata:
      '1860s 19th century American history Civil War currency economics history Lincoln, Abraham precious metal social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '113105',
    Subject: '%Muscle',
    Question:
      'What category of muscle produces movements of these body parts? jaws the face eyeballs the trunk',
    Answer: 'skeletal (or striated)',
    Metadata: 'biology muscle physiology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '71417',
    Subject: '18th-Century Political Factions',
    Question:
      "What 18th century political party opposed adoption of the Constitution, favored states' rights, and consistently opposed expansion of the powers of the federal government?",
    Answer: 'Antifederalists',
    Metadata:
      "18th century American government American history history political party social studies states' rights",
  },
  {
    ID: '21131',
    Subject: 'Prefixes',
    Question: 'What does the prefix in "traverse" mean?',
    Answer: 'across',
    Metadata: 'affix language arts prefix',
  },
  {
    ID: '52929',
    Subject: 'Sea Battles',
    Question:
      'In 1916, the German High Seas Fleet under Admiral Scheer was lured into what battle with the British Grand Fleet under Admiral Jellicoe?',
    Answer: 'Battle of Jutland',
    Metadata:
      '1910s 1916 20th century admiral battle Europe fleet history social studies world history World War I',
  },
  {
    ID: '120422',
    Subject: 'Plant Cells',
    Question:
      'Plant immobility is largely due to the fact that their cells are surrounded by cell walls consisting of a rigid material that is chiefly what carbohydrate?',
    Answer: 'cellulose',
    Metadata: 'biology botany carbohydrate cytology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '418',
    Subject: 'Forms of Poetry',
    Question: 'What style of poetry concerns the rural environment and idyllic lives of shepherds?',
    Answer: 'pastoral',
    Metadata:
      'Greek literature humanities language arts literary form literary style literature poetic form poetry',
  },
  {
    ID: '65707',
    Subject: 'Colonial Quotes',
    Question:
      'This was stated by the leader of which American colony? That so we might after a more special manner rejoice together after we had gathered the fruit of our labors.',
    Answer: 'Plymouth',
    Metadata: '17th century American history colonial period colony history quote social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '33012',
    Subject: 'Latin America',
    Question: 'What is the longest but not the largest country in South America?',
    Answer: 'Chile',
    Metadata: 'geography Latin America social studies South America',
  },
  {
    ID: '89086',
    Subject: '\u001fMatter',
    Question: 'What is the term for the change of a substance to a denser phase?',
    Answer: 'condensation',
    Metadata: 'matter phase change physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '123054',
    Subject: '(Reptiles',
    Question:
      'What heavy-bodied lizards of the American Southwest have beadlike dorsal scales, grooved teeth, and venom glands opening onto the outer gum of the lower jaw?',
    Answer: 'Gila monsters (Mexican beaded lizards)',
    Metadata: 'biology lizard reptile scale (biology) science venom zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '124082',
    Subject: '(Life Classifications',
    Question: 'Amniotes include reptiles, mammals, and what other large group of creatures?',
    Answer: 'birds',
    Metadata: 'amniote biology science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '84297',
    Subject: 'Volcanoes',
    Question:
      "What is said to occur whenever solid, liquid, or gaseous volcanic materials are ejected into the Earth's atmosphere or onto the surface by volcanic activity?",
    Answer: 'eruption',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology science volcano',
  },
  {
    ID: '149577',
    Subject: '3\u0002Sports',
    Question: 'The Ryder Cup is a competition in what sport?',
    Answer: 'golf',
    Metadata: 'sports',
  },
  {
    ID: '123689',
    Subject: '(\tPolymers',
    Question:
      'What polymer and polysaccharide is the primary component of the cell walls of fungi, the exoskeletons of arthropods, the radulas of mollusks, and the beaks of squid?',
    Answer: 'chitin',
    Metadata: 'biology exoskeleton fungus polymer polysaccharide science squid zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '84773',
    Subject: 'Volcanoes',
    Question: 'On which continent is the Cotopaxi volcano?',
    Answer: 'South America',
    Metadata: 'continent Cotopaxi earth science geography geology science social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '84551',
    Subject: 'Stream Profiles',
    Question:
      'While the discharge of a stream increases toward the mouth, what happens to its gradient?',
    Answer: 'It decreases.',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology hydrology science stream',
  },
  {
    ID: '55977',
    Subject: 'Latin American Dictators',
    Question: 'After World War II, Juan and Eva Peron developed a dictatorship in what country?',
    Answer: 'Argentina',
    Metadata:
      '20th century history Latin America Peron, Juan social studies South America world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '77689',
    Subject: '\u001a\fPlanets',
    Question:
      'What is the first letter of the alphabet that does not appear in the name of any planet?',
    Answer: 'b',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science planet science solar system',
  },
  {
    ID: '65050',
    Subject: 'Pardons',
    Question: 'What president unconditionally pardoned almost 10,000 Vietnam War draft evaders?',
    Answer: 'Jimmy Carter',
    Metadata:
      '20th century American history draft history pardon president social studies Vietnam War',
  },
  {
    ID: '2298',
    Subject: 'Climatic Poetry',
    Question:
      "With a term meaning humid and hot, complete this couplet by Lord Byron. What men call gallantry and gods adultery Is much more common where the climate's ...",
    Answer: 'sultry',
    Metadata:
      'adultery climate couplet English literature language arts literature Lord Byron poetry poetry ending',
  },
  {
    ID: '40865',
    Subject: 'Political Vocabulary',
    Question:
      'Reminiscent of a traffic jam, what is a synonym for deadlock, a situation involving opposing parties in which no progress can be made?',
    Answer: 'gridlock',
    Metadata: 'government politics social studies vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '127103',
    Subject: 'Inflammations',
    Question: 'Bursitis is the inflammation of what fluid-filled sacs between bones and tendons?',
    Answer: 'bursae (bursas)',
    Metadata: 'anatomy bone bursitis disorder health inflammation science tendon',
  },
  {
    ID: '80677',
    Subject: '\u001b Continents',
    Question: 'The submerged edges of continents with gradual slopes are called continental what?',
    Answer: 'shelves',
    Metadata: 'continent earth science geology oceanography science',
  },
  {
    ID: '84525',
    Subject: '\u0002Seafloor Spreading',
    Question:
      'Name the long, narrow sea adjacent to Mexico that was created by seafloor spreading.',
    Answer: 'Sea of Cortes (Gulf of California)',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology plate tectonics science seafloor spreading',
  },
  {
    ID: '16482',
    Subject: 'Adjectives',
    Question:
      'What degree of adjective comparison is used in this example? Here bloom red roses dewy wet And beds of fragrant mignonette.',
    Answer: 'positive',
    Metadata: 'adjective grammar language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '45896',
    Subject: '\u0012 Laws',
    Question:
      'What is the meaning of the abbreviation "FOI" in relation to laws requiring the government to release documents to the public on request or to state why the information cannot be released?',
    Answer: 'freedom of information',
    Metadata: 'abbreviation American government government law legislation social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '118204',
    Subject: '&Post Mortem',
    Question:
      "Increasing rigidity of the body's muscles and joints begins soon after death and reaches its maximum in ten to fifteen hours. It then subsides twenty-four to thirty-six hours later. Name this phenomenon.",
    Answer: 'rigor mortis',
    Metadata: 'biology death muscle science',
  },
  {
    ID: '53416',
    Subject: 'Island Hideaways',
    Question:
      'Name the island southeast of Tahiti upon which nine mutineers, six Tahitian men, and thirteen women remained undiscovered between 1787 and 1808.',
    Answer: 'Pitcairn Island',
    Metadata: '18th century history island mutiny Oceania social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '50892',
    Subject: '\u0002 Codes of Behavior',
    Question: 'The code of honor of the military caste called Bushido developed in what country?',
    Answer: 'Japan',
    Metadata: 'Asia Bushido caste history social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '135343',
    Subject: '+Pyramids',
    Question: 'The apothem of a truncated pyramid equals the height of what?',
    Answer: 'any of its sides (a side)',
    Metadata: 'apothem geometry math pyramid solid geometry',
  },
  {
    ID: '26533',
    Subject: 'French',
    Question: "What is the meaning of this French expression? billet d'amour",
    Answer: 'love letter',
    Metadata: 'foreign language French language language arts',
  },
  {
    ID: '5454',
    Subject: '\u0002Faulknerian Quotations',
    Question:
      'What word completes this thought by William Faulkner? Man will not merely endure. He will ...',
    Answer: 'prevail',
    Metadata: 'American literature Faulkner, William language arts literature quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '49251',
    Subject: 'Island Explorers',
    Question:
      'In this archipelago, the land is poor and the climate is worse. What explorer first called this region "Tierra del Fuego"?',
    Answer: 'Ferdinand Magellan',
    Metadata:
      '16th century archipelago explorer history Latin America quote social studies South America Tierra del Fuego world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '116722',
    Subject: '&! Geologic Time',
    Question:
      'The age of insects, the age of crinoids, and the age of fishes all occurred during which era of geologic time?',
    Answer: 'Paleozoic era',
    Metadata:
      'biology crinoid earth science fish geologic era geologic time geology insect science',
  },
  {
    ID: '15624',
    Subject: 'Punctuation',
    Question: 'Indirect questions end with what punctuation mark?',
    Answer: 'period',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts punctuation',
  },
  {
    ID: '80157',
    Subject: '\u001bTides',
    Question:
      'Spring tides occur during two different moon phases, the new moon phase and what other?',
    Answer: 'full moon phase',
    Metadata: 'earth science Moon oceanography science spring tide tide',
  },
  {
    ID: '87837',
    Subject: '\u001f Atmospheric Pressure',
    Question:
      'A thirty-inch column of what element can be supported by normal air pressure at sea level?',
    Answer: 'mercury',
    Metadata:
      'atmospheric pressure earth science measurement meteorology physical science physics science',
  },
  {
    ID: '37519',
    Subject: 'Conferences',
    Question:
      'What organization convened these conferences? -1992 Earth Summit -1993 World Conference on Human Rights -1994 World Summit on Trade Efficiency -1995 Fourth World Conference on Women -2001 World Conference on Racism -2005 World Conference on Disaster Reduction',
    Answer: 'United Nations',
    Metadata: 'government history international relations social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '606',
    Subject: 'British Verse',
    Question:
      'What poet laureate appointed by Queen Victoria in 1850 wrote this imaginative verse? Who would be a mermaid fair, Singing alone, combing her hair Under the sea, in a golden curl With a comb of pearl, on a throne?',
    Answer: 'Alfred Tennyson',
    Metadata:
      '19th century author English literature language arts literature poet laureate poetry Queen Victoria quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '133827',
    Subject: '+Reasoning',
    Question:
      'Which of the two types of reasoning is used in this example? The perimeter of a square is 16 feet, so each side is 4 feet.',
    Answer: 'deduction',
    Metadata: 'geometry math perimeter reasoning',
  },
  {
    ID: '66966',
    Subject: 'Never Said It',
    Question:
      'Horace Greeley publicly, repeatedly, and unsuccessfully denied ever having used what famous statement coined by John Lane Soule?',
    Answer: 'Go west young man.',
    Metadata: '19th century American history Greeley, Horace history quote social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '150172',
    Subject: '4The Internet',
    Question:
      'Name the transmission technology capable of simultaneously supporting voice, high-speed data, and video.',
    Answer: 'broadband',
    Metadata: 'electronics Internet technology vocational',
  },
  {
    ID: '17759',
    Subject: 'Phrases',
    Question:
      'What kind of phrase begins this sentence? Having fooled some of the people some of the time, Bill went on to see what he could do with all of the people.',
    Answer: 'participial (participle)',
    Metadata: 'grammar language arts phrase',
  },
  {
    ID: '144584',
    Subject: '0#Digital Photography',
    Question: 'The number of pixels in a digital photo is commonly called its image what?',
    Answer: 'resolution',
    Metadata: 'art fine arts photography technology',
  },
  {
    ID: '63464',
    Subject: 'Muckraking',
    Question:
      'Terrible conditions in what industry were exposed in Upton Sinclair\'s novel, "The Jungle"?',
    Answer: 'meat packing',
    Metadata:
      '1900s 1906 20th century American history American literature history industry Jungle, The language arts literature muckraking novel Sinclair, Upton social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '34755',
    Subject: '\u0002River Regions',
    Question:
      'What is the general name for the land on both sides of the Rhine River in western Germany?',
    Answer: 'Rhineland',
    Metadata: 'Europe geography Germany Rhine River social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '52173',
    Subject: '\u0002Water Tanks',
    Question: 'Medieval castles had tanks for holding rainwater. Name these receptacles.',
    Answer: 'cisterns',
    Metadata: 'history medieval social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '121121',
    Subject: '(Byrd Birds',
    Question: 'What type of bird is most prevalent in the region explored by Richard Byrd?',
    Answer: 'penguin (or tern)',
    Metadata: 'biology bird Byrd, Richard ornithology science zoology',
  },
  {
    ID: '149244',
    Subject: '3Swimming',
    Question: 'When swimming a medley, what stroke is swum first?',
    Answer: 'butterfly',
    Metadata: 'sports swimming',
  },
  {
    ID: '45689',
    Subject: '\u0012Legal Documents',
    Question:
      'What is the name for a document with a form resembling this? This court orders the sheriff to locate the named person, wherever he may be found, and to deliver that said person to the custody of this court.',
    Answer: 'warrant (arrest warrant, delivery warrant)',
    Metadata: 'law legal document social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '63390',
    Subject: 'Land Deals',
    Question: 'In 1803, the U.S. purchased Louisiana from what country?',
    Answer: 'France',
    Metadata:
      '1800s 1803 19th century American history history Louisiana social studies westward expansion',
  },
  {
    ID: '135352',
    Subject: '+Circles',
    Question:
      'What is the geometric term for a circular disk with a concentric hole at its center?',
    Answer: 'annulus',
    Metadata: 'circle geometry math plane geometry vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '145863',
    Subject: '1 Folk Songs',
    Question:
      'According to the folksong, what is the color of the elderly female mammal that "ain\'t what she used to be"?',
    Answer: 'gray',
    Metadata: 'fine arts folksong humanities lyrics music song',
  },
  {
    ID: '118157',
    Subject: '&Biomes',
    Question:
      'Boreal describes the northern biotic area dominated by tundra, taiga, and what kind of forests?',
    Answer: 'coniferous (evergreen)',
    Metadata: 'biology biome boreal forest science',
  },
  {
    ID: '6894',
    Subject: '\u0002Novels',
    Question: 'This is the opening line of what Ayn Rand novel? Who is John Galt?',
    Answer: 'Atlas Shrugged',
    Metadata:
      'American literature language arts literary beginning literature novel quote Rand, Ayn',
  },
  {
    ID: '134883',
    Subject: '+Volume Problems',
    Question:
      'A tank with a square base has sides 1.2 meters long. If it contains 3600 liters of water, the depth is how many centimeters?',
    Answer: '250',
    Metadata: 'geometry math solid geometry volume word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '145391',
    Subject: '0Theater',
    Question: 'What is a synonym for an arena stage?',
    Answer: 'theater in the round',
    Metadata: 'fine arts humanities theater',
  },
  {
    ID: '130999',
    Subject: '*Numbers',
    Question: 'What comes next in this sequence of Fibonnaci numbers? 144, 233, 377, ...',
    Answer: '610',
    Metadata: 'Fibonacci sequence math sequence',
  },
  {
    ID: '92335',
    Subject: '\u001fOptical Images',
    Question: 'What kind of image that cannot be projected can be seen by looking through a lens?',
    Answer: 'virtual image',
    Metadata: 'image lens optics physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '70287',
    Subject: 'Official Banners',
    Question: 'What state has a yellow beaver on a blue field on one side of its flag?',
    Answer: 'Oregon',
    Metadata: 'American history flag history social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '64581',
    Subject: 'Space Programs',
    Question: 'Which manned space flight program was first to place an American in space?',
    Answer: 'Mercury',
    Metadata: '20th century American history history social studies space exploration',
  },
  {
    ID: '22994',
    Subject: 'Affixes',
    Question: 'What is indicated by these Greek affixes? philo- -phile -philia -phily',
    Answer: 'love',
    Metadata: 'affix language arts prefix suffix',
  },
  {
    ID: '84684',
    Subject: 'Crustal Features',
    Question:
      "In what kind of circular deformation of the Earth's crust are the youngest strata found in the center?",
    Answer: 'basin',
    Metadata: 'earth science geology science stratigraphy',
  },
  {
    ID: '1017',
    Subject: 'Fictional Characters',
    Question:
      'What rotund twins who are exactly alike in speech, manner, and appearance were created by Lewis Carroll?',
    Answer: 'Tweedledum, Tweedledee',
    Metadata:
      'Alice in Wonderland Carroll, Lewis English literature fantasy language arts literary character literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '149235',
    Subject: '3! Athletes',
    Question:
      'Name the most celebrated and gifted athlete ever coached by Pop Warner at the Carlisle Indian School in Pennsylvania.',
    Answer: 'Jim Thorpe',
    Metadata:
      '20th century American history history Indian Pennsylvania people sports sports history track',
  },
  {
    ID: '27969',
    Subject: 'City Nicknames',
    Question:
      'What California city has these nicknames? Ess Eff Fogtown Baghdad by the Bay The City by the Bay',
    Answer: 'San Francisco',
    Metadata:
      'American geography California city geography nickname social studies state geography',
  },
  {
    ID: '93970',
    Subject: '\u001f\u0002Physical Phenomena',
    Question:
      'These are characteristics of what disturbances traveling through a medium? transmission, absorption, reflection, interference, reflection, diffraction, polarization',
    Answer: 'waves',
    Metadata: 'physical science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '50327',
    Subject: 'Anthropology',
    Question:
      'German paleontologist Hans Reck found the remains of hundreds of extinct Pleistocene mammals in the same African gorge where Louis and Mary Leakey later found stone tools. Name that gorge.',
    Answer: 'Olduvai Gorge',
    Metadata:
      '20th century Africa anthropology geologic epoch gorge history Leakey Pleistocene epoch social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '36845',
    Subject: 'Taxation',
    Question:
      'The power of the U.S. government to levy income taxes is established by what amendment?',
    Answer: '16th',
    Metadata: 'amendment American government government income tax social studies taxation',
  },
  {
    ID: '116727',
    Subject: '&The Skeleton',
    Question:
      'The thorax is one of the three regions of the axial skeleton. Identify either of the others.',
    Answer: 'skull, spinal column',
    Metadata: 'axial skeleton biology science skeletal system thorax',
  },
  {
    ID: '98346',
    Subject: '!!Collectors',
    Question: 'What did the scientist, Harvey Nininger collect?',
    Answer: 'meteorites',
    Metadata: 'earth science history Nininger, Harvey science history',
  },
  {
    ID: '82153',
    Subject: 'Mythical Geology',
    Question:
      'The guardian of Crete stood on high cliffs and threw boulders at approaching ships. His name is the same as what geological term for a sloping mass of debris at the bottom of a cliff?',
    Answer: 'talus',
    Metadata: 'cliff Crete earth science geology Greek myth language arts myth science',
  },
  {
    ID: '54889',
    Subject: 'New Nations',
    Question:
      'From 1975 to 1999, East Timor was considered a province by what Southeast Asian nation?',
    Answer: 'Indonesia',
    Metadata: '20th century Asia East Timor history social studies Southeast Asia world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '140757',
    Subject: '-Unlikely Interstellar Travel',
    Question:
      'An Apollo spacecraft took 3 days to reach the Moon which is 100 million times closer than Proxima Centauri. At that rate, to the nearest 100,000, how many years would it take a vehicle to travel from Earth to that nearby star?',
    Answer: '800,000',
    Metadata: 'astronomy earth science math Proxima Centauri science star word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '112806',
    Subject: '#Disorders',
    Question: 'Dementia involves reduced functioning of what organ?',
    Answer: 'brain',
    Metadata: 'abnormal psychology dementia disorder psychology science',
  },
  {
    ID: '78870',
    Subject: '\u001a\u000217th-Century Astronomy',
    Question: 'Giovanni Cassini discovered the major division in the rings of what planet?',
    Answer: 'Saturn',
    Metadata:
      '17th century astronomy astronomy history Cassini, Giovanni earth science planet science',
  },
  {
    ID: '29670',
    Subject: 'Georgia',
    Question: 'Georgia borders Azerbaijan, Armenia, Russia, and what sea?',
    Answer: 'Black Sea',
    Metadata: 'Armenia Azerbaijan border geography Georgia (republic) social studies Transcaucasia',
  },
  {
    ID: '43073',
    Subject: 'Businesses',
    Question:
      'What kind of shop loans you money for items you bring in, and then gives you a month or two to redeem the items by repaying the money owed plus a fee?',
    Answer: 'pawn shop',
    Metadata: 'business economics loan social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '146239',
    Subject: '1 Dance',
    Question:
      "In what kind of dance are these lyrics heard? Ladies change! Shet up dat talkin! Do yo' talkin' after while. Right and lef' don't want no walkin' Make yo' steps an' show yo' style.",
    Answer: 'square dance',
    Metadata: 'dance fine arts humanities lyrics music',
  },
  {
    ID: '85066',
    Subject: 'Plate Tectonics',
    Question: 'Name the greatest tectonic plate underlying the Bay of Bengal.',
    Answer: 'Indian Plate',
    Metadata: 'Asia Bay of Bengal geography geology plate tectonics social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '149187',
    Subject: '3Track Events',
    Question:
      'The heptathlon consists of seven events. Which is missing from this list? 100 meter hurdles high jump shot put 200 and 800 meter run long jump',
    Answer: 'javelin',
    Metadata: 'sports track',
  },
  {
    ID: '80459',
    Subject: '\u001b\tSpits',
    Question: 'When a spit reaches partly across the mouth of a bay, it is a bay-mouth what?',
    Answer: 'bar',
    Metadata: 'bay coast earth science geology landform oceanography science spit',
  },
  {
    ID: '86126',
    Subject: '\u001dMeasurement Scales',
    Question: 'What scale ranging from 0 to 17 is used to classify wind velocities?',
    Answer: 'Beaufort',
    Metadata: 'earth science meteorology scale science wind',
  },
  {
    ID: '1221',
    Subject: 'Bards',
    Question: 'Who was the Bard of Avon?',
    Answer: 'William Shakespeare',
    Metadata: 'author bard English literature epithet language arts literature',
  },
  {
    ID: '55899',
    Subject: 'Uprisings',
    Question:
      'Palestinians staged their first intifada from 1987 to 1991 to protest the Israeli occupation of the West Bank and what Mediterranean coastal area?',
    Answer: 'Gaza Strip',
    Metadata: 'history intifada Israel Mideast protest social studies world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '15106',
    Subject: 'Appositives',
    Question:
      'What phrase is used in apposition in this line? NASA, hoping to salvage the Hubble Space Telescope project, announced plans to launch Rex, the $1.1 billion seeing-eye satellite.',
    Answer: 'the $1.1 billion seeing-eye satellite',
    Metadata: 'appositive grammar language arts sentence analysis',
  },
  {
    ID: '29320',
    Subject: '\u0002Counties',
    Question:
      'These are counties in what U.S. state? Middlesex, Berkshire, Suffolk, Essex, Nantucket, Plymouth',
    Answer: 'Massachusetts',
    Metadata: 'American geography county geography social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '128711',
    Subject: '*Metric Prefixes',
    Question: 'The prefix "atto" in the metric system denotes ten to what power?',
    Answer: '-18th power',
    Metadata: 'math metric prefix',
  },
  {
    ID: '114624',
    Subject: '%\fBodily Arcs',
    Question:
      'What kind of arc includes a sensory receptor, an afferent neuron, the brain or spinal cord, an efferent neuron, and an effector organ?',
    Answer: 'reflex arc',
    Metadata:
      'afferent biology brain effector efferent nervous system neuron physiology receptor science spinal cord',
  },
  {
    ID: '127935',
    Subject: 'Agricultural Experiments',
    Question:
      'In the Bataan Experiment of 1947, Philippine health authorities were able to reduce the incidence of beriberi by nearly 90 percent when they fortified what common foodstuff with thiamine, niacin, and iron?',
    Answer: 'rice',
    Metadata:
      '1940s 1947 20th century beriberi deficiency disease health history niacin Philippines science',
  },
  {
    ID: '45704',
    Subject: '\u0012Documents',
    Question:
      'What kind of document issued by a legal authority creates a public or private entity such as a city, college, or bank?',
    Answer: 'charter',
    Metadata: 'document law social studies vocabulary',
  },
  {
    ID: '61334',
    Subject: 'Rebuilding Europe',
    Question:
      'What Soviet program for Eastern European countries was similar in intent to the Marshall Plan?',
    Answer: 'COMECON',
    Metadata:
      'Cold War Eastern Europe Europe history international relations Marshall Plan social studies Soviet Union world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '35476',
    Subject: 'Southeast Asia',
    Question: 'Much of the border between Laos and Thailand is formed by what river?',
    Answer: 'Mekong',
    Metadata: 'Asia border geography Laos river social studies Southeast Asia Thailand',
  },
  {
    ID: '148529',
    Subject: '1Musical Instruments',
    Question:
      'What musical instrument produces sound by driving pressurized air through pipes that are selected by means of a keyboard?',
    Answer: 'pipe organ',
    Metadata: 'fine arts humanities music musical instrument',
  },
  {
    ID: '128953',
    Subject: '*Cards',
    Question:
      'You pull 1 card randomly from a standard deck. What are the chances it is a black card?',
    Answer: '1/2 (or 26/52)',
    Metadata: 'math playing cards probability',
  },
  {
    ID: '14573',
    Subject: 'Ancient Greece',
    Question:
      'According to Homer, this city on the northeast portion of the Plain of Argos was the home of Agamemnon, leader of the Greek heroes at Troy. Name this city.',
    Answer: 'Mycenae',
    Metadata: 'Agamemnon archaeology Argos city Greek myth Homer language arts myth Troy',
  },
  {
    ID: '35779',
    Subject: '\u0002Peninsular Populations',
    Question: "What country on Europe's Iberian Peninsula has the largest population?",
    Answer: 'Spain',
    Metadata: 'Europe geography Iberian Peninsula peninsula social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '11072',
    Subject: 'Biblical Passages',
    Question:
      'This is from what book of the Bible? And I will give to you and to your descendants after you all the land of Canaan for an everlasting possession, and I will be their God.',
    Answer: 'Genesis',
    Metadata: 'Bible language arts literature quote',
  },
  {
    ID: '31920',
    Subject: 'Asian Islands',
    Question:
      'What island chain, stretching from the Kamchatka Peninsula to Japan, lies between the Sea of Okhotsk and the Pacific?',
    Answer: 'Kuril Islands',
    Metadata:
      'archipelago Asia geography island Japan Kamchatka Peninsula peninsula Sea of Okhotsk social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '44642',
    Subject: '\u0012Crime',
    Question:
      'A person who steals something of comparatively low value could be charged with petty what?',
    Answer: 'larceny (theft)',
    Metadata: 'crime law social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '74430',
    Subject: 'Libraries',
    Question:
      'In what state could you visit the Calvin Coolidge Presidential Library and the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library?',
    Answer: 'Massachusetts',
    Metadata:
      'American history Coolidge, Calvin history Kennedy, John presidential library social studies state history',
  },
  {
    ID: '149015',
    Subject: '3 \u0002Tennis',
    Question:
      'Name the part of the tennis racket which includes the rounded frame and the strings.',
    Answer: 'head',
    Metadata: 'sports tennis',
  },
  {
    ID: '139371',
    Subject: '-Percentage Problems',
    Question:
      'A five-pound box of dried snail-darters was increased in price from $9.00 to $13.00. This represents an increase in price of what percent?',
    Answer: '44%',
    Metadata: 'math percent word problem',
  },
  {
    ID: '136615',
    Subject: ',Polynomial Multiplication',
    Question: 'Multiply -x by the quantity (y-5z).',
    Answer: '-xy + 5xz',
    Metadata: 'algebra math multiplication polynomial',
  },
  {
    ID: '134344',
    Subject: '+Prisms',
    Question: 'The two general categories of prisms are right prisms and what other?',
    Answer: 'oblique',
    Metadata: 'geometry math prism (geometry) solid geometry',
  },
  {
    ID: '147878',
    Subject: '1!Songs',
    Question:
      'These are songs from what Broadway musical? Shoeless Joe from Hannibal, Mo. Whatever Lola Wants Two Lost Souls Heart',
    Answer: 'Damn Yankees',
    Metadata: 'Broadway fine arts music musical song',
  },
  {
    ID: '56209',
    Subject: '\u0002 Symbols',
    Question: "What two implements were the Soviet Union's symbols for industry and agriculture?",
    Answer: 'hammer, sickle',
    Metadata: '20th century history social studies Soviet Union symbol world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '129649',
    Subject: '*Pepper Permutations',
    Question:
      'You have five quart jars of jalapeno peppers. In how many ways can these jars be arranged on a shelf?',
    Answer: '120',
    Metadata: 'math permutation',
  },
  {
    ID: '79442',
    Subject: '\u001aComets',
    Question: 'Comets often have two tails. These are the dust tail and what other?',
    Answer: 'ion (gas) tail',
    Metadata: 'astronomy comet earth science science',
  },
  {
    ID: '59338',
    Subject: 'Offensives',
    Question: 'The last desperate German offensive occurred in 1944. Name this battle.',
    Answer: 'Battle of the Bulge (the Ardennes Forest)',
    Metadata:
      '1940s 1944 20th century battle Europe Germany history social studies war world history World War II',
  },
  {
    ID: '31438',
    Subject: 'Compass Headings',
    Question:
      'A yak train leaves Kabul, Afghanistan on a 90 degree heading. What will be the next country it enters?',
    Answer: 'Pakistan',
    Metadata: 'Afghanistan Asia compass geography social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '66558',
    Subject: 'Political Influence',
    Question: 'Tammany Hall was a political power in the history of what U.S. city?',
    Answer: 'New York',
    Metadata: '19th century American history city history social studies Tammany Hall',
  },
  {
    ID: '135809',
    Subject: ',Conic Sections',
    Question: 'Which conic section is described by this equation? 4(x squared) + y squared = 9',
    Answer: 'ellipse',
    Metadata: 'algebra conic section curve graphing math',
  },
  {
    ID: '76418',
    Subject: 'Captives',
    Question:
      'In 2014, U.S. Marine Sergeant Andrew Tahmooressi was being held in a prison in what country?',
    Answer: 'Mexico',
    Metadata: '2010s 2014 21st century American history Marine Corps people social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '20809',
    Subject: 'Root Words',
    Question: 'What does the root mean in these words? philology philodendron philosopher',
    Answer: 'love',
    Metadata: 'etymology language arts philosophy root word',
  },
  {
    ID: '74502',
    Subject: 'Lawmen',
    Question:
      'What New Mexican sheriff said this after his final encounter with a celebrated gunman? I, at no time, contemplated taking any chances with Billy the Kid which I could avoid with caution or cunning. The only circumstances under which we could have met on equal terms would have been accidental, and to which I would have been an unwilling party.',
    Answer: 'Pat Garrett',
    Metadata:
      '1880s 19th century American history Billy the Kid New Mexico Old West social studies state history',
  },
  {
    ID: '112105',
    Subject: '#!\tAbnormal Psychology',
    Question:
      'Name the psychological disturbance arising from some form of trauma that may manifest as paralysis, blindness, deafness, or anesthesia.',
    Answer: 'hysteria',
    Metadata:
      'abnormal psychology anesthesia blindness deafness paralysis psychology science trauma',
  },
  {
    ID: '73520',
    Subject: 'Conquistadors',
    Question: 'What conquistador gave Florida its name?',
    Answer: 'Ponce de Leon',
    Metadata: 'American history conquistador Florida history social studies state history',
  },
  {
    ID: '7715',
    Subject: '\u0002 Science Fiction',
    Question:
      'In what novel by Michael Crichton do supersmall, supersmart nanobots get out of control?',
    Answer: 'Prey',
    Metadata:
      'American literature Crichton, Michael language arts literature nanotechnology science fiction',
  },
  {
    ID: '5812',
    Subject: '\u0002\fLegends',
    Question:
      "This indicates what legendary character? Everybody knows he taught the bronco how to buck and it is a matter of record that he dug the Rio Grande one dry year when he grew tired of packin' water from the Gulf of Mexico.",
    Answer: 'Pecos Bill',
    Metadata: 'American literature language arts legend literature Old West',
  },
  {
    ID: '40694',
    Subject: 'Military Jargon',
    Question:
      'Armed forces transported to a war zone who are actually doing the fighting are called "boots on the" what?',
    Answer: 'ground',
    Metadata: 'government jargon military social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '46611',
    Subject: 'Archaeology',
    Question:
      'What is the last principal period in the three-age system for classifying prehistoric societies?',
    Answer: 'Iron Age',
    Metadata: 'ancient history archaeology history social studies three age system world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '30629',
    Subject: 'Seas',
    Question: 'Between Saudi Arabia and Africa is what sea?',
    Answer: 'Red Sea',
    Metadata: 'Africa geography Saudi Arabia sea social studies',
  },
  {
    ID: '17479',
    Subject: '\u0002Conjunctions',
    Question:
      'Name either of the two coordinate conjunctions missing from this list. for, so, or, nor, yet',
    Answer: 'but, and',
    Metadata: 'conjunction coordinating conjunction grammar language arts part of speech',
  },
  {
    ID: '145852',
    Subject: '1Lyrics',
    Question:
      "These lyrics are associated with what 1969 upstate New York meadowlands festival? Why don't we sing this song together? Open our senses - let the images come - and if we close our eyes together - we'll all see from where we are.",
    Answer: 'Woodstock',
    Metadata: '1960s 20th century festival humanities lyrics music New York song',
  },
  {
    ID: '73127',
    Subject: 'Historical Verse',
    Question:
      "This is from a song about the establishment of what nation? First, gallant South Carolina nobly made the stand; Then came Alabama who took her by the hand; Next, quickly Mississippi, Georgia, and Florida, All rais'd on high the Bonnie Blue Flag, That bears a Single Star!",
    Answer: 'Confederates States of America',
    Metadata: 'American history history social studies song',
  },
  {
    ID: '48897',
    Subject: 'Pacific Islands',
    Question:
      'This refers to what Pacific island? The ancient statues, called moai, are carved from volcanic stone in the shape of busts up to forty feet in height.',
    Answer: 'Easter Island',
    Metadata:
      'anthropology history humanities island Oceania Pacific Ocean Polynesia sculpture social studies statue world history',
  },
  {
    ID: '42178',
    Subject: 'Job Insurance',
    Question:
      'Barring some substantial inability to perform or some significant wrongful act, many teachers have a guaranteed right to a job once a probationary period has passed. Name this guarantee.',
    Answer: 'tenure',
    Metadata: 'economics social studies university vocabulary vocational',
  },
  {
    ID: '45703',
    Subject: '\u0012Law Enforcement',
    Question:
      'There is often concern in sting operations about persuading a person to commit an offense that he otherwise would have been unlikely to commit. What is the legal term for such inducement?',
    Answer: 'entrapment',
    Metadata: 'law law enforcement social studies sting operation',
  },
  {
    ID: '121870',
    Subject: '( Critters',
    Question: 'The Rambouillet, Columbia, Hampshire, and Suffolk are breeds of what animals?',
    Answer: 'sheep',
    Metadata: 'biology mammal science zoology',
  },
];
